<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sc>

<item>
<content>Some bat caves,like honeybee hives, have residents that take on different duties such as defending the entrance, acting as sentinels and to sound a warning at the approach of danger, and scouting outside the cave for new food and roosting sites.</content>
<a>acting as sentinels and to sound</a>
<b>acting as sentinels and sounding</b>

<c>to act as sentinels and sound</c>
<d>to act as sentinels and to sound</d>
<e>to act as a sentinel sounding</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-1</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>However much United States voters may agree that there is waste in government and that the government as a whole spends beyond its means, it is difficult to find broad support for a movement toward a minimal state.</content>

<a>However much United States voters may agree that</a>
<b>Despite the agreement among United States voters to the fact</b>
<c>Although United States voters agree</c>
<d>Even though United States voters may agree</d>
<e>There is agreement among United States voters that</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-2</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Native American burial sites dating back 5,000 years indicate that the residents of Maine at that time were part of a widespread culture of Algonquian-speaking people.</content>
<a>were part of a widespread culture of Algonquian-speaking people</a>
<b>had been part of a widespread culture of people who were Algonquian-speaking</b>
<c>were people who were part of a widespread culture that was Algonquian-speaking</c>
<d>had been people who were part of a widespread culture that was Algonquian-speaking</d>
<e>were a people which had been part of a widespread, algonquian-speaking culture</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-3</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The voluminous personal papers of Thomas Alva Edison reveal that his inventions typically sprang to life not in a flash of inspiration but evolved slowly from previous works.</content>
<a>sprang to life not in a flash of inspiration but evolved slowly</a>
<b>sprang to life not in a flash of inspiration but were slowly evolved</b>
<c>did not spring to life in a flash of inspiration but evolved slowly</c>
<d>did not spring to life in a flash of inspiration but had slowly evolved</d>
<e>did not spring to life in a flash of inspiration but they were slowly evolved</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-4</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A Labor Department study states that the numbers of women employed outside the home grew by more than a thirty-five percent increase in the past decade and accounted for more than sixty-two percent of the total growth in the civilian work force.</content>
<a>numbers of women employed outside the home grew by more than a thirty-five percent increase</a>
<b>numbers of women employed outside the home grew more than thirty-five percent</b>
<c>numbers of women employed outside the home were raised by more than thirty-five percent</c>

<d>number of women employed outside the home increased by more than thirty-five percent</d>
<e>number of women employed outside the home was raised by more than a thirty-five percent increase</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-5</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>From the earliest days of the tribe, kinship determined the way in which the Ojibwa society organized its labor, provided access to its resources, and defined rights and obligations involved in the distribution and consumption of those resources</content>
<a>and defined rights and obligations involved in the distribution and consumption of those resources</a>

<b>defining rights and obligations involved in their distribution and consumption</b>
<c>and defined rights and obligations as they were involved in its distribution and consumption</c>
<d>whose rights and obligations were defined in their distribution and consumption</d>
<e>the distribution and consumption of them defined by rights and obligations</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-6</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>Delighted by the reported earnings for the first quarter of the fiscal year, it was decided by the company manager to give her staff a raise.</content>
<a>it was decided by the company manager to give her staff a raise</a>
<b>the decision of the company manager was to give her staff a raise</b>
<c>the company manager decided to give her staff a raise</c>
<d>the staff was given a raise by the company manager</d>
<e>a raise was given to the staff by the company manager</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-7</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>The rising of costs of data-processing operations at many financial institutions has created a growing opportunity for independent companies to provide these services more efficiently and at lower cost.</content>
<a>The rising of costs</a>
<b>Rising costs</b>
<c>The rising cost</c>
<d>Because the rising cost</d>
<e>Because of rising costs</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-8</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>William H. Johnson's artistic debt to Scandinavia is evident in paintings that range from sensitive portraits of citizens in his wife's Danish home, kerteminde, and awe-inspiring views of fjords and mountain peaks in the western and northern regions of Norway.</content>
<a>and</a>
<b>to</b>
<c>and to</c>
<d>with</d>

<e>in addition to</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-9</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Growing competitive pressures may be encouraging auditors to bend the rules in favor of clients；auditors may, for instance, allow a questionable loan to remain on the books in order to maintain a bank's profits on paper.</content>
<a>clients；auditors may, for instance, allow</a>
<b>clients, as an instance,to allow</b>

<c>clients,like to allow</c>
<d>clients,such as to be allowing</d>
<e>clients；which might, as an instance, be the allowing of</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-10</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>It is well known in the supermarket industry that how items are placed on shelves and the frequency of inventory turnovers can be crucial to profits.</content>

<a>the frequency of inventory turnovers can be</a>
<b>the frequency of inventory turnovers is often</b>
<c>the frequency with which the inventory turns over is often</c>
<d>how frequently is the inventory turned over are often</d>
<e>how frequently the inventory turns over can be</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-11</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Iguanas have been an important food source in Latin America since prehistoric times, and it is still prized as a game animal by the campesinos,who typically cook the meat in a heavily spiced stew.</content>
<a>it is still prized as a game animal</a>
<b>it is still prized as game animals</b>
<c>they are still prized as game animals</c>
<d>they are still prized as being a game anima</d>
<e>being still prized as a game animal</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-12</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Except for a concert performance that the composer himself staged in 1911,Scott Joplin's ragtime opera＂Treemonisha＂was not produced　until 1972,sixty-one years after its completion.</content>
<a>Except for a concert performance that the composer himself staged</a>
<b>Except for a concert performance with the composer himself staging it</b>
<c>Besides a concert performance being staged by the composer himself</c>
<d>Excepting a concert performance that the composer himself staged</d>
<e>With the exception of a concert performance with the staging done by the composer himself</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-13</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>From the time of its defeat by the Germans in 1940 until its liberation in 1944, france was a bitter and divided country；a kind of civil war raged in the Vichy government between those who wanted to collaborate with the Nazis with those who opposed them.</content>
<a>between those who wanted to collaborate with the Nazis with those who opposed</a>
<b>between those who wanted to collaborate with the Nazis and those who opposed</b>
<c>between those wanting to collaborate with the Nazis with those opposing</c>

<d>among those who wanted to collaborate with the Nazis and those who opposed</d>
<e>among those wanting to collaborate with the Nazis with those opposing</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-14</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Chinese,the most ancient of living writing systems, consists of tens of thousands of ideographic characters,the most ancient of living writing systems, consists of tens of thousands of ideographic characters, each character a miniature calligraphic composition inside its own square frame.</content>
<a>each character a miniature calligraphic composition inside its</a>

<b>all the characters a miniature calligraphic composition inside their</b>
<c>all the characters a miniature calligraphic composition inside its</c>
<d>every character a miniature calligraphic composition inside their</d>
<e>each character a miniature calligraphic composition inside their</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-15</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>Declining values for farm equipment and land,the collateral against which farmers borrow to get through the harvest season, is going to force many lenders to tighten or deny credit this spring.</content>
<a>the collateral against which farmers borrow to get through the harvest season, is</a>
<b>which farmers use as collateral to borrow against to get through the harvest season, is</b>
<c>the collateral which is borrowed against by farmers to get through the harvest season, is</c>
<d>Which farmers use as collateral to borrow against to get through the harvest season, are</d>
<e>the collateral against which farmers borrow to get through the harvest season, are</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-16</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>In the mid-1960's a newly installed radar warning system mistook the.rising of the moon as a massive missile attack by the Soviets.</content>
<a>rising of the moon as a massive missile attack by the Soviets</a>
<b>rising of the moon for a massive Soviet missile attack</b>
<c>moon rising to a massive missile attack by the Soviets</c>
<d>moon as it was rising for a massive Soviet missile attack</d>
<e>rise of the moon as a massive Soviet missile attack</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-17</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>With only 5 percent of the world's population,United States citizens consume 28 percent of its nonrenewable resources, drive more than one-third 0f its automobiles, and use 21 times more water per capita than Europeans do.</content>
<a>With</a>
<b>As</b>
<c>Being</c>
<d>Despite having</d>

<e>Although accounting for</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-18</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>While depressed property values can hurt some large investors, they are potentially devastating for homeowners, whose equity-in many cases representing a life's savings--can plunge or even disappear.</content>
<a>they are potentially devastating for homeowners,whose</a>
<b>they can potentially devastate homeowners in that their</b>

<c>for homeowners they are potentially devastating, because their</c>
<d>for homeowners, it is potentially devastating in that their</d>
<e>it can potentially devastate homeowners,whose</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-19</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Consumers may not think of household cleaning products to be hazardous substances, but many of them can be harmful to health, especially if they are used improperly.</content>

<a>Consumers may not think of household cleaning products to be</a>
<b>Consumers may not think of household cleaning products being</b>
<c>A consumer may not think of their household cleaning products being</c>
<d>A consumer may not think of household cleaning products as</d>
<e>Household cleaning products may not be thought of by consumers, as</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-20</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>It is possible that Native Americans originally have migrated to the Western Hemisphere over a bridge of land that once existed between Siberia and Alaska.</content>
<a>have migrated to the Western Hemisphere over a bridge of land that once existed</a>
<b>were migrating to the Western Hemisphere over a bridge of land that existed once</b>
<c>migrated over a bridge of land to the Western Hemisphere that once existed</c>
<d>migrated to the Western Hemisphere over a bridge of land that once existed</d>
<e>were migrating to the Western Hemisphere over a bridge of land existing once</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-21</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In recent years cattle breeders have increasingly used crossbreeding, in part that their steers should acquire certain characteristics and partly because crossbreeding is said to provide hybrid vigor.</content>
<a>in part that their steers should acquire certain characteristics</a>
<b>in part for the acquisition of certain characteristics in their steers</b>
<c>partly because of their steers acquiring certain characteristics</c>
<d>partly because certain characteristics should be acquired by their steers</d>
<e>partly to acquire certain characteristics in their steers</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-22</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like Auden,the language of James Merrill is chatty, arch, and conversational-given to complex syntactic flights as well as to prosaic free' verse strolls.</content>
<a>Like Auden,the language of James Merrill</a>
<b>Like Auden, james Merrill's language</b>
<c>Like Auden's, james Merrill's language</c>

<d>As with Auden, james Merrill's language</d>
<e>As is Auden~the language of James Merrill</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-23</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The period when the great painted caves at Lascaux and Altamira were occupied by Upper Paleolithic people has been established by carbon-14 dating, but what is much more difficult  to determine are the reason for their decoration,the use to which primitive people put the caves, and the meaning of the magnificently depicted animals.</content>
<a>has been established by carbon-14 dating, but what is much more difficult to determine are</a>

<b>has been established by carbon-14 dating, but what is much more difficult to determine is</b>
<c>have been established by carbon-14 dating, but what is much more difficult to determine is</c>
<d>have been established by carbon-14 dating, but what is much more difficult to determine are</d>
<e>are established by carbon-14 dating, but that which is much more difficult to determine is</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-24</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>The Baldrick Manufacturing Company has for several years followed a policy aimed at decreasing operating costs and improving the efficiency of its distribution system.</content>
<a>aimed at decreasing operating costs and improving</a>
<b>aimed at the decreasing of operating costs and to improve</b>
<c>aiming at the decreasing of operating costs and improving</c>
<d>the aim of which is the decreasing of operating costs and improving</d>
<e>with the aim to decrease operating costs and to improve</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-25</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Eating saltwater fish may significantly reduce the risk of heart attacks and also aid for sufferers of rheumatoid arthritis and asthma, according to three research studies published in the New England Journal of Medicine.</content>
<a>significantly reduce the risk of heart attacks and also aid for</a>
<b>be significant in reducing the risk of heart attacks and aid for</b>
<c>significantly reduce the risk of heart attacks and aid</c>
<d>cause a significant reduction in the risk of heart attacks and aid to</d>
<e>significantly reduce the risk of heart attacks as well as aiding</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-26</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Minnesota is the only one of the contiguous forty-eight states that still has a sizable wolf population, and where this predator remains the archenemy of cattle and sheep.</content>
<a>that still has a sizable wolf population, and where</a>
<b>that still has a sizable wolf population,where</b>
<c>that still has a sizable population of wolves, and where</c>
<d>where the population of wolves is still sizable；</d>

<e>where there is still a sizable population of wolves and where</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-27</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In reference to the current hostility toward smoking smokers frequently expressed anxiety that their prospects for being hired and promoted are being stunted by their habit.</content>
<a>In reference to the current hostility toward smoking,smokers frequently expressed anxiety that</a>
<b>Referring to the current hostility toward smoking,smokers frequently expressed anxiety about</b>

<c>When referring to the current hostility toward smoking,smokers frequently express anxiety about</c>
<d>With reference to the current hostility toward smoking,smokers frequently expressed anxiety about</d>
<e>Referring to the current hostility toward smoking,smokers frequently express anxiety that</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-28</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to some economists,the July decrease in unemployment so that it was the lowest in two years suggests that the gradual improvement in the job market is continuing.</content>

<a>so that it was the lowest in two years</a>
<b>so that it was the lowest two-year rate</b>
<c>to what would be the lowest in two years</c>
<d>to a two-year low level</d>
<e>to the lowest level in two years</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-29</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Thomas Eakins' powerful style and his choices of subject-the advances in modern surgery, the discipline of sport,the strains of individuals in tension with society or even with themselves-was as disturbing to his own time as it is compelling for ours.</content>
<a>was as disturbing to his own time as it is</a>
<b>were as disturbing to his own time as they are</b>
<c>has been as disturbing in his own time as they are</c>
<d>had been as disturbing in his own time as it was</d>
<e>have been as disturbing in his own time as</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-30</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like Rousseau, Tolstoi rebelled against the unnatural complexity of human relations in modem society.</content>
<a>Like Rousseau, Tolstoi rebelled</a>
<b>Like Rousseau, Tolstoi's rebellion was</b>
<c>As Rousseau, Tolstoi rebelled</c>
<d>As did Rousseau, Tolstoi's rebellion was</d>
<e>Tolstoi's rebellion, as Rousseau's was</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-31</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Waller stein study indicates that even after a decade young men and women still experience some of the effects of a divorce occurring when a child.</content>
<a>occurring when a child</a>
<b>occurring when children</b>
<c>that occurred when a child</c>

<d>that occurred when they were children</d>
<e>that has occurred as each was a child</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-32</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Carbon-14 dating reveals that the megalithic monuments in Brittany are nearly 2,000 years as old as any of their supposed Mediterranean predecessors.</content>
<a>as old as any of their supposed</a>

<b>older than any of their supposed</b>
<c>as old as their supposed</c>
<d>older than any of their supposedly</d>
<e>as old as their supposedly</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-33</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>Lacking information about energy use,people tend to overestimate the amount of energy used by equipment, such as lights, that are visible and must be turned on and off and underestimate that used by unobtrusive equipment,such as water heaters.</content>
<a>equipment,such as lights,that are visible and must be turned on and off and underestimate that</a>
<b>equipment,such as lights,that are visible and must be turned on and off and underestimate it when</b>
<c>equipment, such as lights,that is visible and must be turned on and off and underestimate it when</c>
<d>visible equipment, such as lights, that must be turned on and off and underestimate that</d>
<e>visible equipment,such as lights,that must be turned on and off and underestimate it when</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-34</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>The rise in the Commerce Department's index of leading economic indicators suggest that the economy should continue its expansion into the coming months, but that the mixed performance of the index's individual components indicates that economic growth will proceed at a more moderate pace than in the first quarter of this year.</content>
<a>suggest that the economy should continue its expansion into the coming months, but that</a>
<b>suggest that the economy is to continue expansion in the coming months, but</b>
<c>suggests that the economy will continue its expanding in the coming months, but that</c>
<d>suggests that the economy is continuing to expand into the coming months, but that</d>
<e>suggests that the economy will continue to expand in the coming months, but</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-35</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>What was as remarkable as the development of the compact disc has been the use of the new technology to revitalize, in better sound than was ever before possible, some of the classic recorded performances of the pre-LP era.</content>
<a>What was as remarkable as the development of the compact disc</a>
<b>The thing that was as remarkable as developing the compact disc</b>
<c>No less remarkable than the development of the compact disc</c>
<d>Developing the compact disc has been none the less remarkable than</d>

<e>Development of the compact disc has been no less remarkable as</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-36</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Some buildings that were destroyed and heavily damaged in the earthquake last year were constructed in violation of the city's building cede.</content>
<a>Some buildings that were destroyed and heavily damaged in the earthquake last year were</a>
<b>Some buildings that were destroyed or heavily damaged in the earthquake last year had been</b>

<c>Some buildings that the earthquake destroyed and heavily damaged last year have been</c>
<d>Last year the earthquake destroyed or heavily damaged some buildings that have been</d>
<e>Last year some of the buildings that were destroyed or heavily damaged in the earthquake had been</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-37</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Using a Doppler ultrasound device, fetal heartbeats can be detected by the twelfth week of pregnancy.</content>

<a>Using a Doppler ultrasound device, fetal heartbeats can be detected by the twelfth week of pregnancy.</a>
<b>Fetal heartbeats can be detected by the twelfth week of pregnancy, using a Doppler ultrasound device.</b>
<c>Detecting fetal heartbeats by the twelfth week of pregnancy, a physician can use a Doppler ultrasound device.</c>
<d>By the twelfth week of pregnancy, fetal heartbeats can be detected using a Doppler ultrasound device by a physician.</d>
<e>Using a Doppler ultrasound device, a physician can detect fetal heartbeats by the twelfth week of pregnancy.</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-38</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A study commissioned by the Department of Agriculture showed that if calves exercise and associated with other calves, they will require less medication and gain weight quicker than do those raised in confinement.</content>
<a>associated with other calves,they will require less medication and gain weight quicker than do</a>
<b>associated with other calves,they require less medication and gain weight quicker than</b>
<c>associate with other calves,they required less medication and will gain weight quicker than do</c>
<d>associate with other calves,they have required less medication and will gain weight more quickly than do</d>
<e>associate with other calves,they require less medication and gain weight more quickly than</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-39</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recent study has found that within the past few years,many doctors.had elected early retirement rather than face the threats of lawsuits and the rising costs of malpractice insurance.</content>
<a>had elected early retirement rather than face</a>
<b>had elected early retirement instead of facing</b>
<c>have elected retiring early instead of facing</c>
<d>have elected to retire early rather than facing</d>
<e>have elected to retire early rather than face</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-40</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Gorton-Dodd bill requires that a bank disclose to their customers how long they will delay access to funds from deposited checks.</content>
<a>that a bank disclose to their customers how long they will delay access to funds from deposited checks</a>
<b>a bank to disclose to their customers how long they will delay access to funds from a deposited check</b>
<c>that a bank disclose to its customers how long it will delay access to funds from deposited checks</c>

<d>a bank that it should disclose to its customers how long it will delay access to funds from a deposited check</d>
<e>that banks disclose to customers how long access to funds from their deposited check is to be delayed</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-41</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike a funded pension system, in which contributions are invested to pay future beneficiaries, a pay-as-you-go approach is the foundation of social Security.</content>
<a>a pay-as-you-go approach is the foundation of Social Security</a>

<b>the foundation of Social Security is a pay-as-you-go approach</b>
<c>the approach of Social Security is pay-as-you-go</c>
<d>Social Security's approach is pay-as-you-go</d>
<e>Social Security is founded on a pay-as-you-go approach</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-42</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>Although she had signed a pledge of abstinence while being an adolescent, frances Willard was 35 years old before she chose to become a temperance activist.</content>
<a>while being an adolescent</a>
<b>while in adolescence</b>
<c>at the time of her being adolescent</c>
<d>as being in adolescence</d>
<e>	as an adolescent</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-43</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Though the term＂graphic　design＂may　suggest　laying　out corporate brochures and annual reports,they have come to signify widely ranging work,　from package designs and company logotypes to signs, book jackets, computer graphics.and film titles.</content>
<a>suggest laying out corporate brochures and annual reports,they have come to signify widely ranging</a>
<b>suggest laying out corporate brochures and annual reports, it has come to signify a wide range of</b>
<c>suggest corporate brochure and annual report layout, it has signified widely ranging</c>
<d>have suggested corporate brochure and annual report layout, it has signified a wide range of</d>
<e>have suggested laying out corporate brochures and annual reports,they have come to signify widely ranging</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-44</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In contrast to large steel plants that take iron ore through all the steps needed to produce several different kinds of steel,processing steel scrap into a specialized group of products has enabled small mills to put capital into new technology and remain economically viable.</content>
<a>processing steel scrap into a specialized group of products has enabled small mills to put capital Into new technology and remain</a>
<b>processing steel scrap into a specialized group of products has enabled small mills to put capital into new technology, remaining</b>
<c>the processing of steel scrap into a specialized group of products has enabled small mills to put capital into new technology, remaining</c>

<d>small mills, by processing steel scrap into a specialized group of products, have been able to put capital into new technology and remain</d>
<e>small mills, by processing steel scrap into a specialized group of products, have been able to put capital into new technology and remained</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-45</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The psychologist William James believed that facial expressions not only provide a visible sign of an emotion, actually contributing to the feeling itself.</content>
<a>emotion, actually contributing to the feeling itself</a>

<b>emotion but also actually contributing to the feeling itself</b>
<c>emotion but also actually contribute to the feeling itself</c>
<d>emotion；they also actually contribute to the feeling of it</d>
<e>emotion；the feeling itself is also actually contributed to by them</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-46</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>The financial crash of October 1987 demonstrated that the world's capital markets are.integrated more closely than never before and events in one part of the global village may be transmitted to the rest of the village -almost instantaneously.</content>
<a>integrated more closely than never before and</a>
<b>closely integrated more than ever before so</b>
<c>more closely integrated as never before while</c>
<d>more closely integrated than ever before and that</d>
<e>more than ever before closely integrated as</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-47</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Wisconsin, illinois, Florida, and Minnesota have begun to enforce statewide bans.prohibiting landfills to accept leaves, brush, and grass clippings.</content>
<a>prohibiting landfills to accept leaves, brush, and grass clippings</a>
<b>prohibiting that landfills accept leaves, brush, and grass clippings</b>
<c>prohibiting landfills from accepting leaves, brush, and grass clippings</c>
<d>that leaves, brush, and grass clippings cannot be accepted in landfills</d>
<e>that landfills cannot accept leaves, brush, and grass clippings</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-48</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Reporting that one of its many problems had been the recent extended sales slump in women's apparel,the seven-store retailer said it would start a three-month liquidation sale in all of its stores.</content>
<a>its many problems had been the recent</a>
<b>its many problems has been the recently</b>
<c>its many problems is the recently</c>
<d>their many problems is the recent</d>

<e>their many problems had been the recent</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-49</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Domestic automobile manufacturers have invested millions of dollars into research to develop cars more gasoline-efficient even than presently on the road.</content>
<a>into research to develop cars more gasoline-efficient even than presently on the road</a>
<b>into research for developing even more gasoline-efficient cars on the road than at present</b>

<c>for research for cars to be developed that are more gasoline-efficient even than presently the road</c>
<d>In research to develop cars even more gasoline-efficient than those at present on the road</d>
<e>in research for developing cars that are even more gasoline-efficient than presently on the road</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-50</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In developing new facilities for the incineration of solid wastes,we must avoid the danger of shifting environmental problems from landfills polluting the water to polluting the air with incinerators.</content>

<a>landfills polluting the water to polluting the air with incinerators</a>
<b>landfills polluting the water to the air being polluted with incinerators</b>
<c>the pollution of water by landfills to the pollution of air by incinerators</c>
<d>pollution of the water by landfills to incinerators that pollute the air</d>
<e>water that is polluted by landfills to incinerators that pollute the air</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-51</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The winds that howl across the Great Plains not only blow away valuable topsoil,thereby reducing the potential crop yield of a tract of land, and also damage or destroy young plants.</content>
<a>and also damage or destroy</a>
<b>as well as damaging or destroying</b>
<c>but they also cause damage or destroy</c>
<d>but also damage or destroy</d>
<e>but also causing damage or destroying</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-52</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In a 5-to-4 decision,the Supreme Court ruled that two upstate New York counties owed restitution to three tribes of Oneida Indians for the unlawful seizure of their ancestral lands in the eighteenth century.</content>
<a>that two upstate New York counties owed restitution to three tribes of Oneida Indians for the unlawful seizure of</a>
<b>that two upstate New York counties owed restitution to three tribes of Oneida Indians because of their unlawful seizure of</b>
<c>two upstate New York counties to owe restitution to three tribes of Oneida Indians for their unlawful seizure of</c>
<d>on two upstate New York counties that owed restitution to three tribes of Oneida Indians because they unlawfully seized</d>
<e>on the restitution that two upstate New York counties owed to three tribes of Oneida Indians for the unlawful seizure of</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-53</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The extraordinary diary of William Lyon Mackenzie King,prime minister of Canada for over twenty years,revealed—that this most bland and circumspect of men was a mystic guided in both public and private life by omens,messages received at séances, and signs from heaven.</content>
<a>that this most bland and circumspect of men was a mystic guided in both public and</a>
<b>that this most bland and circumspect of men was a mystic and also guided both in public as well as</b>
<c>this most bland and circumspect of men was a mystic and that he was guided in both public and</c>

<d>this most bland and circumspect of men was a mystic and that he was guided in both public as well as</d>
<e>this most bland and circumspect of men to have been a mystic and that he guided himself both in public as well as</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-54</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In one of the most stunning reversals in the history of marketing,the Coca—Cola company in July 1985 yielded to thousands of irate consumers demanding that it should bring back the original Coke formula</content>
<a>demanding that it should</a>

<b>demanding it to</b>
<c>and their demand to</c>
<d>who demanded that it</d>
<e>who demanded it to</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-55</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>Recently discovered fossil remains strongly suggest that the Australian egg-laying mammals of today are a branch of the main stem of mammalian evolution rather than developing independently from a common ancestor of mammals more than 220 million years ago.</content>
<a>rather than developing independently from</a>
<b>rather than a type that developed independently from</b>
<c>rather than a type whose development was independent of</c>
<d>instead of developing independently from</d>
<e>instead of a development that was independent of</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-56</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>A patient accusing a doctor of malpractice will find it difficult to prove damage if there is a lack of some other doctor to testify about proper medical procedures.</content>
<a>if there is a lack of some other doctor to testify</a>
<b>unless there will be another doctor to testify</b>
<c>without another doctor's testimony</c>
<d>should there be no testimony from some other doctor</d>
<e>lacking another doctor to testify</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-57</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recording system was so secretly installed and operated in the Kennedy Oval Office that even Theodore C.Sorensen,the White House counsel, did not know it existed.</content>
<a>A recording system was so secretly installed and operated in the Kennedy Oval Office that</a>
<b>So secret was a recording system installation and operation in the Kennedy Oval Office</b>
<c>It was so secret that a recording system was installed and operated in the Kennedy Oval Office</c>
<d>A recording system that was so secretly installed and operated in the Kennedy Oval Office</d>

<e>Installed and operated so secretly In the Kennedy Oval Office was a recording system that</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-58</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Neanderthals had a vocal tract that resembled those of the apes and so were probably without language, a shortcoming that may explain why they were supplanted by our own species.</content>
<a>Neanderthals had a vocal tract that resembled those of the apes</a>
<b>Neanderthals had a vocal tract resembling an ape's</b>

<c>The vocal tracts of Neanderthals resembled an ape's</c>
<d>The Neanderthal's vocal tracts resembled the apes'</d>
<e>The vocal tracts of the Neanderthals resembled those of the apes</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-59</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The energy source on Voyager 2 is not a nuclear reactor, in which atoms are actively broken apart；rather a kind of nuclear battery that uses natural radioactive decay to produce power.</content>

<a>apart; rather</a>
<b>apart, but rather</b>
<c>apart, but rather that of</c>
<d>apart, but that of</d>
<e>apart; it is that of</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-60</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Archaeologists in Ireland believe that a recently discovered chalice, which dates from the eighth century, was probably buried to keep from being stolen by invaders.</content>
<a>to keep from</a>
<b>to keep it from</b>
<c>to avoid</c>
<d>in order that it would avoid</d>
<e>in order to keep from</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-61</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Lawmakers are examining measures that would require banks to disclose all fees and account requirements in writing,provide free cashing of government checks, and to create basic savings accounts to carry minimal fees and require minima initial deposits.</content>
<a>provide free cashing of government checks, and to create basic savings accounts to carry</a>
<b>provide free cashing of government checks, and creating basic savings accounts carrying</b>
<c>to provide free cashing of government checks, and creating basic savings accounts that carry</c>
<d>to provide free cashing of government checks, creating basic savings accounts to carry</d>
<e>to provide free cashing of government checks, and to create basic savings accounts that carry</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-62</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Certain pesticides can become ineffective if used repeatedly in the same place；one reason is suggested by the finding that there are much larger populations of pesticide-degrading microbes in soils with a relatively long history of pesticide use than in soils that are free of such chemicals.</content>
<a>Certain pesticides can become ineffective if used repeatedly in the same place；one reason is suggested by the finding that there are much larger populations of pesticide-degrading microbes in soils with a relatively long history of pesticide use than in soils that are free of such chemicals.</a>
<b>If used repeatedly in the same place,one reason that certain pesticides can become ineffective is suggested by the finding that there are much larger populations of pesticide-degrading microbes in soils with a relatively long history of pesticide use than in soils that are free of such chemicals.</b>
<c>If used repeatedly in the same place,one reason certain pesticides can become ineffective is suggested by the finding that much larger populations of pesticide-degrading microbes are found in soils with a relatively long history of pesticide use than those that are free of such chemicals.</c>

<d>The finding that there are much larger populations of pesticide-degrading microbes in soils with a relatively long history of pesticide use than in soils that are free of such chemicals is suggestive of one reason, if used repeatedly in the same place, certain pesticides can become ineffective.</d>
<e>The finding of much larger populations of pesticide-degrading microbes in soils with a relatively long history of pesticide use than in those that are free of such chemicals suggests one reason certain pesticides can become ineffective if used repeatedly in the same place.</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-63</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In the textbook publishing business,the second quarter is historically weak, because revenues are 1ow and marketing expenses are high as companies prepare for the coming school year.</content>
<a>1ow and marketing expenses are high as companies prepare</a>

<b>low and their marketing expenses are high as they prepare</b>
<c>low with higher marketing expenses in preparation</c>
<d>low, while marketing expenses are higher to prepare</d>
<e>low, while their marketing expenses are higher in preparation</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-64</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>Parliament did not accord full refugee benefits to twelve of the recent immigrants because it believed that to do it rewards them for entering the country illegally.</content>
<a>to do it rewards</a>
<b>doing it rewards</b>
<c>to do this would reward</c>
<d>doing so would reward</d>
<e>to do it would reward</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-65</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Many policy experts say that shifting a portion of health-benefit costs back to the workers helps to control the employer's costs, but also helps to limit medical spending by making patients more careful consumers.</content>
<a>helps to control the employer's costs, but also helps</a>
<b>helps the control of the employer's costs, and also</b>
<c>not only helps to control the employer's costs, but also helps</c>
<d>helps to control not only the employer's costs, but</d>
<e>not only helps to control the employer's costs, and also helps</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-66</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Ms. Chambers is among the forecasters who predict that the rate of addition to arable lands will drop while those of loss rise.</content>
<a>those of loss rise</a>
<b>it rises for loss</b>
<c>those of losses rise</c>
<d>the rate of loss rises</d>

<e>there are rises for the rate of loss</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-67</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike auto insurance,the frequency of claims does not affect the premiums for personal property coverage, but if the insurance company is able to prove excessive loss due to owner negligence, it may decline to renew the policy.</content>
<a>Unlike auto insurance,the frequency of claims does not affect the premiums for personal property coverage</a>
<b>Unlike with auto insurance.the frequency of claims do not affect the premiums for personal property coverage</b>

<c>Unlike the frequency of claims for auto insurance,the premiums for personal property coverage are not affected by the frequency of claims</c>
<d>Unlike the premiums for auto insurance,the premiums for personal property coverage are not affected by the frequency of claims</d>
<e>Unlike with the premiums for auto insurance,the premiums for personal property coverage is not affected by the frequency of claims</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-68</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Organized in 1966 by the Fish and Wildlife Service,the Breeding Bird Survey uses annual roadside counts along established routes for monitoring of population changes of as many as,or of more than 250 bird species, including 180 songbirds.</content>

<a>for monitoring of population changes of as many as,or of</a>
<b>to monitor population changes of as many, or</b>
<c>to monitor changes in the populations of</c>
<d>that monitors population changes of</d>
<e>that monitors changes in populations of as many as,or</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-69</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Faced with an estimated$2 billion budget gap,the city's mayor proposed a nearly 17 percent reduction in the amount allocated the previous year to maintain the city's major cultural institutions and to subsidize hundreds of local arts groups.</content>
<a>proposed a nearly 17 percent reduction in the amount allocated the previous year to maintain the city's major cultural institutions and to subsidize</a>
<b>proposed a reduction from the previous year of nearly 17 percent in the amount it was allocating to maintain the city's major cultural institutions and for subsidizing</b>
<c>proposed to reduce, by nearly 17 percent,the amount from the previous year that was allocated for the maintenance of the city's major cultural institutions and to subsidize</c>
<d>has proposed a reduction from the previous year of nearly 17 percent of the amount it was allocating for maintaining the city's major cultural institutions, and to subsidize</d>
<e>was proposing that the amount they were allocating be reduced by nearly 17 percent from the previous year for maintaining the city's major cultural institutions and for the subsidization</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-70</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>By offering lower prices and a menu of personal communications options,such as caller identification and voice mail,the new telecommunications company has not only captured customers from other phone companies but also forced them to offer competitive prices.</content>
<a>has not only captured customers from other phone companies but also forced them</a>
<b>has not only captured customers from other phone companies, but it also forced them</b>
<c>has not only captured customers from other phone companies but also forced these companies</c>
<d>not only has captured customers from other phone companies but also these companies have been forced</d>
<e>not only captured customers from other phone companies, but it also has forced them</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-71</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The gyrfalcon, an Arctic bird of prey, has survived a close brush with extinction；its numbers are now five times greater than when the use of DDT was sharply restricted in the early 1970's.</content>
<a>extinction；its numbers are now five times greater than</a>
<b>extinction；its numbers are now five times more than</b>
<c>extinction,their numbers now fivefold what they were</c>

<d>extinction,now with fivefold the numbers they had</d>
<e>extinction,now with numbers five times greater than</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-72</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Analysts blamed May's sluggish retail sales on unexciting merchandise as well as the weather, colder and wetter than was usual in some regions, which slowed sales of barbecue grills and lawn furniture</content>
<a>colder and wetter than was usual in some regions,which slowed</a>

<b>which was colder and wetter than usual in some regions,slowing</b>
<c>since it was colder and wetter than usually in some regions,which slowed</c>
<d>being colder and wetter than usually in some regions,slowing</d>
<e>having been colder and wetter than was usual in some regions and slowed</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-73</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>The bank holds$3 billion in loans that are seriously delinquent or in such trouble that they do not expect payments when due.</content>
<a>they do not expect payments when</a>
<b>it does not expect payments when it is</b>
<c>it does not expect payments to be made when they are</c>
<d>payments are not to be expected to be paid when</d>
<e>payments are not expected to be paid when they will be</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-74</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>In a recent poll,86 percent of the public favored a Clean Air Act as strong or—stronger than the present act.</content>
<a>a Clean Air Act as strong or stronger than</a>
<b>a Clean Air Act that is stronger, or at least so strong as,</b>
<c>at least as strong a Clean Air Act as is</c>
<d>a Clean Air Act as strong or stronger than is</d>
<e>a Clean Air Act at least as strong as</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-75</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>State officials report that soaring.rates of liability insurance have risen to force cutbacks in the operations of everything from local governments and school districts to day-care centers and recreational facilities.</content>
<a>rates of liability insurance have risen to force</a>
<b>rates of liability insurance are a force for</b>
<c>rates for liability insurance are forcing</c>
<d>rises in liability insurance rates are forcing</d>

<e>liability insurance rates have risen to force</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-76</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Each of Hemingway's wives—Hadley Richardson, Pauline Pfeiffer, Martha Gelhorn, and Mary Welsh-were strong and interesting women,very different from the often pallid women who populate his novels.</content>
<a>Each of Hemingway's wives-Hadley Richardson,Pauline Pfeiffer, Martha Gelhorn, and Mary Welsh-were strong and interesting women,</a>
<b>Hadley Richardson,Pauline Pfeiffer, Martha Gelhorn, and Mary Welsh-each of them Hemingway's wives-were strong and interesting women,</b>

<c>Hemingway's wives-Hadley Richardson,Pauline Pfeiffer, Martha Gelhorn, and Mary Welsh - were all strong and interesting women,</c>
<d>Strong and interesting women-Hadley Richardson,Pauline Pfeiffer, Martha Gelhorn, and Mary Welsh—each a wife of Hemingway, was</d>
<e>Strong and interesting women-Hadley Richardson,Pauline Pfeiffer, Martha Gelhorn, and Mary Welsh - every one of Hemingway's wives were</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-77</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>While some academicians believe that business ethics should be integrated into every business course.others say that students will take ethics seriously only if it would be taught as a separately required course.</content>

<a>only if it would be taught as a separately required course</a>
<b>only if it is taught as a separate,required Course</b>
<c>if it is taught only as a course required separately</c>
<d>if it was taught only as a separate and required course</d>
<e>if it would only be taught as a required course,separately</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-78</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Scientists have observed large concentrations of heavy metal deposits in the upper twenty centimeters of Baltic Sea sediments,which are consistent with the growth of industrial activity there.</content>
<a>Baltic Sea sediments,which are consistent with the growth of industrial activity there</a>
<b>Baltic Sea sediments,where the growth of industrial activity is consistent with these findings</b>
<c>Baltic Sea sediments, findings consistent with its growth of industrial activity</c>
<d>sediments from the Baltic Sea, findings consistent with the growth of industrial activity in the area</d>
<e>sediments from the Baltic Sea, consistent with the growth of industrial activity there</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-79</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Under a provision of the Constitution that was never applied, Congress has been required to call a convention for considering possible amendments to the document when formally asked to do it by the legislatures of two-thirds of the states.</content>
<a>was never applied, congress has been required to call a convention for considering possible amendments to the document when formally asked to do it</a>
<b>was never applied,there has been a requirement that Congress call a convention for consideration of possible amendments to the document when asked to do it formally</b>
<c>was never applied,whereby Congress is required to call a convention for considering possible amendments to the document when asked to do it formally</c>
<d>has never been applied,whereby Congress is required to call a convention to consider possible amendments to the document when formally  asked to do so</d>
<e>has never been applied, congress is required to call a convention to consider possible amendments to the document when formally asked to do so</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-80</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The current administration, being worried over some foreign trade barriers being removed and our exports failing to increase as a result of deep cuts in the value of the dollar, has formed a group to study ways to sharpen our competitiveness.</content>
<a>being worried over some foreign trade barriers being removed and our exports failing</a>
<b>worrying over some foreign trade barriers being removed, also over the failure of our exports</b>
<c>worried about the removal of some foreign trade barriers and the failure of our exports</c>

<d>in that they were worried about the removal of some foreign trade barriers and also about the failure of our exports</d>
<e>because of its worry concerning the removal of some foreign trade barriers, also concerning the failure of our exports</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-81</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Geologists believe that the warning signs for a major earthquake may include sudden fluctuations in local seismic activity, tilting, and other deformations of the Earth's crust, changing the measured strain across a fault zone and varying the electrical properties of underground rocks.</content>
<a>changing the measured strain across a fault zone and varying</a>

<b>changing measurements of the strain across a fault zone, and varying</b>
<c>changing the strain as measured across a fault zone, and variations of</c>
<d>changes in the measured strain across a fault zone, and variations in</d>
<e>changes in measurements of the strain across a fault zone, and variations among</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-82</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>If the proposed expenditures for gathering information abroad are reduced even further, international news reports have been and will continue to diminish in number and quality.</content>
<a>have been and will continue to diminish</a>
<b>have and will continue to diminish</b>
<c>will continue to diminish, as they already did,</c>
<d>will continue to diminish, as they have already,</d>
<e>will continue to diminish</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-83</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>The rooted systems of most flowing perennials either become too crowded, which results in loss in vigor, and spread too far outward, producing a bare center.</content>
<a>which results in loss in vigor, and spread</a>
<b>resulting in loss in vigor, or spreading</b>
<c>with the result of loss of vigor, or spreading</c>
<d>resulting in loss of vigor, or spread</d>
<e>with a resulting loss of vigor, and spread</e>
<answer>D</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-84</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Any medical test will sometimes fail to detect a condition when it is present and indicate that there is one when it is not.</content>
<a>a condition when it is present and indicate that there is one</a>
<b>when a condition is present and indicate that there is one</b>
<c>a condition when it is present and indicate that it is present</c>
<d>when a condition is present and indicate its presence</d>

<e>the presence of a condition when it is there and indicate its presence</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-85</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Since 1986,when the Department of Labor began to allow investment officers' fees to be based on how the funds they manage perform, several corporations began paying their investment advisers a small basic fee,with a contract promising higher fees if the managers perform well.</content>
<a>investment officers' fees to be based on how the funds they manage perform,several corporations began</a>
<b>investment officers' fees to be based on the performance of the funds they manage,several corporations began</b>

<c>that fees of investment officers be based on how the funds they manage perform,several corporations have begun</c>
<d>fees of investment officers to be based on the performance of the funds they manage, several corporations have begun</d>
<e>that investment officers' fees be based on the performance of the funds they manage,several corporations began</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-86</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The diet of the ordinary Greek in classical times was largely vegetarian—vegetables, fresh cheese,oatmeal, and meal cakes, and meat rarely.</content>

<a>and meat rarely</a>
<b>and meat was rare</b>
<c>with meat as rare</c>
<d>meat a rarity</d>
<e>with meat as a rarity</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-87</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Down-zoning,zoning that typically results in the reduction of housing density, allows for more open space in areas where little water or services exist.</content>
<a>little water or services exist</a>
<b>little water or services exists</b>
<c>few services and little water exists</c>
<d>there is little water or services available</d>
<e>there are few services and little available water</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-88</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Those who come to church with a predisposition to religious belief will be happy in an auditorium or even a storefront, and there is no doubt that religion is sometimes better served by adapted spaces of this kind instead of by some of the buildings actually designed for it.</content>
<a>adapted spaces of this kind instead of by some of the buildings actually designed for it</a>
<b>adapted spaces like these rather than some of the buildings actually designed for them</b>
<c>these adapted spaces instead of by some of the buildings actually designed for it</c>
<d>such adapted spaces rather than by some of the buildings actually designed for them</d>
<e>such adapted spaces than by some of the buildings actually designed for it</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-89</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The concept of the grand jury dates from the twelfth century, when Henry II of England ordered panels of common citizens should prepare lists of  who were their communities' suspected criminals.</content>
<a>should prepare lists of who were their communities' suspected criminals</a>
<b>would do the preparation of lists of their communities' suspected criminals</b>
<c>preparing lists of suspected criminals in their communities</c>

<d>the preparing of a list of suspected criminals in their communities</d>
<e>to prepare lists of suspected criminals in their communities</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-90</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In theory, international civil servants at the United Nations are prohibited from continuing to draw salaries from their own governments；in practice, however some governments merely substitute living allowances for their employees' paychecks, assigned by them to the United Nations.</content>
<a>for their employees' paychecks, assigned by them</a>

<b>for the paychecks of their employees who have been assigned</b>
<c>for the paychecks of their employees, having been assigned</c>
<d>in place of their employees' paychecks, for those of them assigned</d>
<e>in place of the paychecks of their employees to have been assigned by them</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-91</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>According to a study by the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, companies in the United States are providing job training and general education for nearly eight million people, about equivalent to the enrollment of the nation's four-year colleges and universities.</content>
<a>equivalent to the enrollment of</a>
<b>the equivalent of those enrolled in</b>
<c>equal to those who are enrolled in</c>
<d>as many as the enrollment of</d>
<e>as many as are enrolled in</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-92</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Intar, the oldest Hispanic theater company in New York, has moved away from the Spanish classics and now it draws on the works both of contemporary Hispanic authors who live abroad and of those in the United States.</content>
<a>now it draws on the works of contemporary Hispanic authors who live abroad and of those</a>
<b>now draws on the works of contemporary Hispanic authors, both those who live abroad and those who live</b>
<c>it draws on the works of contemporary Hispanic authors now.both those living abroad and who live</c>
<d>draws now on the works both of contemporary Hispanic authors living abroad and who are living</d>
<e>draws on the works now of both contemporary Hispanic authors living abroad and those</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-93</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Last year land values in most parts of the pinelands rose almost so fast, and in some parts even faster than what they did outside the pinelands.</content>
<a>so fast, and in some parts even faster than what they did</a>
<b>so fast, and in some parts even faster than,those</b>
<c>as fast, and in some parts even faster than,those</c>
<d>as fast as, and in some parts even faster than,those</d>

<e>as fast as, and in some parts even faster than what they did</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-94</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>If Dr. Wade was right, any apparent connection of the eating of highly processed foods and excelling at sports is purely coincidental.</content>
<a>If Dr.Wade was right, any apparent connection of the eating of</a>
<b>Should Dr.Wade be right, any apparent connection of eating</b>

<c>If DL Wade Is right, any connection that is apparent between eating of</c>
<d>If Dr.Wade is right, any apparent connection between eating</d>
<e>Should Dr.Wade have been right, any connection apparent between eating</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-95</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The commission proposed that funding for the park's development, which could be open to the public early next year, is obtained through a local bond issue.</content>

<a>that funding for the park's development, which could be open to the public early next year, is</a>
<b>that funding for development of the park,which could be open to the public early next year, be</b>
<c>funding for the development of the park, perhaps open to the public early next year, to be</c>
<d>funds for the park's development,perhaps open to the public early next year, be</d>
<e>development funding for the park, which could be open to the public early next year, is to be</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-96</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Seismologists studying the earthquake that struck northern California in October 1989 are still investigating some of its mysteries：the unexpected power of the seismic waves,the upward thrust that threw one man straight into the air, and the strange electromagnetic signals detected hours before the temblor.</content>
<a>the upward thrust that threw one man straight into the air, and the strange electromagnetic signals detected hours before the temblor</a>
<b>the upward thrust that threw one man straight into the air, and strange electromagnetic signals were detected hours before the temblor</b>
<c>the upward thrust threw one man straight into the air, and hours before the temblor strange electromagnetic signals were detected</c>
<d>one man was thrown straight into the air by the upward thrust, and hours before the temblor strange electromagnetic signals were detected</d>
<e>one man who was thrown straight into the air by the upward thrust, and strange electromagnetic signals that were detected hours before the temblor</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-97</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Two new studies indicate that many people become obese more due to the fact that their bodies burn calories too slowly than overeating.</content>
<a>due to the fact that their bodies burn calories too slowly than overeating</a>
<b>due to their bodies burning calories too slowly than to eating too much</b>
<c>because their bodies burn calories too slowly than that they are overeaters</c>
<d>because their bodies burn calories too slowly than because they eat too much</d>
<e>because of their bodies burning calories too slowly than because of their eating too much</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-98</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Judge Bonham denied a motion to allow members of the jury to go home at the end of each day instead of to confine them to a hotel.</content>
<a>to allow members of the jury to go home at the end of each day instead of to confine them to</a>
<b>that would have allowed members of the jury to go home at the end of each day instead of confined to</b>
<c>under which members of the jury are allowed to go home at the end of each day instead of confining them in</c>

<d>that would allow members of the jury to go home at the end of each day rather than confinement in</d>
<e>to allow members of the jury to go home at the end of each day rather than be confined to</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-99</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Proponents of artificial intelligence say they will be able to make computers that can understand English and other human languages,recognize objects, and reason as an expert does—computers that will be used to diagnose equipment breakdowns, deciding whether to authorize a loan or other purposes such as these.</content>
<a>as an expert does--computers that will be used to diagnose equipment breakdowns, deciding whether to authorize a loan,or other purposes such as these</a>

<b>as an expert does,which may be used for purposes such as diagnosing equipment breakdowns or deciding whether to authorize a loan</b>
<c>like an expert--computers that will be used for such purposes as diagnosing equipment breakdowns or deciding whether to authorize a loan</c>
<d>like an expert,the use of which would be for purposes like the diagnosis of equipment breakdowns or the decision whether or not a loan should be authorized</d>
<e>like an expert.to be used to diagnose equipment breakdowns, deciding whether to authorize a loan or not, or the like</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-100</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>Unlike the United States, where farmers can usually depend on rain or snow all year long,the rains in most parts of Sri Lanka are concentrated in the monsoon months, june to September, and the skies are generally clear for the rest of the year.</content>
<a>Unlike the United States,where farmers can usually depend on rain or snow all year long, the rains in most parts of Sri Lanka</a>
<b>Unlike the United States farmers who can usually depend on rain or snow all year long.the rains in most parts of Sri Lanka</b>
<c>Unlike those of the United States,where farmers can usually depend on rain or snow all year long,most parts of Sri Lanka's rains</c>
<d>In comparison with the United States,whose farmers can usually depend on rain or snow all year long,the rains in most parts of Sri Lanka</d>
<e>In the United States.farmers can usually depend on rain or snow all year long.But in most parts of Sri Lanka the rains</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-101</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Although Napoleon's army entered Russia with far more supplies than they had in their previous campaigns, it had provisions for only twenty-four days.</content>
<a>they had in their previous campaigns</a>
<b>their previous campaigns had had</b>
<c>they had for any previous campaign</c>
<d>in their previous campaigns</d>
<e>for any previous campaign</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-102</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>After the Civil War, contemporaries of Harriet Tubman's maintained that she has all of the qualities of a great leader：coolness in the face of danger, an excellent sense of strategy, and an ability to plan in minute detail.</content>
<a>Tubman's maintained that she has</a>
<b>Tubman's maintain that she had</b>
<c>Tubman's have maintained that she had</c>
<d>Tubman maintained that she had</d>

<e>Tubman had maintained that she has</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-103</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Federalist papers, a strong defense of the United States Constitution and important as a body of work in political science as well,represents the handiwork of three different authors .</content>
<a>and important as a body of work in political science as well,represents</a>
<b>as well as an important body of work in political science,represent</b>

<c>and also a body of work of importance in political science is representing</c>
<d>an important body of work in political science and has been representative of</d>
<e>and as political science an important body of work too,represent</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-104</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>As business grows more complex,students majoring in specialized areas like those of finance and marketing have been becoming increasingly successful in the job market.</content>

<a>majoring in specialized areas like those of finance and marketing have been becoming increasingly</a>
<b>who major in such specialized areas as finance and marketing are becoming more and more</b>
<c>who majored in specialized areas such as those of finance and marketing are being increasingly</c>
<d>who major in specialized areas like those of finance and marketing have been becoming more and more</d>
<e>having majored in such specialized areas as finance and marketing are being increasingly</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-105</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Inuits of the Bering Sea were in isolation from contact with Europeans longer than Aleuts or Inuits of the Noah Pacific and northern Alaska</content>
<a>in isolation from contact with Europeans longer than</a>
<b>isolated from contact with Europeans longer than</b>
<c>in isolation from contact with Europeans longer than were</c>
<d>isolated from contact with Europeans longer than were</d>
<e>in isolation and without contacts with Europeans longer than</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC2-106</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The physical structure of the human eye enables it to sense light of wavelengths up to 0.0005 millimeters；infrared radiation, however, is invisible because its wavelength—0.1 millimeters--is too long to be registered by the eye.</content>
<a>infrared radiation, however, is invisible because its wavelengths0.1 millimeters-is too long to be registered by the eye</a>
<b>however, the wavelength of infrared radiation-0.1 millimeters-is too long to be registered by the eye making it invisible</b>
<c>infrared radiation, however is invisible because its wavelength-0.1 millimeters-is too long for the eye to register it</c>
<d>however because the wavelength of infrared  radiation is 0.1 millimeters.it is too long for the eye to register and thus invisible</d>
<e>however infrared radiation has a wavelength of 0.1 millimeters that is too long for the eye to register, thus making it invisible</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-107</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>As well as heat and light, the Sun is the source of a continuous stream of atomic particles known as the solar wind.</content>
<a>As well as heat and light,the Sun is the source of a continuous stream</a>
<b>Besides heat and light, also the Sun is the source of a continuous stream</b>
<c>Besides heat and light,the Sun is also the source of a continuous streaming</c>

<d>The Sun is the source not only of heat and light, but also of a continuous stream</d>
<e>The Sun is the source of not only heat and light but, as well,of a continuous streaming</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-108</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Bluegrass musician Bill Monroe,whose repertory, views on musical collaboration, and vocal style were influential on generations of bluegrass artists,was also an inspiration to many musicians, that included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia, whose music differed significantly from his own.</content>
<a>were influential on generations of bluegrass artists,was also an inspiration to many musicians,that included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia,whose music differed significantly from</a>

<b>influenced generations of bluegrass artists, also inspired many musicians, including Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia,whose music differed significantly from</b>
<c>was influential to generations of bluegrass artists,was also inspirational to many musicians,that included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia,whose music was different significantly in comparison to</c>
<d>was influential to generations of bluegrass artists, also inspired many musicians,who included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia,the music of whom differed significantly when compared to</d>
<e>were an influence on generations of bluegrass artists,was also an inspiration to many musicians, including Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia,whose music was significantly different from that of</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-109</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>The nephew of Pliny the Eider wrote the only eyewitness account of the great eruption of Vesuvius in two letters to the historian Tacitus.</content>
<a>The nephew of Pliny the Elder wrote the only eyewitness account of the great eruption of Vesuvius in two letters to the historian Tacitus.</a>
<b>To the historian Tacitus,the nephew of Pliny the Elder wrote two letters, being the only eyewitness accounts of the great eruption of Vesuvius.</b>
<c>The only eyewitness account is in two letters by the nephew of Pliny the Elder writing to the historian Tacitus an account of the great eruption of Vesuvius.</c>
<d>Writing the only eyewitness account,Pliny the Elder's nephew accounted for the great eruption of Vesuvius in two letters to the historian Tacitus.</d>
<e>In two letters to the historian Tacitus,the nephew of Pliny the Elder wrote the only eyewitness account of the great eruption of Vesuvius</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-110</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Being a United States citizen since 1988 and born in Calcutta in 1940, author Bharati Mukherjee has lived in England and Canada, and first came to the United States in 1961 to study at the Iowa Writers' Workshop.</content>
<a>Being a United States citizen since 1988 and born in Calcutta in 1940.author Bharati Mukherjee has</a>
<b>Having been a United States citizen since 1988,she was born in Calcutta in 1940；author Bharati Mukherjee</b>
<c>Born in Calcutta in 1940.author Bharati Mukheree became a United States citizen in 1988; she has</c>
<d>Being born in Calcutta in 1940 and having been a United States citizen since 1988, author Bharati Mukherjee</d>
<e>Having been born in Calcutta in 1940 and being a United States citizen since 1988, author Bharati Mukherjee</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-111</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Initiated five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World on Columbus Day 1992,Project SETI pledged a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence.</content>
<a>Initiated five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World on Columbus Day 1992, project SETI pledged a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence.</a>
<b>Initiated on Columbus Day 1992, five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World, a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence was pledged by Project SETI.</b>
<c>Initiated on Columbus Day 1992, five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World,Project SETI pledged a$100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence.</c>
<d>Pledging a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, the initiation of Project SETI five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World on Columbus Day 1992.</d>

<e>Pledging a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World,on Columbus Day 1992,the initiation of Project SETI took place。</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-112</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In A.D. 391,resulting from the destruction of the largest library of the ancient world at Alexandria,later generations lost all but the Iliad and Odyssey among Greek epics,most of the poetry of Pindar and Sappho, and dozens of plays by Aeschylus and Euripides.</content>
<a>resulting from the destruction of the largest library of the ancient world at Alexandria,</a>
<b>the destroying of the largest library of the ancient world at Alexandria resulted and</b>

<c>because of the result of the destruction of the library at Alexandria,the largest of the ancient world,</c>
<d>as a result of the destruction of the library at Alexandria,the largest of the ancient world,</d>
<e>Alexandria's largest library of the ancient world was destroyed, and the result was</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC2-113</mark>
</item>


</sc>