<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sc>
<item>
<content>	Although a surge in retail sales have raised hopes that there is a recovery finally underway, many economists say that without a large amount of spending the recovery might not last.</content>
<a>have raised hopes that there is a recovery finally</a>
<b>raised hopes for there being a recovery finally</b>

<c>had raised hopes for a recovery finally being</c>
<d>has raised hopes that a recovery is finally</d>
<e>raised hopes for a recovery finally</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-1</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Of all the vast tides of migration that have swept through history, maybe none is more concentrated as the wave that brought 12 million immigrants onto American shores in little more than three decades.</content>

<a>maybe none is more concentrated as</a>
<b>it may be that none is more concentrated as</b>
<c>perhaps it is none that is more concentrated than</c>
<d>maybe it is none that was more concentrated than</d>
<e>perhaps none was more concentrated than</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-2</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Diabetes, together with its serious complications, ranks as the nation's third leading cause of death, surpassed only by heart disease and cancer.</content>
<a>ranks as the nation's third leading cause of death, surpassed only</a>
<b>rank as the nation's third leading cause of death, only surpassed</b>
<c>has the rank of the nation's third leading cause of death, only surpassed</c>
<d>are the nation's third leading causes of death, surpassed only</d>
<e>have been ranked as the nation's third leading causes of death, only surpassed</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-3</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	A survey by the National Council of Churches showed that in 1986 there were 20,736 female ministers, almost 9 percent of the nation's clergy, twice as much as 1977.</content>
<a>twice as much as 1977</a>
<b>twice as many as 1977</b>
<c>double what it was in 1977</c>
<d>double the figure for 1977</d>

<e>a number double that of 1977's</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-4</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	As its sales of computer products have surpassed those of measuring instruments, the company has become increasingly willing to compete for the mass market sales they would in the past have conceded to rivals.</content>
<a>they would in the past have conceded to rivals</a>
<b>they would have conceded previously to their rivals</b>

<c>that in the past would have been conceded previously to rivals</c>
<d>it previously would have conceded to rivals in the past</d>
<e>it would in the past have conceded to rivals</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-5</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Like the idolization accorded the Brontes and Brownings, James Joyce and Virginia Woolf are often subjected to the kind of veneration that blurs the distinction between the artist and the human being.</content>

<a>Like the idolization accorded the Brontes and Brownings</a>
<b>As the Brontes' and Brownings' idolization</b>
<c>Like that accorded to the Brontes and Brownings</c>
<d>As it is of the Brontes and Brownings</d>
<e>Like the Brontes and Brownings</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-6</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Carnivorous mammals can endure what would otherwise be lethal levels of body heat because they have a heat-exchange network which kept the brain from getting too hot.</content>
<a>which kept</a>
<b>that keeps</b>
<c>which has kept</c>
<d>that has been keeping</d>
<e>having kept</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-7</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Rising inventories, when unaccompanied correspondingly by increases in sales, can lead to production cutbacks that would hamper economic growth.</content>
<a>when unaccompanied correspondingly by increases in sales, can lead</a>
<b>when not accompanied by corresponding increases in sales, possibly leads</b>
<c>when they were unaccompanied by corresponding sales increases, can lead</c>
<d>if not accompanied by correspondingly increased sales, possibly leads</d>

<e>if not accompanied by corresponding increases in sales, can lead</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-8</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Sunspots, vortices of gas associated with strong electromagnetic activity, are visible as dark spots on the surface of the Sun but have never been sighted on the Sun's poles or equator.</content>
<a>are visible as dark spots on the surface of the Sun but have never been sighted on</a>
<b>are visible as dark spots that never have been sighted on the surface of the Sun</b>

<c>appear on the surface of the Sun as dark spots although never sighted at</c>
<d>appear as dark spots on the surface of the Sun, although never having been sighted at</d>
<e>appear as dark spots on the Sun's surface, which have never been sighted on</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-9</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Unlike the United States, Japanese unions appear reluctant to organize lower-paid workers.</content>

<a>Unlike the United States, Japanese unions appear reluctant to organize</a>
<b>Unlike those in the United States, Japanese unions appear reluctant to organize</b>
<c>In Japan, unlike the United States, unions appear reluctant about organizing</c>
<d>Japanese unions, unlike the United States, appear reluctant to organize</d>
<e>Japanese unions, unlike those in the United States, appear reluctant about organizing</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-10</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Warning that computers in the United States are not secure, the National Academy of Sciences has urged the nation to revamp computer security procedures, institute new emergency response teams, creating a special nongovernment organization to take charge of computer security planning.</content>
<a>creating a special nongovernment organization to take</a>
<b>creating a special nongovernment organization that takes</b>
<c>creating a special nongovernment organization for taking</c>
<d>and create a special nongovernment organization for taking</d>
<e>and create a special nongovernment organization to take</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-11</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	After gradual declension down to about 39 hours in 1970, the workweek in the United States has steadily increased to the point that the average worker now puts in an estimated 164 extra hours of paid labor a year.</content>
<a>After gradual declension down</a>
<b>Following a gradual declension down</b>
<c>After gradual declining down</c>
<d>After gradually declining</d>

<e>Following gradually declining</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-12</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	As Hurricane Hugo approached the Atlantic coast, it increased dramatically in strength, becoming the tenth most intense hurricane to hit the United States mainland in the twentieth century and most intense since Camille in 1969.</content>
<a>most intense since Camille in 1969</a>
<b>most intense after Camille in 1969</b>

<c>the most intense since Camille in 1969</c>
<d>the most intense after 1969, which had Camille</d>
<e>since 1969 and Camille, the most intense</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-13</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The commission has directed advertisers to restrict the use of the word "natural" to foods that do not contain color or flavor additives, chemical preservatives, or nothing that has been synthesized.</content>

<a>or nothing that has been</a>
<b>or that has been</b>
<c>and nothing that is</c>
<d>or anything that has been</d>
<e>and anything</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-14</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The Iroquois were primarily planters, but supplementing their cultivation of maize, squash, and beans with fishing and hunting.</content>
<a>but supplementing</a>
<b>and had supplemented</b>
<c>and even though they supplemented</c>
<d>although they supplemented</d>
<e>but with supplementing</e>
<answer>D</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-15</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	As contrasted with the honeybee, the yellow jacket can sting repeatedly without dying and carries a potent venom that can cause intense pain.</content>
<a>As contrasted with the honeybee</a>
<b>In contrast to the honeybee's</b>
<c>Unlike the sting of the honeybee</c>
<d>Unlike that of the honeybee</d>

<e>Unlike the honeybee</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-16</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	None of the attempts to specify the causes of crime explains why most of the people exposed to the alleged causes do not commit crimes and, conversely, why so many of those not so exposed have.</content>
<a>have</a>
<b>has</b>

<c>shall</c>
<d>do</d>
<e>could</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-17</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Computers are becoming faster, more powerful, and more reliable, and so too are modems, they are the devices to allow two or more computers to share information over regular telephone lines.</content>

<a>so too are modems, they are the devices to allow</a>
<b>so too are modems, the devices that allow</b>
<c>so too modems, the devices allowing</c>
<d>also modems, they are the devices that allow</d>
<e>also modems, which are the devices to allow</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-18</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In virtually all types of tissue in every animal species, dioxin induces the production of enzymes that are the organism's trying to metabolize, or render harmless, the chemical that is irritating it.</content>
<a>trying to metabolize, or render harmless, the chemical that is irritating it</a>
<b>trying that it metabolize, or render harmless, the chemical irritant</b>
<c>attempt to try to metabolize, or render harmless, such a chemical irritant</c>
<d>attempt to try and metabolize, or render harmless, the chemical irritating it</d>
<e>attempt to metabolize, or render harmless, the chemical irritant</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-19</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Based on accounts of various ancient writers, scholars have painted a sketchy picture of the activities of an all-female cult that, perhaps as early as the sixth century BC, worshipped a goddess known in Latin as Bona Dea, "the good goddess."</content>
<a>Based on accounts of various ancient writers</a>
<b>Basing it on various ancient writers' accounts</b>
<c>With accounts of various ancient writers used for a basis</c>
<d>By the accounts of various ancient writers they used</d>

<e>Using accounts of various ancient writers</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-20</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Paleontologists believe that fragments of a primate jawbone unearthed in Burma and estimated at 40 to 44 million years old provide evidence of a crucial step along the evolutionary path that led to human beings.</content>
<a>at 40 to 44 million years old provide evidence of</a>
<b>as being 40 to 44 million years old provides evidence of</b>

<c>that it is 40 to 44 million years old provides evidence of what was</c>
<d>to be 40 to 44 million years old provide evidence of</d>
<e>as 40 to 44 million years old provides evidence of what was</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-21</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The end of the eighteenth century saw the emergence of prize-stock breeding, with individual bulls and cows receiving awards, fetching unprecedented prices, and excited enormous interest whenever they were put on show.</content>

<a>excited</a>
<b>it excited</b>
<c>exciting</c>
<d>would excite</d>
<e>it had excited</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-22</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Of all the possible disasters that threaten American agriculture, the possibility of an adverse change in climate is maybe the more difficult for analysis.</content>
<a>is maybe the more difficult for analysis</a>
<b>is probably the most difficult to analyze</b>
<c>is maybe the most difficult for analysis</c>
<d>is probably the more difficult to analyze</d>
<e>is, it may be, the analysis that is most difficult</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-23</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	For members of the seventeenth-century Ashanti nation in Africa, animal-hide shields with wooden frames were essential items of military equipment, a method to protect warriors against enemy arrows and spears.</content>
<a>a method to protect</a>
<b>as a method protecting</b>
<c>protecting</c>
<d>as a protection of</d>

<e>to protect</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-24</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The golden crab of the Gulf of Mexico has not been fished commercially in great numbers, primarily on account of living at great depths-2,500 to 3,000 feet down.</content>
<a>on account of living</a>
<b>on account of their living</b>

<c>because it lives</c>
<d>because of living</d>
<e>being they live</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-25</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Galileo was convinced that natural phenomena, as manifestations of the laws of physics, would appear the same to someone on the deck of a ship moving smoothly and uniformly through the water as a person standing on land.</content>

<a>water as a</a>
<b>water as to a</b>
<c>water; just as it would to a</c>
<d>water, as it would to the</d>
<e>water; just as to the</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-26</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Health officials estimate that 35 million Africans are in danger of contracting trypanosomiasis, or "African sleeping sickness," a parasitic disease spread by the bites of tsetse flies.</content>
<a>are in danger of contracting</a>
<b>are in danger to contract</b>
<c>have a danger of contracting</c>
<d>are endangered by contraction</d>
<e>have a danger that they will contract</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-27</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Beyond the immediate cash flow crisis that the museum faces, its survival depends on if it can broaden its membership and leave its cramped quarters for a site where it can store and exhibit its more than 12,000 artifacts.</content>
<a>if it can broaden its membership and leave</a>
<b>whether it can broaden its membership and leave</b>
<c>whether or not it has the capability to broaden its membership and can leave</c>
<d>its ability for broadening its membership and leaving</d>

<e>the ability for it to broaden its membership and leave</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-28</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Along with the drop in producer prices announced yesterday, the strong retail sales figures released today seem like it is indicative that the economy, although growing slowly, is not nearing a recession.</content>
<a>like it is indicative that</a>
<b>as if to indicate</b>

<c>to indicate that</c>
<d>indicative of</d>
<e>like an indication of</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-29</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	An inventory equal to 90 days sales is as much as even the strongest businesses carry, and then only as a way to anticipate higher prices or ensure against shortages.</content>

<a>as much as even</a>
<b>so much as even</b>
<c>even so much as</c>
<d>even as much that</d>
<e>even so much that</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-30</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Egyptians are credited as having pioneered embalming methods as long ago as 2650 BC.</content>
<a>as having</a>
<b>with having</b>
<c>to have</c>
<d>as the ones who</d>
<e>for being the ones who</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-31</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The Commerce Department announced that the economy grew during the second quarter at a 7.5 percent annual rate, while inflation eased when it might have been expected for it to rise.</content>
<a>it might have been expected for it to rise</a>
<b>it might have been expected to rise</b>
<c>it might have been expected that it should rise</c>
<d>its rise might have been expected</d>

<e>there might have been an expectation it would rise</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-32</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Although schistosomiasis is not often fatal, it is so debilitating that it has become an economic drain on many developing countries.</content>
<a>it is so debilitating that it has become an economic</a>
<b>it is of such debilitation, it has become an economical</b>

<c>so debilitating is it as to become an economic</c>
<d>such is its debilitation, it becomes an economical</d>
<e>there is so much debilitation that it has become an economical</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-33</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Efforts to equalize the funds available to school districts, a major goal of education reformers and many states in the 1970's, has not significantly reduced the gaps existing between the richest and poorest districts.</content>

<a>has not significantly reduced the gaps existing</a>
<b>has not been significant in reducing the gap that exists</b>
<c>has not made a significant reduction in the gap that exists</c>
<d>have not significantly reduced the gap that exists</d>
<e>have not been significant in a reduction of the gaps existing</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-34</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Federal authorities involved in the investigation have found the local witnesses are difficult to locate, reticent, and are suspicious of strangers.</content>
<a>the local witnesses are difficult to locate, reticent, and are</a>
<b>local witnesses to be difficult to locate, reticent, and are</b>
<c>that local witnesses are difficult to locate, reticent, and</c>
<d>local witnesses are difficult to locate and reticent, and they are</d>
<e>that local witnesses are difficult to locate and reticent, and they are</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-35</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In 1527 King Henry VIII sought to have his marriage to Queen Catherine annulled so as to marry Anne Boleyn.</content>
<a>so as to marry</a>
<b>and so could be married to</b>
<c>to be married to</c>
<d>so that he could marry</d>

<e>in order that he would marry</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-36</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In one of the bloodiest battles of the Civil War, fought at Sharpsburg, Maryland, on September 17, 1862, four times as many Americans were killed as would later be killed on the beaches of Normandy during D-Day.</content>
<a>Americans were killed as</a>
<b>Americans were killed than</b>

<c>Americans were killed than those who</c>
<d>more Americans were killed as there</d>
<e>more Americans were killed as those who</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-37</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Dr. Tonegawa won the Nobel Prize for discovering how the body can constantly change its genes to fashion a seeming unlimited number of antibodies, each specifically targeted at an invading microbe or foreign substance.</content>

<a>seeming unlimited number of antibodies, each specifically targeted at</a>
<b>seeming unlimited number of antibodies, each targeted specifically to</b>
<c>seeming unlimited number of antibodies, all specifically targeted at</c>
<d>seemingly unlimited number of antibodies, all of them targeted specifically to</d>
<e>seemingly unlimited number of antibodies, each targeted specifically at</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-38</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Scientists have recently discovered what could be the largest and oldest living organism on Earth, a giant fungus that is an interwoven filigree of mushrooms and rootlike tentacles spawned by a single fertilized spore some 10,000 years ago and extending for more than 30 acres in the soil of a Michigan forest.</content>
<a>extending</a>
<b>extends</b>
<c>extended</c>
<d>it extended</d>
<e>is extending</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-39</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The plot of The Bostonians centers on the rivalry between Olive Chancellor, an active feminist, with her charming and cynical cousin, Basil Ransom, when they find themselves drawn to the same radiant young woman whose talent for public speaking has won her an ardent following.</content>
<a>rivalry between Olive Chancellor, an active feminist, with her charming and cynical cousin, Basil Ransom</a>
<b>rivals Olive Chancellor, an active feminist, against her charming and cynical cousin, Basil Ransom</b>
<c>rivalry that develops between Olive Chancellor, an active feminist, and Basil Ransom, her charming and cynical cousin</c>
<d>developing rivalry between Olive Chancellor, an active feminist, with Basil Ransom, her charming and cynical cousin</d>

<e>active feminist, Olive Chancellor, and the rivalry with her charming and cynical cousin Basil Ransom</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-40</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	While larger banks can afford to maintain their own data-processing operations, many smaller regional and community banks are finding that the cost associated with upgrading data-processing equipment and with the development and maintenance of new products and technical staff are prohibitive.</content>
<a>cost associated with</a>
<b>costs associated with</b>

<c>costs arising from</c>
<d>cost of</d>
<e>costs of</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-41</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Quasars, at billions of light-years from Earth the most distant observable objects in the universe, believed to be the cores of galaxies in an early stage of development.</content>

<a>believed to be</a>
<b>are believed to be</b>
<c>some believe them to be</c>
<d>some believe they are</d>
<e>it is believed that they are</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-42</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Five fledgling sea eagles left their nests in western Scotland this summer, bringing to 34 the number of wild birds successfully raised since transplants from Norway began in 1975.</content>
<a>bringing</a>
<b>and brings</b>
<c>and it brings</c>
<d>and it brought</d>
<e>and brought</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-43</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The automotive conveyor-belt system, which Henry Ford modeled after an assembly-line technique introduced by Ransom Olds, reduced from a day and a half to 93 minutes the required time of assembling a Model T.</content>
<a>from a day and a half to 93 minutes the required time of assembling a Model T</a>
<b>the time being required to assemble a Model T, from a day and a half down to 93 minutes</b>
<c>the time being required to assemble a Model T, a day and a half to 93 minutes</c>
<d>the time required to assemble a Model T from a day and a half to 93 minutes</d>

<e>from a day and a half to 93 minutes, the time required for the assembling of a Model T</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-44</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	According to some analysts, the gains in the stock market reflect growing confidence that the economy will avoid the recession that many had feared earlier in the year and instead come in for a "soft landing," followed by a gradual increase in business activity.</content>
<a>that the economy will avoid the recession that many had feared earlier in the year and instead come</a>
<b>in the economy to avoid the recession, what many feared earlier in the year, rather to come</b>

<c>in the economy's ability to avoid the recession, something earlier in the year many had feared, and instead to come</c>
<d>in the economy to avoid the recession many were fearing earlier in the year, and rather to come</d>
<e>that the economy will avoid the recession that was feared earlier this year by many, with it instead coming</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-45</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	To Josephine Baker, Paris was her home long before it was fashionable to be an expatriate, and she remained in France during the Second World War as a performer and an intelligence agent for the Resistance.</content>

<a>To Josephine Baker, Paris was her home long before it was fashionable to be an expatriate</a>
<b>For Josephine Baker, long before it was fashionable to be an expatriate, Paris was her home</b>
<c>Josephine Baker made Paris her home long before to be an expatriate was fashionable</c>
<d>Long before it was fashionable to be an expatriate, Josephine Baker made Paris her home</d>
<e>Long before it was fashionable being an expatriate, Paris was home to Josephine Baker</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-46</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	By providing such services as mortgages, home improvement loans, automobile loans, financial advice, and staying within the metropolitan areas, Acme Bank has become one of the most profitable savings banks in the nation.</content>
<a>financial advice, and staying</a>
<b>financial advice, and by staying</b>
<c>and financial advice, staying</c>
<d>and financial advice, and staying</d>
<e>and financial advice, and by staying</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-47</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The report recommended that the hospital should eliminate unneeded beds, expensive services should be consolidated, and use space in other hospitals.</content>
<a>should eliminate unneeded beds, expensive services should be consolidated, and use space in other hospitals</a>
<b>should eliminate unneeded beds, expensive services should be consolidated, and other hospitals' space be used</b>
<c>should eliminate unneeded beds, expensive services should be consolidated, and to use space in other hospitals</c>
<d>eliminate unneeded beds, consolidate expensive services, and other hospitals' space used</d>

<e>eliminate unneeded beds, consolidate expensive services, and use space in other hospitals</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-48</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Many house builders offer rent-to-buy programs that enable a family with insufficient savings for a conventional down payment to be able to move into new housing and to apply part of the rent to a purchase later.</content>
<a>programs that enable a family with insufficient savings for a conventional down payment to be able to move into new housing and to apply</a>
<b>programs that enable a family with insufficient savings for a conventional down payment to move into new housing and to apply</b>

<c>programs; that enables a family with insufficient savings for a conventional down payment to move into new housing, to apply</c>
<d>programs, which enables a family with insufficient savings for a conventional down payment to move into new housing, applying</d>
<e>programs, which enable a family with insufficient savings for a conventional down payment to be able to move into new housing, applying</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-49</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	That educators have not anticipated the impact of microcomputer technology can hardly be said that it is their fault: Alvin Toffler, one of the most prominent students of the future, did not even mention microcomputers in Future Shock, published in 1970.</content>

<a>That educators have not anticipated the impact of microcomputer technology can hardly be said that it is their fault</a>
<b>That educators have not anticipated the impact of microcomputer technology can hardly be said to be at fault</b>
<c>It can hardly be said that it is the fault of educators who have not anticipated the impact of microcomputer technology</c>
<d>It can hardly be said that educators are at fault for not anticipating the impact of microcomputer technology</d>
<e>The fact that educators are at fault for not anticipating the impact of microcomputer technology can hardly be said</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-50</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The Olympic Games helped to keep peace among the pugnacious states of the Greek world in that a sacred truce was proclaimed during the festival's month.</content>
<a>world in that a sacred truce was proclaimed during the festival's month</a>
<b>world, proclaiming a sacred truce during the festival's month</b>
<c>world when they proclaimed a sacred truce for the festival month</c>
<d>world, for a sacred truce was proclaimed during the month of the festival</d>
<e>world by proclamation of a sacred truce that was for the month of the festival</e>
<answer>D</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-51</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	While all states face similar industrial waste problems, the predominating industries and the regulatory environment of the states obviously determines the types and amounts of waste produced, as well as the cost of disposal.</content>
<a>all states face similar industrial waste problems, the predominating industries and the regulatory environment of the states obviously determines</a>
<b>each state faces a similar industrial waste problem, their predominant industries and regulatory environment obviously determine</b>
<c>all states face a similar industrial waste problem; their predominating industries and regulatory environment obviously determines</c>
<d>each state faces similar industrial waste problems, the predominant industries and the regulatory environment of each state obviously determines</d>

<e>all states face similar industrial waste problems, the predominant industries and the regulatory environment of each state obviously determine</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-52</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Section 13(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 requires anyone who buys more than 5 percent of a company's stock make a public disclosure of the purchase.</content>
<a>make</a>
<b>will also make</b>

<c>to make</c>
<d>must make</d>
<e>must then make</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-53</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	When Congress reconvenes, some newly elected members from rural states will try and establish tighter restrictions for the amount of grain farmers are to be allowed to grow and to encourage more aggressive sales of United States farm products overseas.</content>

<a>and establish tighter restrictions for the amount of grain farmers are to be allowed to grow and to encourage</a>
<b>and establish tighter restrictions on the amount of grain able to be grown by farmers and encouraging</b>
<c>establishing tighter restrictions for the amount of grain farmers are allowed to grow and to encourage</c>
<d>to establish tighter restrictions on the amount of grain capable of being grown by farmers and encouraging</d>
<e>to establish tighter restrictions on the amount of grain farmers will be allowed to grow and to encourage</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-54</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Doctors generally agree that such factors as cigarette smoking, eating rich foods high in fats, and alcohol consumption not only do damage by themselves but also aggravate genetic predispositions toward certain diseases.</content>
<a>not only do damage by themselves but also aggravate</a>
<b>do damage by themselves but also are aggravating to</b>
<c>are damaging by themselves but also are aggravating</c>
<d>not only do damage by themselves, they are also aggravating to</d>
<e>are doing damage by themselves, and they are also aggravating</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-55</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In a plan to stop the erosion of East Coast beaches, the Army Corps of Engineers proposed building parallel to shore a breakwater of rocks that would rise six feet above the waterline and act as a buffer, so that it absorbs the energy of crashing waves and protecting the beaches.</content>
<a>act as a buffer, so that it absorbs</a>
<b>act like a buffer so as to absorb</b>
<c>act as a buffer, absorbing</c>
<d>acting as a buffer, absorbing</d>

<e>acting like a buffer, absorb</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-56</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Affording strategic proximity to the Strait of Gibraltar, Morocco was also of interest to the French throughout the first half of the twentieth century because they assumed that if they did not hold it, their grip on Algeria was always insecure.</content>
<a>if they did not hold it, their grip on Algeria was always insecure</a>
<b>without it their grip on Algeria would never be secure</b>

<c>their grip on Algeria was not ever secure if they did not hold it</c>
<d>without that, they could never be secure about their grip on Algeria</d>
<e>never would their grip on Algeria be secure if they did not hold it</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-57</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Once they had seen the report from the medical examiner, the investigators did not doubt whether the body recovered from the river was the man who had attempted to escape from the state prison.</content>

<a>did not doubt whether the body recovered from the river was</a>
<b>have no doubt whether the body recovered from the river was</b>
<c>had not doubted that the body recovered from the river was</c>
<d>have no doubt whether the body recovered from the river was that of</d>
<e>had no doubt that the body recovered from the river was that of</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-58</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	His studies of ice-polished rocks in his Alpine homeland, far outside the range of present-day glaciers, led Louis Agassiz in 1837 to propose the concept of an age in which great ice sheets had existed in now currently temperate areas.</content>
<a>in which great ice sheets had existed in now currently temperate areas</a>
<b>in which great ice sheets existed in what are now temperate areas</b>
<c>when great ice sheets existed where there were areas now temperate</c>
<d>when great ice sheets had existed in current temperate areas</d>
<e>when great ice sheets existed in areas now that are temperate</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-59</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	More and more in recent years, cities are stressing the arts as a means to greater economic development and investing millions of dollars in cultural activities, despite strained municipal budgets and fading federal support.</content>
<a>to greater economic development and investing</a>
<b>to greater development economically and investing</b>
<c>of greater economic development and invest</c>
<d>of greater development economically and invest</d>

<e>for greater economic development and the investment of</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-60</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Since 1986 enrollments of African Americans, American Indians, and Hispanic Americans in full time engineering programs in the United States has steadily increased, while the number of other students who enter the field has fallen.</content>
<a>has steadily increased, while the number of other students who enter the field has fallen</a>
<b>has steadily increased, while other students entering the field have declined in number</b>

<c>increased steadily, while there was a decline in the number of other students entering the field</c>
<d>have steadily increased, while the number of other students entering the field has fallen</d>
<e>have steadily increased, while that of other students who enter the field fell</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-61</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	A 1972 agreement between Canada and the United States reduced the amount of phosphates that municipalities had been allowed to dump into the Great Lakes.</content>

<a>reduced the amount of phosphates that municipalities had been allowed to dump</a>
<b>reduced the phosphate amount that municipalities had been dumping</b>
<c>reduces the phosphate amount municipalities have been allowed to dump</c>
<d>reduced the amount of phosphates that municipalities are allowed to dump</d>
<e>reduces the amount of phosphates allowed for dumping by municipalities</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-62</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	A proposal has been made to trim the horns from rhinoceroses to discourage poachers; the question is whether tourists will continue to visit game parks and see rhinoceroses after their horns are trimmed.</content>
<a>whether tourists will continue to visit game parks and see rhinoceroses after their horns are</a>
<b>whether tourists will continue to visit game parks to see one once their horns are</b>
<c>whether tourists will continue to visit game parks to see rhinoceroses once the animals' horns have been</c>
<d>if tourists will continue to visit game parks and see rhinoceroses once the animals' horns are</d>
<e>if tourists will continue to visit game parks to see one after the animals' horns have been</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-63</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The technical term "pagination" is a process that leaves editors, instead of printers, assemble the page images that become the metal or plastic plates used in printing.</content>
<a>is a process that leaves editors, instead of printers, assemble</a>
<b>refers to a process that allows editors, rather than printers, to assemble</b>
<c>is a process leaving the editors, rather than printers, to assemble</c>
<d>refers to a process which allows editors, but not to printers, the assembly of</d>

<e>has reference to the process leaving to editors, instead of the printer, assembling</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-64</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The only way for growers to salvage frozen citrus is to process them quickly into juice concentrate before they rot when warmer weather returns.</content>
<a>to process them quickly into juice concentrate before they rot when warmer weather returns</a>
<b>if they are quickly processed into juice concentrate before warmer weather returns to rot them</b>

<c>for them to be processed quickly into juice concentrate before the fruit rots when warmer weather returns</c>
<d>if the fruit is quickly processed into juice concentrate before they rot when warmer weather returns</d>
<e>to have it quickly processed into juice concentrate before warmer weather returns and rots the fruit</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-65</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Unlike a typical automobile loan, which requires a 15 to 20 percent down payment, the lease-loan buyer is not required to make an initial deposit on the new vehicle.</content>

<a>the lease-loan buyer is not required to make</a>
<b>with lease-loan buying there is no requirement of</b>
<c>lease-loan buyers are not required to make</c>
<d>for the lease-loan buyer there is no requirement of</d>
<e>a lease-loan does not require the buyer to make</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-66</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Defense attorneys have occasionally argued that their clients' misconduct stemmed from a reaction to something ingested, but in attributing criminal or delinquent behavior to some food allergy, the perpetrators are in effect told that they are not responsible for their actions.</content>
<a>in attributing criminal or delinquent behavior to some food allergy</a>
<b>if criminal or delinquent behavior is attributed to an allergy to some food</b>
<c>in attributing behavior that is criminal or delinquent to an allergy to some food</c>
<d>if some food allergy is attributed as the cause of criminal or delinquent behavior</d>
<e>in attributing a food allergy as the cause of criminal or delinquent behavior</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-67</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Unlike computer skills or other technical skills, there is a disinclination on the part of many people to recognize the degree to which their analytical skills are weak.</content>
<a>Unlike computer skills or other technical skills, there is a disinclination on the part of many people to recognize the degree to which their analytical skills are weak.</a>
<b>Unlike computer skills or other technical skills, which they admit they lack, many people are disinclined to recognize that their analytical skills are weak.</b>
<c>Unlike computer skills or other technical skills, analytical skills bring out a disinclination in many people to recognize that they are weak to a degree.</c>
<d>Many people, willing to admit that they lack computer skills or other technical skills, are disinclined to recognize that their analytical skills are weak.</d>

<e>Many people have a disinclination to recognize the weakness of their analytical skills while willing to admit their lack of computer skills or other technical skills.</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-68</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	A report by the American Academy for the Advancement of Science has concluded that much of the currently uncontrolled dioxins to which North Americans are exposed comes from the incineration of wastes.</content>
<a>much of the currently uncontrolled dioxins to which North Americans are exposed comes</a>
<b>much of the currently uncontrolled dioxins that North Americans are exposed to come</b>

<c>much of the dioxins that are currently uncontrolled and that North Americans are exposed to comes</c>
<d>many of the dioxins that are currently uncontrolled and North Americans are exposed to come</d>
<e>many of the currently uncontrolled dioxins to which North Americans are exposed come</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-69</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Displays of the aurora borealis, or "northern lights," can heat the atmosphere over the Arctic enough to affect the trajectories of ballistic missiles, induce electric currents that can cause blackouts in some areas and corrosion in north-south pipelines.</content>

<a>to affect the trajectories of ballistic missiles, induce</a>
<b>that the trajectories of ballistic missiles are affected, induce</b>
<c>that it affects the trajectories of ballistic missiles, induces</c>
<d>that the trajectories of ballistic missiles are affected and induces</d>
<e>to affect the trajectories of ballistic missiles and induce</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-70</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The cameras of the Voyager II spacecraft detected six small, previously unseen moons circling Uranus, which doubles to 12 the number of satellites now known as orbiting the distant planet.</content>
<a>which doubles to 12 the number of satellites now known as orbiting</a>
<b>doubling to 12 the number of satellites now known to orbit</b>
<c>which doubles to 12 the number of satellites now known in orbit around</c>
<d>doubling to 12 the number of satellites now known as orbiting</d>
<e>which doubles to 12 the number of satellites now known that orbit</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-71</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Architects and stonemasons, huge palace and temple clusters were built by the Maya without benefit of the wheel or animal transport.</content>
<a>huge palace and temple clusters were built by the Maya without benefit of the wheel or animal transport</a>
<b>without the benefits of animal transport or the wheel, huge palace and temple clusters were built by the Maya</b>
<c>the Maya built huge palace and temple clusters without the benefit of animal transport or the wheel</c>
<d>there were built, without the benefit of the wheel or animal transport, huge palace and temple clusters by the Maya</d>

<e>were the Maya who, without the benefit of the wheel or animal transport, built huge palace and temple clusters</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-72</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	According to a recent poll, owning and living in a freestanding house on its own land is still a goal of a majority of young adults, like that of earlier generations.</content>
<a>like that of earlier generations</a>
<b>as that for earlier generations</b>

<c>just as earlier generations did</c>
<d>as have earlier generations</d>
<e>as it was of earlier generations</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-73</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Often visible as smog, ozone is formed in the atmosphere from hydrocarbons and nitrogen oxides, two major pollutants emitted by automobiles, react with sunlight.</content>

<a>ozone is formed in the atmosphere from</a>
<b>ozone is formed in the atmosphere when</b>
<c>ozone is formed in the atmosphere, and when</c>
<d>ozone, formed in the atmosphere when</d>
<e>ozone, formed in the atmosphere from</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-74</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Salt deposits and moisture threaten to destroy the Mohenjo-Daro excavation in Pakistan, the site of an ancient civilization that flourished at the same time as the civilizations in the Nile delta and the river valleys of the Tigris and Euphrates.</content>
<a>that flourished at the same time as the civilizations</a>
<b>that had flourished at the same time as had the civilizations</b>
<c>that flourished at the same time those had</c>
<d>flourishing at the same time as those did</d>
<e>flourishing at the same time as those were</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-75</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Never before had taxpayers confronted so many changes at once as they had in the Tax Reform Act of 1986.</content>
<a>so many changes at once as they had in</a>
<b>at once as many changes as</b>
<c>at once as many changes that there were with</c>
<d>as many changes at once as they confronted in</d>

<e>so many changes at once that confronted them in</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-76</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Even though the direct costs of malpractice disputes amounts to a sum lower than 1 percent of the $541 billion the nation spent on health care last year, doctors say fear of lawsuits plays a major role in health-care inflation.</content>
<a>amounts to a sum lower</a>
<b>amounts to less</b>

<c>amounted to less</c>
<d>amounted to lower</d>
<e>amounted to a lower sum</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-77</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Visitors to the park have often looked up into the leafy canopy and saw monkeys sleeping on the branches, whose arms and legs hang like socks on a clothesline.</content>

<a>saw monkeys sleeping on the branches, whose arms and legs hang</a>
<b>saw monkeys sleeping on the branches, whose arms and legs were hanging</b>
<c>saw monkeys sleeping on the branches, with arms and legs hanging</c>
<d>seen monkeys sleeping on the branches, with arms and legs hanging</d>
<e>seen monkeys sleeping on the branches, whose arms and legs have hung</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-78</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The Parthenon was a church from 1204 until 1456, when Athens was taken by General Mohammed the Conqueror, the Turkish sultan, who established a mosque in the building and used the Acropolis as a fortress.</content>
<a>who established a mosque in the building and used the Acropolis as</a>
<b>who, establishing a mosque in the building, used the Acropolis like</b>
<c>who, when he had established a mosque in the building, used the Acropolis like</c>
<d>who had established a mosque in the building, using the Acropolis to be</d>
<e>establishing a mosque in the building and using the Acropolis as</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-79</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	New hardy varieties of rice show promise of producing high yields without the costly requirements of irrigation and application of commercial fertilizer by earlier high-yielding varieties.</content>
<a>requirements of irrigation and application of commercial fertilizer by earlier high  yielding varieties</a>
<b>requirements by earlier high-yielding varieties of application of commercial fertilizer and irrigation</b>
<c>requirements for application of commercial fertilizer and irrigation of earlier high  yielding varieties</c>
<d>application of commercial fertilizer and irrigation that was required by earlier high  yielding varieties</d>

<e>irrigation and application of commercial fertilizer that were required by earlier high  yielding varieties</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-80</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In an effort to reduce their inventories, Italian vintners have cut prices; their wines have been priced to sell, and they are.</content>
<a>have been priced to sell, and they are</a>
<b>are priced to sell, and they have</b>

<c>are priced to sell, and they do</c>
<d>are being priced to sell, and have</d>
<e>had been priced to sell, and they have</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-81</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Senator Lasker has proposed legislation requiring that employers should retain all older workers indefinitely or show just cause for dismissal.</content>

<a>that employers should retain all older workers</a>
<b>that all older workers be retained by employers</b>
<c>the retaining by employers of all older workers</c>
<d>employers' retention of all older workers</d>
<e>employers to retain all older workers</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-82</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Most state constitutions now mandate that the state budget be balanced each year.</content>
<a>mandate that the state budget be balanced</a>
<b>mandate the state budget to be balanced</b>
<c>mandate that the state budget will be balanced</c>
<d>have a mandate for a balanced state budget</d>
<e>have a mandate to balance the state budget</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-83</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Under the Safe Drinking Water Act, the Environmental Protection Agency is required either to approve individual state plans for controlling the discharge of wastes into underground water or that they enforce their own plan for states without adequate regulations.</content>
<a>that they enforce their</a>
<b>for enforcing their</b>
<c>they should enforce their</c>
<d>it should enforce its</d>

<e>to enforce its</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-84</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Dirt roads may evoke the bucolic simplicity of another century, but financially strained townships point out that dirt roads cost twice as much as maintaining paved roads.</content>
<a>dirt roads cost twice as much as maintaining paved roads</a>
<b>dirt roads cost twice as much to maintain as paved roads do</b>

<c>maintaining dirt roads costs twice as much as paved roads do</c>
<d>maintaining dirt roads costs twice as much as it does for paved roads</d>
<e>to maintain dirt roads costs twice as much as for paved roads</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-85</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Although early soap operas were first aired on evening radio in the 1920's, they had moved to the daytime hours of the 1930's when the evening schedule became crowded with comedians and variety shows.</content>

<a>were first aired on evening radio in the 1920's, they had moved to the daytime hours of the 1930's</a>
<b>were first aired on evening radio in the 1920's, they were moved to the daytime hours in the 1930's</b>

<c>were aired first on evening radio in the 1920's, moving to the daytime hours in the 1930's</c>
<d>were aired first in the evening on 1920's radio, they moved to the daytime hours of the 1930's</d>
<e>aired on evening radio first in the 1920's, they were moved to the 1930's in the daytime hours</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-86</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The energy source on Voyager 2 is not a nuclear reactor, in which atoms are actively broken apart; rather a kind of nuclear battery that uses natural radioactive decay to produce power.</content>
<a>apart; rather</a>
<b>apart, but rather</b>
<c>apart, but rather that of</c>
<d>apart, but that of</d>
<e>apart; it is that of</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-87</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The recent surge in the number of airplane flights has clogged the nation's air-traffic control system, to lead to 55 percent more delays at airports, and prompts fears among some officials that safety is being compromised.</content>
<a>to lead to 55 percent more delays at airports, and prompts</a>
<b>leading to 55 percent more delay at airports and prompting</b>
<c>to lead to a 55 percent increase in delay at airports and prompt</c>
<d>to lead to an increase of 55 percent in delays at airports, and prompted</d>

<e>leading to a 55 percent increase in delays at airports and prompting</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-88</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Presenters at the seminar, one who is blind, will demonstrate adaptive equipment that allows visually impaired people to use computers.</content>
<a>one who</a>
<b>one of them who</b>

<c>and one of them who</c>
<d>one of whom</d>
<e>one of which</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-89</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The peaks of a mountain range, acting like rocks in a streambed, produce ripples in the air flowing over them; the resulting flow pattern, with crests and troughs that remain stationary although the air that forms them is moving rapidly, are known as "standing waves."</content>

<a>crests and troughs that remain stationary although the air that forms them is moving rapidly, are</a>
<b>crests and troughs that remain stationary although they are formed by rapidly moving air, are</b>
<c>crests and troughs that remain stationary although the air that forms them is moving rapidly, is</c>
<d>stationary crests and troughs although the air that forms them is moving rapidly, are</d>
<e>stationary crests and troughs although they are formed by rapidly moving air, is</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-90</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The Senate approved immigration legislation that would grant permanent residency to millions of aliens currently residing here and if employers hired illegal aliens they would be penalized.</content>
<a>if employers hired illegal aliens they would be penalized</a>
<b>hiring illegal aliens would be a penalty for employers</b>
<c>penalize employers who hire illegal aliens</c>
<d>penalizing employers hiring illegal aliens</d>
<e>employers to be penalized for hiring illegal aliens</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-91</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Despite protests from some waste-disposal companies, state health officials have ordered the levels of bacteria in seawater at popular beaches to be measured and that the results be published.</content>
<a>the levels of bacteria in seawater at popular beaches to be measured and that the results be</a>
<b>that seawater at popular beaches should be measured for their levels of bacteria, with the results being</b>
<c>the measure of levels of bacteria in seawater at popular beaches and the results to be</c>
<d>seawater measured at popular beaches for levels of bacteria, with their results</d>

<e>that the levels of bacteria in seawater at popular beaches be measured and the results</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-92</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	By a vote of 9 to 0, the Supreme Court awarded the Central Intelligence Agency broad discretionary powers enabling it to withhold from the public the identities of its sources of intelligence information.</content>
<a>enabling it to withhold from the public</a>
<b>for it to withhold from the public</b>

<c>for withholding disclosure to the public of</c>
<d>that enable them to withhold from public disclosure</d>
<e>that they can withhold public disclosure of</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-93</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The Coast Guard is conducting tests to see whether pigeons can be trained to help find survivors of wrecks at sea.</content>

<a>to see whether pigeons can be trained to help find</a>
<b>to see whether pigeons can be trained as help to find</b>
<c>to see if pigeons can be trained for helping to find</c>
<d>that see if pigeons are able to be trained in helping to find</d>
<e>that see whether pigeons are able to be trained for help in finding</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-94</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Unlike Schoenberg's 12-tone system that dominated the music of the postwar period, Bartok founded no school and left behind only a handful of disciples.</content>
<a>Schoenberg's 12-tone system that dominated</a>
<b>Schoenberg and his 12-tone system which dominated</b>
<c>Schoenberg, whose 12-tone system dominated</c>
<d>the 12-tone system of Schoenberg that has dominated</d>
<e>Schoenberg and the 12-tone system, dominating</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-95</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Ranked as one of the most important of Europe's young playwrights, Franz Xaver Kroetz has written 40 plays; his workstranslated into more than 30 languagesare produced more often than any contemporary German dramatist.</content>
<a>than any</a>
<b>than any other</b>
<c>than are any</c>
<d>than those of any other</d>

<e>as are those of any</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-96</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The stars, some of them at tremendous speeds, are in motion just as the planets are, yet being so far away from Earth that their apparent positions in the sky do not change enough for their movement to be observed during a single human lifetime.</content>
<a>The stars, some of them at tremendous speeds, are in motion just as the planets are, yet being</a>
<b>Like the planets, the stars are in motion, some of them at tremendous speeds, but they are</b>

<c>Although like the planets the stars are in motion, some of them at tremendous speeds, yet</c>
<d>As the planets, the stars are in motion, some of them at tremendous speeds, but they are</d>
<e>The stars are in motion like the planets, some of which at tremendous speeds are in motion but</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-97</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	As rainfall began to decrease in the Southwest about the middle of the twelfth century, most of the Monument Valley Anasazi abandoned their homes to join other clans whose access to water was less limited.</content>

<a>whose access to water was less limited</a>
<b>where there was access to water that was less limited</b>
<c>where they had less limited water access</c>
<d>with less limitations on water access</d>
<e>having less limitations to water access</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-98</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Just as reading Samuel Pepys's diary gives a student a sense of the seventeenth centuryof its texture and psycheso Jane Freed's guileless child narrator takes the operagoer inside turn-of-the  century Vienna.</content>
<a>so Jane Freed's guileless child narrator takes the operagoer</a>
<b>so listening to Jane Freed's guileless child narrator takes the operagoer</b>
<c>so the guileless child narrator of Jane Freed takes the operagoer</c>
<d>listening to Jane Freed's guileless child narrator takes the operagoer</d>
<e>Jane Freed's guileless child narrator takes the operagoer to her opera</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-99</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Bihar is India's poorest state, with an annual per capita income of $111, lower than in the most impoverished countries of the world.</content>
<a>lower than in</a>
<b>lower than that of</b>
<c>and lower than that of</c>
<d>which is lower than in</d>

<e>which is lower than it is in</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-100</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	El Nino, the periodic abnormal warming of the sea surface off Peru, a phenomenon in which changes in the ocean and atmosphere combine allowing the warm water that has accumulated in the western Pacific to flow back to the east.</content>
<a>a phenomenon in which changes in the ocean and atmosphere combine allowing the warm water that has accumulated</a>
<b>a phenomenon where changes in the ocean and atmosphere are combining to allow the warm water that is accumulating</b>

<c>a phenomenon in which ocean and atmosphere changes combine and which allows the warm water that is accumulated</c>
<d>is a phenomenon in which changes in the ocean and atmosphere combine to allow the warm water that has accumulated</d>
<e>is a phenomenon where ocean and atmosphere changes are combining and allow the warm water accumulating</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-101</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Beatrix Potter, in her book illustrations, carefully coordinating them with her narratives, capitalized on her keen observation and love of the natural world.</content>

<a>Beatrix Potter, in her book illustrations, carefully coordinating them with her narratives,</a>
<b>In her book illustrations, carefully coordinating them with her narratives, Beatrix Potter</b>
<c>In her book illustrations, which she carefully coordinated with her narratives, Beatrix Potter</c>
<d>Carefully coordinated with her narratives, Beatrix Potter, in her book illustrations</d>
<e>Beatrix Potter, in her book illustrations, carefully coordinated them with her narratives and</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-102</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The development of a new jumbo rocket that is expected to carry the United States into its next phase of space exploration will be able to deliver a heavier load of instruments into orbit than the space shuttle and at a lower cost.</content>
<a>The development of a new jumbo rocket that is expected to carry the United States into its next phase of space exploration will be able to deliver a heavier load of instruments into orbit than the space shuttle and at a lower cost.</a>
<b>The development of a new jumbo rocket is expected to carry the United States into its next phase of space exploration and be able to deliver a heavier load of instruments into orbit at a lower cost than the space shuttle.</b>
<c>The new development of a jumbo rocket, which is expected to carry the United States into its next phase of space exploration, will be able to deliver a heavier load of instruments into orbit at a lower cost than the space shuttle.</c>
<d>A newly developed jumbo rocket, which is expected to carry the United States into its next phase of space exploration, will be able to deliver a heavier load of instruments into orbit than the space shuttle can, and at a lower cost.</d>
<e>A newly developed jumbo rocket, which is expected to carry the United States into its next phase of space exploration, will be able to deliver a heavier load of instruments into orbit than the space shuttle and to cost less.</e>
<answer>D</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-103</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Nuclear fusion is the force that powers the Sun, the stars, and hydrogen bombs, merging the nuclei of atoms and not splitting them apart, as in nuclear reactors.</content>
<a>merging the nuclei of atoms and not splitting them apart, as in nuclear reactors</a>
<b>merging the nuclei of atoms instead of splitting them apart, like nuclear reactors</b>
<c>merging the nuclei of atoms rather than splitting them apart, as nuclear reactors do</c>
<d>and merges the nuclei of atoms but does not split them apart, as is done in nuclear reactors</d>

<e>and merges the nuclei of atoms, unlike atomic reactors that split them apart</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-104</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Originally developed for detecting air pollutants, a technique called proton-induced X-ray emission, which can quickly analyze the chemical elements in almost any substance without destroying it, is finding uses in medicine, archaeology, and criminology.</content>
<a>Originally developed for detecting air pollutants, a technique called proton  induced X-ray emission, which can quickly analyze the chemical elements in almost any substance without destroying it,</a>
<b>Originally developed for detecting air pollutants, having the ability to analyze the chemical elements in almost any substance without destroying it, a technique called proton-induced X-ray emission</b>

<c>A technique originally developed for detecting air pollutants, called proton-induced X-ray emission, which can quickly analyze the chemical elements in almost any substance without destroying it,</c>
<d>A technique originally developed for detecting air pollutants, called proton-induced X-ray emission, which has the ability to analyze the chemical elements in almost any substance quickly and without destroying it,</d>
<e>A technique that was originally developed for detecting air pollutants and has the ability to analyze the chemical elements in almost any substance quickly and without destroying the substance, called proton  induced X-ray emission,</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-105</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Among the objects found in the excavated temple were small terra-cotta effigies left by supplicants who were either asking the goddess Bona Dea's aid in healing physical and mental ills or thanking her for such help.</content>

<a>in healing physical and mental ills or thanking her for such help</a>
<b>in healing physical and mental ills and to thank her for helping</b>
<c>in healing physical and mental ills, and thanking her for helping</c>
<d>to heal physical and mental ills or to thank her for such help</d>
<e>to heal physical and mental ills or thanking her for such help</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-106</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In his research paper, Dr. Frosh, medical director of the Payne Whitney Clinic, distinguishes mood swings, which may be violent without their being grounded in mental disease, from genuine manic depressive psychosis.</content>
<a>mood swings, which may be violent without their being grounded in mental disease, from genuine manic-depressive psychosis</a>
<b>mood swings, perhaps violent without being grounded in mental disease, and genuine manic-depressive psychosis</b>
<c>between mood swings, which may be violent without being grounded in mental disease, and genuine manic-depressive psychosis</c>
<d>between mood swings, perhaps violent without being grounded in mental disease, from genuine manic-depressive psychosis</d>
<e>genuine manic-depressive psychosis and mood swings, which may be violent without being grounded in mental disease</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-107</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The first decision for most tenants living in a building undergoing being converted to cooperative ownership is if to sign a no-buy pledge with the other tenants.</content>
<a>being converted to cooperative ownership is if to sign</a>
<b>being converted to cooperative ownership is whether they should be signing</b>
<c>being converted to cooperative ownership is whether or not they sign</c>
<d>conversion to cooperative ownership is if to sign</d>

<e>conversion to cooperative ownership is whether to sign</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-108</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Published in Harlem, the owner and editor of the Messenger were two young journalists, Chandler Owen and A. Philip Randolph, who would later make his reputation as a labor leader.</content>
<a>Published in Harlem, the owner and editor of the Messenger were two young journalists, Chandler Owen and A. Philip Randolph, who would later make his reputation as a labor leader.</a>
<b>Published in Harlem, two young journalists, Chandler Owen and A. Philip Randolph, who would later make his reputation as a labor leader, were the owner and editor of the Messenger.</b>

<c>Published in Harlem, the Messenger was owned and edited by two young journalists, A. Philip Randolph, who would later make his reputation as a labor leader, and Chandler Owen.</c>
<d>The Messenger was owned and edited by two young journalists, Chandler Owen and A. Philip Randolph, who would later make his reputation as a labor leader, and published in Harlem.</d>
<e>The owner and editor being two young journalists, Chandler Owen and A. Philip Randolph, who would later make his reputation as a labor leader, the Messenger was published in Harlem.</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-109</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In June of 1987, The Bridge of Trinquetaille, Vincent van Gogh's view of an iron bridge over the Rhone sold for $20.2 million and it was the second highest price ever paid for a painting at auction.</content>

<a>Rhone sold for $20.2 million and it was</a>
<b>Rhone, which sold for $20.2 million, was</b>
<c>Rhone, was sold for $20.2 million,</c>
<d>Rhone was sold for $20.2 million, being</d>
<e>Rhone, sold for $20.2 million, and was</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-110</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	As a baby emerges from the darkness of the womb with a rudimentary sense of vision, it would be rated about 20/500, or legally blind if it were an adult with such vision.</content>
<a>As a baby emerges from the darkness of the womb with a rudimentary sense of vision, it would be rated about 20/500, or legally blind if it were an adult with such vision.</a>
<b>A baby emerges from the darkness of the womb with a rudimentary sense of vision that would be rated about 20/500, or legally blind as an adult.</b>
<c>As a baby emerges from the darkness of the womb, its rudimentary sense of vision would be rated about 20/500; qualifying it to be legally blind if an adult.</c>
<d>A baby emerges from the darkness of the womb with a rudimentary sense of vision that would be rated about 20/500; an adult with such vision would be deemed legally blind.</d>
<e>As a baby emerges from the darkness of the womb, its rudimentary sense of vision, which would deemed legally blind for an adult, would be rated about 20/500.</e>
<answer>D</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-111</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The Federal Reserve Board's reduction of interest rates on loans to financial institutions is both an acknowledgment of past economic trends and an effort to influence their future direction.</content>
<a>reduction of interest rates on loans to financial institutions is both an acknowledgment of past economic trends and an effort</a>
<b>reduction of interest rates on loans to financial institutions is an acknowledgment both of past economic trends as well as an effort</b>
<c>reduction of interest rates on loans to financial institutions both acknowledge past economic trends and attempt</c>
<d>reducing interest rates on loans to financial institutions is an acknowledgment both of past economic trends and an effort</d>

<e>reducing interest rates on loans to financial institutions both acknowledge past economic trends as well as attempt</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-112</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The original building and loan associations were organized as limited life funds, whose members made monthly payments on their share subscriptions, then taking turns drawing on the funds for home mortgages.</content>
<a>subscriptions, then taking turns drawing</a>
<b>subscriptions, and then taking turns drawing</b>

<c>subscriptions and then took turns drawing</c>
<d>subscriptions and then took turns, they drew</d>
<e>subscriptions and then drew, taking turns</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-113</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Gall's hypothesis of there being different mental functions localized in different parts of the brain is widely accepted today.</content>

<a>of there being different mental functions localized in different parts of the brain is widely accepted today</a>
<b>of different mental functions that are localized in different parts of the brain is widely accepted today</b>
<c>that different mental functions are localized in different parts of the brain is widely accepted today</c>
<d>which is that there are different mental functions localized in different parts of the brain is widely accepted today</d>
<e>which is widely accepted today is that there are different mental functions localized in different parts of the brain</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-114</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	George Sand (Aurore Lucile Dupin) was one of the first European writers to consider the rural poor to be legitimate subjects for literature and portray these with sympathy and respect in her novels.</content>
<a>to be legitimate subjects for literature and portray these</a>
<b>should be legitimate subjects for literature and portray these</b>
<c>as being legitimate subjects for literature and portraying them</c>
<d>as if they were legitimate subjects for literature and portray them</d>
<e>legitimate subjects for literature and to portray them</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-115</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Out of America's fascination with all things antique have grown a market for bygone styles of furniture and fixtures that are bringing back the chaise lounge, the overstuffed sofa, and the claw-footed bathtub.</content>
<a>things antique have grown a market for bygone styles of furniture and fixtures that are bringing</a>
<b>things antique has grown a market for bygone styles of furniture and fixtures that is bringing</b>
<c>things that are antiques has grown a market for bygone styles of furniture and fixtures that bring</c>
<d>antique things have grown a market for bygone styles of furniture and fixtures that are bringing</d>

<e>antique things has grown a market for bygone styles of furniture and fixtures that bring</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-116</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	New theories propose that catastrophic impacts of asteroids and comets may have caused reversals in the Earth's magnetic field, the onset of ice ages, splitting apart continents 80 million years ago, and great volcanic eruptions.</content>
<a>splitting apart continents</a>
<b>the splitting apart of continents</b>

<c>split apart continents</c>
<d>continents split apart</d>
<e>continents that were split apart</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-117</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Students in the metropolitan school district lack math skills to such a large degree as to make it difficult to absorb them into a city economy becoming ever more dependent on information-based industries.</content>

<a>lack math skills to such a large degree as to make it difficult to absorb them into a city economy becoming</a>
<b>lack math skills to a large enough degree that they will be difficult to absorb into a city's economy that becomes</b>
<c>lack of math skills is so large as to be difficult to absorb them into a city's economy that becomes</c>
<d>are lacking so much in math skills as to be difficult to absorb into a city's economy becoming</d>
<e>are so lacking in math skills that it will be difficult to absorb them into a city economy becoming</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-118</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The decision by one of the nation's largest banks to admit to $3 billion in potential losses on foreign loans could mean less lending by commercial banks to developing countries and increasing the pressure on multigovernment lenders to supply the funds.</content>
<a>increasing the pressure</a>
<b>the increasing pressure</b>
<c>increased pressure</c>
<d>the pressure increased</d>
<e>the pressure increasing</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-119</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	It has been estimated that the annual cost to the United States of illiteracy in lost industrial output and tax revenues is at least $20 billion a year.</content>
<a>the annual cost to the United States of illiteracy in lost industrial output and tax revenues is at least $20 billion a year</a>
<b>the annual cost of illiteracy to the United States is at least $20 billion a year because of lost industrial output and tax revenues</b>
<c>illiteracy costs the United States at least $20 billion a year in lost industrial output and tax revenues</c>
<d>$20 billion a year in lost industrial output and tax revenues is the annual cost to the United States of illiteracy</d>

<e>lost industrial output and tax revenues cost the United States at least $20 billion a year because of illiteracy</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-120</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	A firm that specializes in the analysis of handwriting claims from a one-page writing sample that it can assess more than 300 personality traits, including enthusiasm, imagination, and ambition.</content>
<a>from a one-page writing sample that it can assess</a>
<b>from a one-page writing sample it has the ability of assessing</b>

<c>the ability, from a one-page writing sample, of assessing</c>
<d>to be able, from a one-page writing sample, to assess</d>
<e>being able to assess, from a one-page writing sample</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-121</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	More than 30 years ago Dr. Barbara McClintock, the Nobel Prize winner, reported that genes can "jump," as pearls moving mysteriously from one necklace to another.</content>

<a>as pearls moving mysteriously from one necklace to another</a>
<b>like pearls moving mysteriously from one necklace to another</b>
<c>as pearls do that move mysteriously from one necklace to others</c>
<d>like pearls do that move mysteriously from one necklace to others</d>
<e>as do pearls that move mysteriously from one necklace to some other one</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-122</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	In Holland, a larger percentage of the gross national product is spent on defense of their coasts from rising seas than is spent on military defense in the United States.</content>
<a>In Holland, a larger percentage of the gross national product is spent on defense of their coasts from rising seas than is spent on military defense in the United States.</a>
<b>In Holland they spend a larger percentage of their gross national product on defending their coasts from rising seas than the United States does on military defense.</b>
<c>A larger percentage of Holland's gross national product is spent on defending their coasts from rising seas than the United States spends on military defense.</c>
<d>Holland spends a larger percentage of its gross national product defending its coasts from rising seas than the military defense spending of the United States.</d>
<e>Holland spends a larger percentage of its gross national product on defending its coasts from rising seas than the United States does on military defense.</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-123</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Canadian scientists have calculated that one human being should be struck every nine years by a meteorite, while each year 16 buildings can be expected to sustain damage from such objects.</content>
<a>one human being should be struck every nine years by a meteorite</a>
<b>a human being should be struck by a meteorite once in every nine years</b>
<c>a meteorite will strike one human being once in every nine years</c>

<d>every nine years a human being will be struck by a meteorite</d>
<e>every nine years a human being should be struck by a meteorite</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-124</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Samuel Sewall viewed marriage, as other seventeenth-century colonists, like a property arrangement rather than an emotional bond based on romantic love.</content>
<a>Samuel Sewall viewed marriage, as other seventeenth-century colonists, like a property arrangement rather than</a>

<b>As did other seventeenth-century colonists, Samuel Sewall viewed marriage to be a property arrangement rather than viewing it as</b>
<c>Samuel Sewall viewed marriage to be a property arrangement, like other seventeenth-century colonists, rather than viewing it as</c>
<d>Marriage to Samuel Sewall, like other seventeenth-century colonists, was viewed as a property arrangement rather than</d>
<e>Samuel Sewall, like other seventeenth  century colonists, viewed marriage as a property arrangement rather than</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-125</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>	A wildlife expert predicts that the reintroduction of the caribou into northern Minnesota would fail if the density of the timber wolf population in that region is more numerous than one wolf for every 39 square miles.</content>
<a>would fail if the density of the timber wolf population in that region is more numerous than</a>
<b>would fail provided the density of the timber wolf population in that region is more than</b>
<c>should fail if the timber wolf density in that region was greater than</c>
<d>will fail if the density of the timber wolf population in that region is greater than</d>
<e>will fail if the timber wolf density in that region were more numerous than</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC1-126</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Found throughout Central and South America, sloths hang from trees by long rubbery limbs and sleep 15 hours a day, moving infrequently enough that two species of algae grow on its coat and between its toes.</content>
<a>sloths hang from trees by long rubbery limbs and sleep 15 hours a day, moving infrequently enough</a>
<b>sloths hang from trees by long rubbery limbs, they sleep 15 hours a day, and with such infrequent movements</b>
<c>sloths use their long rubbery limbs to hang from trees, sleep 15 hours a day, and move so infrequently</c>
<d>the sloth hangs from trees by its long rubbery limbs, sleeping 15 hours a day and moving so infrequently</d>
<e>the sloth hangs from trees by its long rubbery limbs, sleeps 15 hours a day, and it moves infrequently enough</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-127</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Today, because of improvements in agricultural technology, the same amount of acreage produces double the apples that it has in 1910.</content>
<a>double the apples that it has</a>
<b>twice as many apples as it did</b>
<c>as much as twice the apples it has</c>

<d>two times as many apples as there were</d>
<e>a doubling of the apples that it did</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-128</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Joan of Arc, a young Frenchwoman who claimed to be divinely inspired, turned the tide of English victories in her country by liberating the city of Orleans and she persuaded Charles VII of France to claim his throne.</content>
<a>she persuaded Charles VII of France to claim his throne</a>

<b>persuaded Charles VII of France in claiming his throne</b>
<c>persuading that the throne be claimed by Charles VII of France</c>
<d>persuaded Charles VII of France to claim his throne</d>
<e>persuading that Charles VII of France should claim the throne</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-129</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>	As a result of medical advances, many people that might at one time have died as children of such infections as diphtheria, pneumonia, or rheumatic fever now live well into old age.</content>
<a>that might at one time have died as children</a>
<b>who might once have died in childhood</b>
<c>that as children might once have died</c>
<d>who in childhood might have at one time died</d>
<e>who, when they were children, might at one time have died</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC1-130</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Cajuns speak a dialect brought to southern Louisiana by the 4,000 Acadians who migrated there in 1755; their language is basically seventeenth-century French to which has been added English, Spanish, and Italian words.</content>
<a>to which has been added English, Spanish, and Italian words</a>
<b>added to which is English, Spanish, and Italian words</b>
<c>to which English, Spanish, and Italian words have been added</c>
<d>with English, Spanish, and Italian words having been added to it</d>
<e>and, in addition, English, Spanish, and Italian words are added</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-131</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	One view of the economy contends that a large drop in oil prices should eventually lead to lowering interest rates, as well as lowering fears about inflation, a rally in stocks and bonds, and a weakening of the dollar.</content>
<a>lowering interest rates, as well as lowering fears about inflation,</a>
<b>a lowering of interest rates and of fears about inflation,</b>
<c>a lowering of interest rates, along with fears about inflation,</c>

<d>interest rates being lowered, along with fears about inflation,</d>
<e>interest rates and fears about inflation being lowered, with</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-132</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Although the term "psychopath" is popularly applied to an especially brutal criminal, in psychology it is someone who is apparently incapable of feeling compassion or the pangs of conscience.</content>
<a>it is someone who is</a>

<b>it is a person</b>
<c>they are people who are</c>
<d>it refers to someone who is</d>
<e>it is in reference to people</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-133</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>	Recently implemented "shift-work equations" based on studies of the human sleep cycle have reduced sickness, sleeping on the job, fatigue among shift workers, and have raised production efficiency in various industries.</content>
<a>fatigue among shift workers, and have raised</a>
<b>fatigue among shift workers, and raised</b>
<c>and fatigue among shift workers while raising</c>
<d>lowered fatigue among shift workers, and raised</d>
<e>and fatigue among shift workers was lowered while raising</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC1-134</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Spanning more than 50 years, Friedrich Muller began his career in an unpromising apprenticeship as a Sanskrit scholar and culminated in virtually every honor that European governments and learned societies could bestow.</content>
<a>Muller began his career in an unpromising apprenticeship as</a>
<b>Muller's career began in an unpromising apprenticeship as</b>
<c>Muller's career began with the unpromising apprenticeship of being</c>
<d>Muller had begun his career with the unpromising apprenticeship of being</d>
<e>the career of Muller has begun with an unpromising apprenticeship of</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-135</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	Joachim Raff and Giacomo Meyerbeer are examples of the kind of composer who receives popular acclaim while living, often goes into decline after death, and never regains popularity again.</content>
<a>often goes into decline after death, and never regains popularity again</a>
<b>whose reputation declines after death and never regains its status again</b>
<c>but whose reputation declines after death and never regains its former status</c>

<d>who declines in reputation after death and who never regained popularity again</d>
<e>then has declined in reputation after death and never regained popularity</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-136</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>	The company announced that its profits declined much less in the second quarter than analysts had expected it to and its business will improve in the second half of the year.</content>
<a>had expected it to and its business will improve</a>

<b>had expected and that its business would improve</b>
<c>expected it would and that it will improve its business</c>
<d>expected them to and its business would improve</d>
<e>expected and that it will have improved its business</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>
<mark>OG11SC1-137</mark>
</item>

<item>

<content>	The direction in which the Earth and the other solid planetsMercury, Venus, and Marsspins were determined from collisions with giant celestial bodies in the early history of the solar system.</content>
<a>spins were determined from</a>
<b>spins were determined because of</b>
<c>spins was determined through</c>
<d>spin was determined by</d>
<e>spin was determined as a result of</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>OG11th</source>

<mark>OG11SC1-138</mark>
</item>

</sc>