<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<sc>

<item>
<content>To meet the rapidly rising market demand for fish and seafood, suppliers are growing fish twice as fast as their natural growth rate, cutting their feed allotment by nearly half and raising them on special diets.</content>
<a>their natural growth rate, cutting their feed allotment</a>
<b>their natural growth rate, their feed allotment cut</b>
<c>growing them naturally, cutting their feed allotment</c>
<d>they grow naturally, cutting their feed allotment</d>
<e>they grow naturally, with their feed allotment cut</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24465-!-item-!-188;#058&000982</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Organized in 1966 by the Fish and Wildlife Service, the Breeding Bird Survey uses annual roadside counts along established routes for monitoring of population changes of as many as, or of more than 250 bird species, including 180 songbirds.</content>
<a>for monitoring of population changes of as many as, or of</a>
<b>to monitor population changes of as many, or</b>
<c>to monitor changes in the populations of</c>

<d>that monitors population changes of</d>
<e>that monitors changes in populations of as many as, or</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24511-!-item-!-188;#058&001020</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Less than 35 years after the release of African honeybees outside Sao Paulo, Brazil, their descendants, popularly known as killer bees, had migrated as far north as southern Texas.</content>
<a>Less than 35 years after the release of African honeybees outside Sao Paulo, Brazil,</a>

<b>In less than 35 years since releasing African honeybees outside Sao Paulo, Brazil,</b>
<c>In less than the 35 years since African honeybees had been released outside Sao Paulo, Brazil,</c>
<d>It took less than 35 years from the release of African honeybees outside Sao Paulo, Brazil, when</d>
<e>It took less than the 35 years after the time that African honeybees were released outside Sao Paulo, Brazil, and then</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24557-!-item-!-188;#058&001027</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Nikola Tesla, the inventor of alternating current, because he was excited with the prospects of harnessing Niagara Falls for producing electric power, he predicted in the mid-1890's that electricity generated at Niagara would one day power the streetcars of London and the streetlights of Paris.</content>
<a>Nikola Tesla, the inventor of alternating current, because he was excited with the prospects of harnessing Niagara Falls for producing electric power, he</a>
<b>The prospects of harnessing Niagara Falls to produce electric power was exciting to Nikola Tesla, the inventor of alternating current, and so he</b>
<c>Excited about the prospects of harnessing Niagara Falls to produce electric power, Nikola Tesla, the inventor of alternating current,</c>
<d>Nikola Tesla, the inventor of alternating current, excited about the prospects of harnessing Niagara Falls for the production of electric power and</d>
<e>The inventor of alternating current, excited with the prospects of harnessing Niagara Falls for producing of electric power, Nikola Tesla</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>24603-!-item-!-188;#058&001035</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The airline company, following through on recent warnings that it might start reducing service, announced that it was eliminating jet service to nine cities, closing some unneeded operations, and it grounded twenty-two planes.</content>
<a>closing some unneeded operations, and it grounded</a>
<b>closing some unneeded operations, and grounding</b>
<c>was closing some unneeded operations, while it grounded</c>
<d>it closed some unneeded operations and grounded</d>
<e>it was closing some unneeded operations, and grounding</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24795-!-item-!-188;#058&001473</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The list of animals that exhibits a preference of either using the right or the left hand (i.e., claw, paw, or foot) has been expanded to include the lower vertebrates.</content>
<a>exhibits a preference of either using the right or the left hand (i.e., claw, paw, or foot) has been expanded to include</a>
<b>exhibits the preference to use either the right or the left hand (i.e., claw, paw, or foot) has been expanded and includes</b>
<c>exhibit a preference in either using the right or the left hand (i.e., claw, paw, or foot) has been expanded to include</c>

<d>exhibit a preference for using either the right or the left hand (i.e., claw, paw, or foot) has been expanded to include</d>
<e>exhibit the preference as to either using the right or the left hand (i.e., claw, paw, or foot) has been expanded and includes</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24841-!-item-!-188;#058&001528</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Obtaining an investment-grade rating will keep the county's future borrowing costs low, protect its already-tattered image, and increase its ability to buy bond insurance.</content>
<a>Obtaining an investment-grade rating will keep the county's future borrowing costs low, protect</a>

<b>To obtain an investment-grade rating will keep the county's future borrowing costs low, and protect</b>
<c>Having obtained an investment-grade rating will, in keeping the county's future borrowing costs low, protect</c>
<d>To obtain an investment-grade rating would keep the county's future borrowing costs low, protecting</d>
<e>Obtaining an investment-grade rating, keeping the county's borrowing costs low, would be protecting</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24887-!-item-!-188;#058&001530</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Achaemenid empire of Persia reached the Indus Valley in the fifth century B.C., bringing the Aramaic script with it, from which was derived both northern and southern Indian alphabets.</content>
<a>the Aramaic script with it, from which was derived both northern and</a>
<b>the Aramaic script with it, and from which deriving both the northern and the</b>
<c>with it the Aramaic script, from which derive both the northern and the</c>
<d>with it the Aramaic script, from which derives both northern and</d>
<e>with it the Aramaic script, and deriving from it both the northern and</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>24933-!-item-!-188;#058&001582</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Based on records from ancient Athens, each year young Athenian women collaborated to weave a new woolen robe that they used to dress a statue of the goddess Athena and that this robe depicted scenes of a battle between Zeus, Athena's father, and giants.</content>
<a>Based on records from ancient Athens, each year young Athenian women collaborated to weave a new woolen robe that they used to dress</a>
<b>Based on records from ancient Athens, each year young Athenian women had collaborated to weave a new woolen robe with which to dress</b>
<c>According to records from ancient Athens, each year young Athenian women collaborated to weave a new woolen robe that they used to dress</c>
<d>Records from ancient Athens indicate that each year young Athenian women collaborated to weave a new woolen robe with which they dressed</d>
<e>Records from ancient Athens indicate each year young Athenian women had collaborated to weave a new woolen robe for dressing</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24979-!-item-!-188;#058&001658</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Ancient hunter-gatherers developed instincts that stigmatized selfishness, and voluntary cooperation was encouraged as well, whether it be within the group or also with outsiders.</content>
<a>selfishness, and voluntary cooperation was encouraged as well, whether it be within the group or</a>
<b>selfishness, encouraging voluntary cooperation as well, both within the group but</b>
<c>selfishness and also encouraging voluntary cooperation, within the group and</c>

<d>selfishness and they encouraged voluntary cooperation, whether it be within the group or</d>
<e>selfishness and encouraged voluntary cooperation, not only within the group but</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25025-!-item-!-188;#058&001699</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Japanese researchers are producing a series of robots that can identify human facial expressions, to which they will then respond; their goal is primarily creating a robot that will empathize with us.</content>
<a>expressions, to which they will then respond; their goal is primarily creating</a>

<b>expressions, then responding to them; primarily to create</b>
<c>expressions and then respond to them; the researchers' primary goal is to create</c>
<d>expressions as well as giving a response to them; their primary goal is creation of</d>
<e>expressions and responding to them; primarily, the researchers' goal is creating</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25071-!-item-!-188;#058&001704</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In contrast to ongoing trade imbalances with China and Japan, the United States trade deficit with Mexico declined by $500 million as a result of record exports to that country.</content>
<a>In contrast to ongoing trade imbalances with China and Japan, the United States trade deficit with Mexico declined by $500 million as a result of record exports to that country.</a>
<b>In contrast to ongoing trade imbalances with China and Japan, the United States sold record exports to Mexico, reducing its trade deficit by $500 million.</b>
<c>When compared with ongoing trade imbalances with China and Japan, the United States sold record exports to Mexico, reducing their trade deficit by $500 million.</c>
<d>Compared with ongoing trade imbalances with China and Japan, the United States sold record exports to Mexico, reducing the trade deficit by $500 million.</d>
<e>Compared to ongoing trade imbalances with China and Japan, the United States record exports to Mexico caused a $500 million decline in the trade deficit with that country.</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25117-!-item-!-188;#058&001707</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike most severance packages, which require workers to stay until the last day scheduled to collect, workers at the automobile company are eligible for its severance package even if they find a new job before they are terminated.</content>
<a>the last day scheduled to collect, workers at the automobile company are eligible for its severance package</a>
<b>the last day they are scheduled to collect, workers are eligible for the automobile company's severance package</b>
<c>their last scheduled day to collect, the automobile company offers its severance package to workers</c>
<d>their last scheduled day in order to collect, the automobile company's severance package is available to workers</d>
<e>the last day that they are scheduled to collect, the automobile company's severance package is available to workers</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25163-!-item-!-188;#058&001734</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Having finally reached a tentative labor agreement with its company's pilots, it must now be determined by the airline's board of directors how the airline can both increase profits and compete more effectively for customers than they did in the past.</content>
<a>it must now be determined by the airline's board of directors how the airline can both increase profits and compete more effectively for customers than they did in the past</a>
<b>it must now be determined by the airline's board of directors how the airline can both increase profits and must compete more effectively than in the past for customers</b>
<c>the airline's board of directors must now determine both how to make the airline increase profits and compete more effectively for customers than they did in the past</c>

<d>the airline's board of directors must now determine how the airline can both increase profits and compete more effectively for customers than it did in the past</d>
<e>the airline's board of directors must now determine how the airline can both increase profits and also how to make it compete more effectively than in the past for customers</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25209-!-item-!-188;#058&001758</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Even though sub-Saharan Africa often evokes images of drought and famine, researchers say that the area is the home of more than 2,000 grains, vegetables, roots, fruits, and other foods that have the possibility for feeding the continent, even other parts of the world.</content>
<a>have the possibility for feeding the continent, even</a>

<b>have the possibility of feeding the continent, even of</b>
<c>could feed the continent, so even with</c>
<d>could feed the continent and even</d>
<e>could possibly feed the continent and, in addition, for even</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25405-!-item-!-188;#058&001909</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In her later poems, Phyllis Wheatley's blending of solar imagery, Judeo-Christian thought and figures, and the images she borrowed from ancient classicism suggesting her range and depth of influences, not the least of which is her African heritage.</content>
<a>the images she borrowed from ancient classicism suggesting</a>
<b>borrowing images from ancient classicism, suggests</b>
<c>she borrowed images from ancient classicism, which suggests</c>
<d>images borrowed from ancient classicism suggests</d>
<e>images that she borrowed from ancient classicism, suggesting</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25451-!-item-!-188;#058&001942</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Rejecting the apprenticeship model of training social workers in philanthropic agencies, twentieth-century reformer Edith Abbott was convinced of social work education belonging in the university so that students could be offered a broad range of courses dealing with social issues.</content>
<a>of social work education belonging in the university so that</a>
<b>that social work education should be in the university, and that</b>
<c>about the importance of social work education belonging in the university while</c>
<d>that social work education belonged in the university, where</d>
<e>of the necessity of social work education being in the university and</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25497-!-item-!-188;#058&001948</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Bluegrass musician Bill Monroe, whose repertory, views on musical collaboration, and vocal style were influential on generations of bluegrass artists, was also an inspiration to many musicians, that included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia, whose music differed significantly from his own.</content>
<a>were influential on generations of bluegrass artists, was also an inspiration to many musicians, that included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia, whose music differed significantly from</a>
<b>influenced generations of bluegrass artists, also inspired many musicians, including Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia, whose music differed significantly from</b>
<c>was influential to generations of bluegrass artists, was also inspirational to many musicians, that included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia, whose music was different significantly in comparison to</c>

<d>was influential to generations of bluegrass artists, also inspired many musicians, who included Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia, the music of whom differed significantly when compared to</d>
<e>were an influence on generations of bluegrass artists, was also an inspiration to many musicians, including Elvis Presley and Jerry Garcia, whose music was significantly different from that of</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25543-!-item-!-188;#058&001954</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Although unhappy with the high rent her company was paying for its suburban office building, the chief executive recognized rental rates for buildings in the suburbs as far lower than it typically is for property that is located within the city limits.</content>
<a>rental rates for buildings in the suburbs as far lower than it typically is for property that is located within the city limits</a>

<b>rental rates for buildings in the suburbs as being far lower than what the rates typically charged within the city limits had been for property located there</b>
<c>rental rates typically being charged for property located within the city limits to be far lower as they typically were within the city limits for the property there</c>
<d>that rental rates for buildings in the suburbs were far lower than rental rates typically being charged within the city limits for property located there</d>
<e>that rental rates for buildings in the suburbs were far lower than those typically charged for property located within the city limits</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25589-!-item-!-188;#058&002028</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The hognose snake puts on an impressive bluff, hissing and rearing back, broadens the flesh behind its head the way a cobra does, feigning repeated strikes, but, having no dangerous fangs and no venom, eventually, if its pursuer is not cowed by the performance, will fall over and play dead.</content>
<a>broadens the flesh behind its head the way a cobra does, feigning repeated strikes, but, having no dangerous fangs and no venom,</a>
<b>broadens the flesh behind its head the way a cobra does and feigns repeated strikes, but with no dangerous fangs and no venom,</b>
<c>broadening the flesh behind its head the way a cobra does and feigning repeated strikes, but it has no dangerous fangs and no venom, and</c>
<d>broadening the flesh behind its head the way a cobra does and feigns repeated strikes, but with no dangerous fangs and no venom, and</d>
<e>broadening the flesh behind its head the way a cobra does, feigning repeated strikes, but with no dangerous fangs and no venom, and</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25635-!-item-!-188;#058&002069</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>When Nigeria achieved full independence in 1960, they had already established a federal political structure consisting of three regions based on the three major population clusters that were in its borders.</content>
<a>they had already established a federal political structure consisting of three regions based on the three major population clusters that were in</a>
<b>they already had established a federal political structure consisting of three regions that was based on the three major population clusters inside</b>
<c>they already had established a federal political structure that consisted of three regions based on the three major population clusters in</c>
<d>it had already established a federal political structure that consisted of three regions based on the three major population clusters within</d>
<e>it already had established a federal political structure consisting of three regions being based on the three major population clusters it had within</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25681-!-item-!-188;#058&002107</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The company announced that its profits declined much less in the second quarter than analysts had expected it to and its business will improve in the second half of the year.</content>
<a>had expected it to and its business will improve</a>
<b>had expected and that its business would improve</b>
<c>expected it would and that it will improve its business</c>

<d>expected them to and its business would improve</d>
<e>expected and that it will have improved its business</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25727-!-item-!-188;#058&002127</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>While they remove carbon dioxide from the air, conserve soil and water, and house thousands of species, forests also supply potentially valuable pharmaceuticals, and, as sources of building material and firewood, that provide employment for millions worldwide.</content>
<a>pharmaceuticals, and, as sources of building material and firewood, that provide</a>

<b>pharmaceuticals, and sources of building material and firewood, are providers of</b>
<c>pharmaceuticals and, as sources of building material and firewood that are providing</c>
<d>pharmaceuticals and sources of building material and firewood, for providing</d>
<e>pharmaceuticals and, as sources of building material and firewood, provide</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25773-!-item-!-188;#058&002128</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Employment costs rose 2.8 percent in the 12 months that ended in September, slightly less than they did in the year that ended in the previous quarter.</content>
<a>less than they did</a>
<b>less than it did</b>
<c>less than they were</c>
<d>lower than</d>
<e>lower than they were</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25819-!-item-!-188;#058&002130</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Often incorrectly referred to as a tidal wave, a tsunami, a seismic sea wave that can reach up to 150 miles per hour in speed and 200 feet high, is caused by underwater earthquakes or volcanic eruptions.</content>
<a>up to 150 miles per hour in speed and 200 feet high, is</a>
<b>up to 150 miles per hour in speed and heights of up to 200 feet, is</b>
<c>speeds of up to 150 miles per hour and 200 feet high, are</c>
<d>speeds of up to 150 miles per hour and heights of up to 200 feet, is</d>
<e>speeds of up to 150 miles per hour and as high as 200 feet, are</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25865-!-item-!-188;#058&002136</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The investigations of many psychologists and anthropologists support the generalization of there being little that is a significant difference in the underlying mental processes manifested by people from different cultures.</content>
<a>of there being little that is a significant difference</a>
<b>of there being little that is significantly different</b>
<c>of little that is significantly different</c>

<d>that there is little that is significantly different</d>
<e>that there is little of significant differences</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25911-!-item-!-188;#058&002160</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>When drafting the Declaration of Sentiments that was adopted at the Seneca Falls Women's Rights Convention in 1848, included in it by the author, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, was a call for female enfranchisement.</content>
<a>When drafting the Declaration of Sentiments that was adopted at the Seneca Falls Women's Rights Convention in 1848, included in it by the author, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, was a call for female enfranchisement.</a>

<b>Including a call for female enfranchisement, a draft of the Declaration of Sentiments was adopted at the Seneca Falls Women's Rights Convention in 1848 that Elizabeth Cady Stanton wrote.</b>
<c>When the Declaration of Sentiments drafted by Elizabeth Cady Stanton was adopted at the Seneca Falls Women's Convention in 1848, a call for female enfranchisement had been included in it.</c>
<d>A call for female enfranchisement, included in Elizabeth Cady Stanton's draft of the Declaration of Sentiments in 1848, that was adopted by the Seneca Falls Women's Rights Convention.</d>
<e>When Elizabeth Cady Stanton drafted the Declaration of Sentiments that was adopted at the Seneca Falls Women's Rights Convention in 1848, she included in it a call for female enfranchisement.</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25957-!-item-!-188;#058&002223</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Polio, although it is eradicated in the United States, it continues elsewhere and is able to be brought into the country by visitors.</content>
<a>Polio, although it is eradicated in the United States, it continues elsewhere and is able to be</a>
<b>Polio, although eradicated in the United States, it still continues elsewhere and can be</b>
<c>Although still continuing elsewhere, polio has been eradicated in the United States and could be</c>
<d>Although having been eradicated in the United States, polio still continues elsewhere and is capable of being</d>
<e>Although eradicated in the United States, polio continues elsewhere and could be</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26003-!-item-!-188;#058&002229</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Oaks preferring drier ones, pine trees thrive in relatively wet climates.</content>
<a>Oaks preferring drier ones, pine trees thrive in relatively wet climates.</a>
<b>With oaks preferring drier ones, pine trees thrive in relatively wet climates.</b>
<c>Whereas oaks prefer drier ones, with pine trees thriving in relatively wet climates.</c>
<d>Pine trees thrive in relatively wet climates, whereas oaks prefer drier ones.</d>
<e>Pine trees thriving in climates that are relatively wet ones, oaks prefer drier climates.</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26049-!-item-!-188;#058&002254</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Five fledgling sea eagles left their nests in western Scotland this summer, bringing to 34 the number of wild birds successfully raised since transplants from Norway began in 1975.</content>
<a>bringing</a>
<b>and brings</b>
<c>and it brings</c>

<d>and it brought</d>
<e>and brought</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26095-!-item-!-188;#058&002442</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to some economists, the July decrease in unemployment so that it was the lowest in two years suggests that the gradual improvement in the job market is continuing.</content>
<a>so that it was the lowest in two years</a>

<b>so that it was the lowest two-year rate</b>
<c>to what would be the lowest in two years</c>
<d>to a two-year low level</d>
<e>to the lowest level in two years</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26141-!-item-!-188;#058&002444</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Initiated five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World on Columbus Day 1992, Project SETI pledged a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence.</content>
<a>Initiated five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World on Columbus Day 1992, Project SETI pledged a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence.</a>
<b>Initiated on Columbus Day 1992, five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World, a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence was pledged by Project SETI.</b>
<c>Initiated on Columbus Day 1992, five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World, Project SETI pledged a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence.</c>
<d>Pledging a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence, the initiation of Project SETI five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World on Columbus Day 1992.</d>
<e>Pledging a $100 million investment in the search for extraterrestrial intelligence five centuries after Europeans arrived in the New World, on Columbus Day 1992, the initiation of Project SETI took place.</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26187-!-item-!-188;#058&002462</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>More than 300 rivers drain into Siberia's Lake Baikal, which holds 20 percent of the world's fresh water, more than all the North American Great Lakes combined.</content>
<a>More than 300 rivers drain into Siberia's Lake Baikal, which holds 20 percent of the world's fresh water, more than all the North American Great Lakes combined.</a>
<b>With 20 percent of the world's fresh water, that is more than all the North American Great Lakes combined, Siberia's Lake Baikal has more than 300 rivers that drain into it.</b>
<c>Siberia's Lake Baikal, with more than 300 rivers draining into it, it holds more of the world's fresh water than all that of the North American Great Lakes combined, 20 percent.</c>
<d>While more than 300 rivers drain into it, Siberia's Lake Baikal holds 20 percent of the world's fresh water, which is more than all the North American Great Lakes combined.</d>
<e>More than all the North American Great Lakes combined, Siberia's Lake Baikal, with more than 300 rivers draining into it, holds 20 percent of the world's fresh water.</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26233-!-item-!-188;#058&002541</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Hundreds of species of fish generate and discharge electric currents, in bursts or as steady electric fields around their bodies, using their power either to find and attack prey, to defend themselves, or also for communicating and navigating.</content>
<a>either to find and attack prey, to defend themselves, or also for communicating and navigating</a>
<b>either for finding and attacking prey, defend themselves, or for communication and navigation</b>
<c>to find and attack prey, for defense, or communication and navigation</c>

<d>for finding and attacking prey, to defend themselves, or also for communication and navigation</d>
<e>to find and attack prey, to defend themselves, or to communicate and navigate</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26279-!-item-!-188;#058&002548</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In laboratory rats, a low dose of aspirin usually suffices to block production of thromboxane, which is a substance that promotes blood clotting, but not seriously interfering with the production of prostacyclin, which prevents clotting.</content>
<a>which is a substance that promotes blood clotting, but not seriously interfering</a>

<b>a substance that promotes blood clotting, but not seriously interfering</b>
<c>a substance that promotes blood clotting, but does not seriously interfere</c>
<d>which is a substance to promote blood clotting, but does not seriously interfere</d>
<e>which is a substance that promotes blood clotting, but not a serious interference</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26325-!-item-!-188;#058&002592</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Thomas Eakins's powerful style and his choices of subject--the advances in modern surgery, the discipline of sport, the strains of individuals in tension with society or even with themselves--was as disturbing to his own time as it is compelling for ours.</content>
<a>was as disturbing to his own time as it is</a>
<b>were as disturbing to his own time as they are</b>
<c>has been as disturbing in his own time as they are</c>
<d>had been as disturbing in his own time as it was</d>
<e>have been as disturbing in his own time as</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26371-!-item-!-188;#058&002614</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>One report concludes that many schools do not have, or likely to have, enough computers to use them effectively.</content>
<a>or</a>
<b>nor</b>
<c>or are</c>
<d>nor are they</d>
<e>nor are not</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26417-!-item-!-188;#058&002629</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like Rousseau, Tolstoi rebelled against the unnatural complexity of human relations in modern society.</content>
<a>Like Rousseau, Tolstoi rebelled</a>
<b>Like Rousseau, Tolstoi's rebellion was</b>
<c>As Rousseau, Tolstoi rebelled</c>

<d>As did Rousseau, Tolstoi's rebellion was</d>
<e>Tolstoi's rebellion, as Rousseau's, was</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26463-!-item-!-188;#058&002639</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Sports Medicine Programs of the Olympic Training Center, a complex where final tryouts are held for athletes representing the United States in the Olympics, is geared toward enhancing athletes' performance and toward their preparation for international competition.</content>
<a>is geared toward enhancing athletes' performance and toward their preparation</a>

<b>is geared to enhance the performance of athletes and to prepare them</b>
<c>are geared to enhance athletes' performance and their preparation</c>
<d>are geared toward the enhancement of athletes' performance and toward preparing them</d>
<e>are geared toward enhancing the performance of athletes and preparing them</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26509-!-item-!-188;#058&002648</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>With an awareness that there are connotations associated with the numbers 1 and 2 and the letters A and B, companies conducting consumer taste tests of foods or beverages typically choose numbers such as 697 or 483 to label the products.</content>
<a>With an awareness that there are connotations associated with the numbers 1 and 2 and the letters A and B</a>
<b>Because the numbers 1 and 2 and the letters A and B have connotations they are aware of</b>
<c>Because of an awareness of the numbers 1 and 2 and the letters A and B having connotations</c>
<d>Aware of the connotations of the numbers 1 and 2 and the letters A and B</d>
<e>Since the numbers 1 and 2 and the letters A and B have connotations associated with them and they are aware of it</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26555-!-item-!-188;#058&002661</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The budget for education reflects the administration's demand that the money is controlled by local school districts, but it can only be spent on teachers, not on books, computers, or other materials or activities.</content>
<a>the money is controlled by local school districts, but it can only be spent</a>
<b>the money be controlled by local school districts, but it allows them to spend the money only</b>
<c>the money is to be controlled by local school districts, but allowing it only to be spent</c>
<d>local school districts are in control of the money, but it allows them to spend the money only</d>
<e>local school districts are to be in control of the money, but it can only spend it</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26601-!-item-!-188;#058&002718</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>As a result of a supernova explosion, every human being on Earth was bombarded on February 23, 1987, by about 100 billion neutrinos; fortunately, neutrinos are harmless elementary particles that are produced in nuclear reactions and that interact very weakly with matter.</content>
<a>neutrinos are harmless elementary particles that are produced in nuclear reactions and that</a>
<b>neutrinos, which are harmless, are elementary particles produced in nuclear reactions and which</b>
<c>neutrinos are harmless elementary particles produced in nuclear reactions and which</c>

<d>these harmless elementary particles are produced in nuclear reactions, and neutrinos</d>
<e>these elementary particles, harmless products of nuclear reactions, are neutrinos that</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26647-!-item-!-188;#058&002738</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A one-million-year-old skull bearing traits associated both with Homo erectus and, in addition, Homo sapiens has been found in the Afar region of Eritrea, and indicates that modern humans developed much earlier than previously thought.</content>
<a>both with Homo erectus and, in addition, Homo sapiens has been found in the Afar region of Eritrea, and indicates</a>

<b>both with Homo erectus and Homo sapiens have been found in the Afar region of Eritrea, which indicates</b>
<c>with both Homo erectus and Homo sapiens has been found in the Afar region of Eritrea, indicating</c>
<d>with both Homo erectus and Homo sapiens and found in the Afar region of Eritrea, indicating</d>
<e>with both Homo erectus and Homo sapiens have been found in the Afar region of Eritrea, which indicates</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26693-!-item-!-188;#058&002873</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Scientists at the Los Alamos National Laboratory have succeeded for the first time in mining heat from the Earth's interior and producing energy on a commercial scale, enough for efficient generation of electricity and heating factories and homes.</content>
<a>and producing energy on a commercial scale, enough for efficient generation of electricity and heating</a>
<b>and producing enough energy on a commercial scale for electricity to be generated efficiently and to heat</b>
<c>for energy production on a commercial scale, enough for generating electricity efficiently and to heat</c>
<d>to produce energy on a commercial scale, enough for generating electricity efficiently and for heating</d>
<e>to produce enough energy on a commercial scale for efficient generation of electricity and heat</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26787-!-item-!-188;#058&002971</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The application of a new method for analyzing the chemistry of tooth enamel allows scientists to examine molars of prehuman ancestors and determining that their diets were more varied than had been supposed.</content>
<a>The application of a new method for analyzing the chemistry of tooth enamel allows scientists to examine molars of prehuman ancestors and determining</a>
<b>Through the application of a new method for analyzing the chemistry of tooth enamel, the molars of prehuman ancestors were examined by scientists who determined</b>
<c>When they applied a new method for analyzing the chemistry of tooth enamel, scientists examined molars of prehuman ancestors, determining</c>
<d>Applying a new method for analyzing the chemistry of tooth enamel, the molars of prehuman ancestors have been examined by scientists, who determined</d>
<e>Applying a new method for analyzing the chemistry of tooth enamel, scientists have examined molars of prehuman ancestors and determined</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26929-!-item-!-188;#058&003015</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The continental United States receives an average of 30 inches of precipitation a year; transpiration from soil and from plants returns approximately 21 of the 30 inches to the atmosphere, while the balance of 9 inches contributes to the flow of streams and rivers.</content>
<a>transpiration from soil and from plants returns approximately 21 of the 30 inches to the atmosphere, while the balance of 9 inches contributes to the flow</a>
<b>even though transpiration from soil and from plants returns approximately 21 of the 30 inches to the atmosphere, the remainder of 9 inches contribute to the flowing</b>
<c>although transpiration from soil and from plants return approximately 21 of the 30 inches to the atmosphere, the balance of 9 inches contribute to the flowing</c>

<d>with transpiration from soil and from plants to return approximately 21 inches to the atmosphere, the rest of the 9 inches contributes to the flow</d>
<e>as transpiration from soil and from plants return approximately 21 of the 30 inches to the atmosphere, the rest of the 9 inches contribute to the flow</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26975-!-item-!-188;#058&003041</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>1998 saw several new ventures promoting online distance learning both at the college and graduate level, but also faculty members in large numbers began questioning whether the computer screen was an adequate replacement for the classroom.</content>
<a>1998 saw several new ventures promoting online distance learning both at the college and graduate level, but also faculty members in large numbers began</a>

<b>In 1998 several new ventures were promoting online distance learning for both college-and for graduate-level courses, but it was also a year for a large number of faculty members who began</b>
<c>With several new ventures promoting online distance learning both for college and graduate courses in 1998, it was also a year when a large number of faculty members had begun</c>
<d>Although 1998 saw several new ventures promoting online distance learning for both college- and graduate-level courses, it was also a year when a large number of faculty members began</d>
<e>Several new ventures were promoting online distance learning in 1998, at both the college level as well as the graduate, but it was also a year for faculty members to begin in large numbers</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27021-!-item-!-188;#058&003068</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Whereas scientists, because of random fluctuations in the weather, cannot determine the transition from one season to the next by monitoring temperatures on a daily basis, so they cannot determine the onset of global warming by monitoring average annual temperatures.</content>
<a>Whereas scientists</a>
<b>Just as scientists</b>
<c>Like scientists who</c>
<d>Inasmuch as a scientist</d>
<e>In the same way a scientist</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27067-!-item-!-188;#058&003096</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The automobile company announced that the average price of next year's models would decrease four-tenths of one percent, amounting to about $72, as compared with comparably equipped cars and trucks this year.</content>
<a>The automobile company announced that the average price of next year's models would decrease four-tenths of one percent, amounting to about $72, as compared with comparably equipped cars and trucks this year.</a>
<b>The automobile company announced that the average price of next year's cars and trucks would decrease four-tenths of one percent, or about $72, from that of comparably equipped models this year.</b>
<c>The automobile company announced that there would be a decrease of four-tenths of one percent in next year's models' average price, or about $72, below this year's comparably equipped cars and trucks.</c>
<d>Compared to comparably equipped models this year, the automobile company announced that the average price of next year's cars and trucks would decrease about $72, less by four-tenths of one percent.</d>
<e>Contrasted with comparably equipped cars and trucks of this year, the automobile company announced that the average price of next year's models would decrease about $72, or four-tenths of one percent.</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27113-!-item-!-188;#058&003110</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Many teenagers undergo stress, but results of a recent study indicate that the patterns of stress that girls experience are more likely to result in depression than are those that boys experience.</content>
<a>are those that boys experience</a>
<b>what boys experience</b>
<c>boys' experience would</c>

<d>boys' stress patterns do</d>
<e>stress patterns of boys</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27159-!-item-!-188;#058&003134</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Gasoline marketing is undergoing major changes as stations often not only add convenience stores but also combine with major fast-food chains to build complexes where customers can shop and eat as well as buy gasoline.</content>
<a>not only add convenience stores but also combine with major fast-food chains to build</a>

<b>not only add convenience stores but also they combine with major fast-food chains to build</b>
<c>are not only adding convenience stores but also in combination with major fast-food chains they build</c>
<d>add not only convenience stores, but also combining with major fast-food chains to build</d>
<e>are not only adding convenience stores, but also in combining with major fast-food chains they build</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27205-!-item-!-188;#058&003142</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In addition to her work on the Miocene hominid fossil record, Mary Leakey contributed to archaeology with her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstakingly documenting East African cave paintings.</content>
<a>Leakey contributed to archaeology with her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstakingly documenting</a>
<b>Leakey contributed to archaeology by her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and by painstakingly documenting</b>
<c>Leakey was a contributor to archaeology with her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and with her painstaking documentation of</c>
<d>Leakey's contributions to archaeology include her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and her painstaking documentation of</d>
<e>Leakey's contributions to archaeology include discovering the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstaking documentation of</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27251-!-item-!-188;#058&003145</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Most vaccines are derived from weakened or killed strains of the same virus that they prevent, unlike the derivation of smallpox vaccine from a different virus altogether.</content>
<a>the derivation of smallpox vaccine from a different virus altogether</a>
<b>smallpox vaccine, which is derived from a different virus altogether</b>
<c>smallpox's vaccine, which gets derived from a different virus altogether</c>
<d>when smallpox vaccine is derived from an altogether different virus</d>
<e>the altogether different virus from which smallpox vaccine is derived</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27297-!-item-!-188;#058&003151</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike using spices for cooking, in medicinal usage they are taken in large quantities in order to treat particular maladies.</content>
<a>Unlike using spices for cooking, in medicinal usage they are taken</a>
<b>Unlike spices that are used in cooking, in using spices for medicine, they are taken</b>
<c>Unlike cooking with spices, taking spices for medicinal use is done</c>

<d>In cooking, small quantities of spices are used, whereas in medicinal usage spices are taken</d>
<e>In cooking, the usage of spices is in small quantities, whereas in medicinal usage they are taken</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27343-!-item-!-188;#058&003156</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Shipwrecks are more likely to be found undisturbed at great depths than in shallow coastal waters, which exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and makes them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether they be archaeologist, treasure hunter, or sport diver.</content>
<a>than in shallow coastal waters, which exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and makes them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether they be</a>

<b>than in shallow coastal waters, where archaeological remains are exposed to turbulence and are accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether</b>
<c>as opposed to shallow waters along the coast, where archaeological remains are exposed to turbulence and are accessible to anyone in scuba gear, including</c>
<d>instead of in shallow waters along the coast, which exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and makes them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, including an</d>
<e>instead of shallow coastal waters, because it exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and makes them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27389-!-item-!-188;#058&003179</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>First discovered more than 30 years ago, Lina's sunbird, a four-and-a-half-inch animal found in the Philippines and that resembles a hummingbird, has shimmering metallic colors on its head; a brilliant orange patch, bordered with red tufts, in the center of its breast; and a red eye.</content>
<a>found in the Philippines and that resembles</a>
<b>found in the Philippines and that, resembling</b>
<c>found in the Philippines and resembling</c>
<d>that is found in the Philippines and it resembles</d>
<e>that is found in the Philippines and that, resembling</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27435-!-item-!-188;#058&003186</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Anasazi settlements at Chaco Canyon were built on a spectacular scale with more than 75 carefully engineered structures, of up to 600 rooms each, were connected by a complex regional system of roads.</content>
<a>with more than 75 carefully engineered structures, of up to 600 rooms each, were</a>
<b>with more than 75 carefully engineered structures, of up to 600 rooms each,</b>
<c>of more than 75 carefully engineered structures of up to 600 rooms, each that had been</c>
<d>of more than 75 carefully engineered structures of up to 600 rooms and with each</d>
<e>of more than 75 carefully engineered structures of up to 600 rooms each had been</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27481-!-item-!-188;#058&003189</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Both weakened by concern about the government's agreement with the International Monetary Fund and by growing fears of a rise in inflation, the country's currency continued its slide to a record low against the dollar, which forced the central bank to intervene for the fourth time in a week.</content>
<a>Both weakened by concern about the government's agreement with the International Monetary Fund and by growing fears of a rise in inflation, the country's currency continued its slide to a record low against the dollar, which forced</a>
<b>Both concern about the government's agreement with the International Monetary Fund and the growing fears of a rise in inflation weakened the country's currency, continuing its slide to a record low against the dollar, which forced</b>
<c>Both because it was weakened by concern about the government's agreement with the International Monetary Fund and by growing fears of a raise in inflation, the country's currency continued its slide to a record low against the dollar, forcing</c>

<d>The country's currency, weakened both by concern about the government's agreement with the International Monetary Fund and by growing fears of a rise in inflation, continued its slide to a record low against the dollar, forcing</d>
<e>The country's currency, weakened by both concern about the government's agreement with the International Monetary Fund and growing fears of a raise in inflation, continued its slide to a record low against the dollar, which forced</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27527-!-item-!-188;#058&003203</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A new genetically engineered papaya was produced not by seed companies who have been motivated by profit, which was the case with most genetically modified crops previously approved for commercial use, but university and United States Department of Agriculture researchers who allowed growers to use it free of charge.</content>
<a>produced not by seed companies who have been motivated by profit, which was the case with most genetically modified crops previously approved for commercial use, but</a>

<b>produced not by profit-motivated seed companies, the case with most genetically modified crops previously approved for commercial use, but</b>
<c>produced not by profit-motivated seed companies, as was the case with most genetically modified crops previously approved for commercial use, but by</c>
<d>not produced by profit-motivated seed companies, which was the case with most genetically modified crops previously approved for commercial use, but was produced by</d>
<e>not produced by seed companies who have been motivated by profit, the case with most genetically modified crops previously approved for commercial use, but by</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27573-!-item-!-188;#058&003208</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Mideast immigrants' rates of entrepreneurship exceed virtually every other immigrant group in the increasingly diverse United States economy.</content>
<a>Mideast immigrants' rates of entrepreneurship exceed</a>
<b>Mideast immigrants are exhibiting rates of entrepreneurship exceeding</b>
<c>Immigrants from the Mideast exhibit rates of entrepreneurship exceeding those of</c>
<d>The rates of entrepreneurship in immigrants from the Mideast exceed</d>
<e>The rates of Mideast immigrants' entrepreneurship exceeds those of</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27763-!-item-!-188;#058&003346</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The bones of Majungatholus atopus, a meat-eating dinosaur that is a distant relative of Tyrannosaurus rex and closely resembles South American predatory dinosaurs, have been discovered in Madagascar.</content>
<a>The bones of Majungatholus atopus, a meat-eating dinosaur that is a distant relative of Tyrannosaurus rex and closely resembles South American predatory dinosaurs, have been discovered in Madagascar.</a>
<b>The bones of a meat-eating dinosaur, Majungatholus atopus, a distant relative of Tyrannosaurus rex and with a close resemblance to South American predatory dinosaurs, has been discovered in Madagascar.</b>
<c>In Madagascar, the bones of a meat-eating dinosaur, Majungatholus atopus, distantly related to Tyrannosaurus rex and closely resembled South American predatory dinosaurs, have been discovered.</c>
<d>A distant relative of Tyrannosaurus rex, bearing a close resemblance to South American predatory dinosaurs is Majungatholus atopus, a meat-eating dinosaur, the bones of which have been discovered in Madagascar.</d>
<e>A distant relative of Tyrannosaurus rex and closely resembling South American predatory dinosaurs, the bones of a meat-eating dinosaur, Majungatholus atopus, have been discovered in Madagascar.</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27809-!-item-!-188;#058&003354</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Data gathered by weather satellites has been analyzed by scientists, reporting that the Earth's northern latitudes have become about ten percent greener since 1980, due to more vigorous plant growth associated with warmer temperatures and higher levels of atmospheric carbon dioxide.</content>
<a>Data gathered by weather satellites has been analyzed by scientists, reporting that the Earth's northern latitudes have</a>
<b>Data gathered by weather satellites has been analyzed by scientists, and they report the Earth's northern latitudes as having</b>
<c>After analyzing data gathered by weather satellites, scientists report that the Earth's northern latitudes have</c>

<d>After analysis of data, gathered by weather satellites, scientists report the Earth's northern latitudes as having</d>
<e>After data gathered by weather satellites was analyzed by scientists, who report that the Earth's northern latitudes have</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27855-!-item-!-188;#058&003426</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike emergency calls that travel through regular telephone lines, where they thus automatically inform the operator of the location and phone number of the caller, cellular calls require emergency operators to determine the location of the caller.</content>
<a>lines, where they thus automatically inform the operator of the location and phone number of the caller, cellular calls require emergency operators to determine the location of the caller</a>

<b>lines and thus automatically inform the operator of the location and phone number of the caller, cellular calls require emergency operators to determine the location of the caller</b>
<c>lines, thus automatically informing the operator of the location and phone number of the caller, the location of the caller on a cellular phone has to be determined by the operator</c>
<d>lines, and thus automatically inform the operator of the location and phone number of the caller, emergency operators have to determine the location of the cellular phone caller</d>
<e>lines, thus automatically informing the operator of the location and phone number of the caller, emergency operators receiving a cellular call have to determine the location of the caller</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27901-!-item-!-188;#058&003440</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Recently documented examples of neurogenesis, the production of new brain cells, include the brain growing in mice when placed in a stimulating environment or neurons increasing in canaries that learn new songs.</content>
<a>the brain growing in mice when placed in a stimulating environment or neurons increasing in canaries that</a>
<b>mice whose brains grow when they are placed in a stimulating environment or canaries whose neurons increase when they</b>
<c>mice's brains that grow when they are placed in a stimulating environment or canaries' neurons that increase when they</c>
<d>the brain growth in mice when placed in a stimulating environment or the increase in canaries' neurons when they</d>
<e>brain growth in mice that are placed in a stimulating environment or an increase in neurons in canaries that</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27947-!-item-!-188;#058&003452</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Developed by Pennsylvania's Palatine Germans about 1750, they made Conestoga wagons with high wheels capable of crossing rutted roads, muddy flats, and the nonroads of the prairie and they had a floor curved upward on either end so as to prevent cargo from shifting on steep grades.</content>
<a>they made Conestoga wagons with high wheels capable of crossing rutted roads, muddy flats, and the nonroads of the prairie and they had a floor curved upward on either end so as to prevent</a>
<b>they made Conestoga wagons, which had high wheels capable of crossing rutted roads, muddy flats, and the nonroads of the prairie, and floors curved upward on their ends so that they prevented</b>
<c>Conestoga wagons, with high wheels capable of crossing rutted roads, muddy flats, and the nonroads of the prairie, and had a floor that was curved upward at both ends to prevent</c>
<d>Conestoga wagons had high wheels capable of crossing rutted roads, muddy flats, and the nonroads of the prairie, and a floor that was curved upward at both ends to prevent</d>
<e>Conestoga wagons had high wheels capable of crossing rutted roads, muddy flats, and the nonroads of the prairie and floors curving upward at their ends so that it prevented</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28041-!-item-!-188;#058&003495</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Africa's black rhino population in the mid-1970's numbered about 20,000, ten times the estimated population of 2,000 in 1997.</content>
<a>the estimated population</a>
<b>that of their estimated population</b>
<c>more than the population's estimated amount</c>

<d>more black rhinos than their population estimate</d>
<e>more than that of their population's estimated amount</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28087-!-item-!-188;#058&003498</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Scientists say that each of the photographs taken of the Ares Vallis plain by the Mars Pathfinder indicate the overwhelming extent to flooding on the planet billions of years ago and the degree that rocks were scattered by its force.</content>
<a>indicate the overwhelming extent to flooding on the planet billions of years ago and the degree that</a>

<b>indicate that the extent of the floods on the planet billions of years ago was overwhelming and the degree to which</b>
<c>indicate the overwhelming extent of the floods on the planet billions of years ago and the degree to which</c>
<d>indicates the overwhelming extent of the flooding on the planet billions of years ago and the degree to which</d>
<e>indicates the overwhelming extent to flooding on the planet billions of years ago and the degree that</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28133-!-item-!-188;#058&003500</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>For the best extraction of the flavor of saffron threads, it should be soaked in liquid after being pounded with a mortar and pestle.</content>
<a>For the best extraction of the flavor of saffron threads, it should be soaked in liquid after being pounded</a>
<b>To best extract their flavor, saffron threads should be soaked in liquid after pounding</b>
<c>The best way to extract the flavor from saffron threads is soaking them in liquid after being pounded</c>
<d>The best way to extract the flavor from saffron threads is to soak them in liquid after pounding them</d>
<e>The flavor of saffron threads can best be extracted by soaking it in liquid after pounding it</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28179-!-item-!-188;#058&003508</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The proliferation of so-called cybersquatters, people who register the Internet domain names of high-profile companies in hopes of reselling the rights to those names for a profit, led to passing the Anti-Cybersquatting Consumer Protection Act in 1999, allowing companies to seek up to $100,000 in damages against those who register domain names with the sole intent of selling them later.</content>
<a>passing the Anti-Cybersquatting Consumer Protection Act in 1999, allowing companies to seek up to $100,000 in damages against those who register domain names with the sole intent of selling</a>
<b>the passage of the Anti-Cybersquatting Consumer Protection Act in 1999, which allows companies to seek up to $100,000 in damages against those who register domain names with the sole intent that they will sell</b>
<c>the passage in 1999 of the Anti-Cybersquatting Consumer Protection Act, which allows companies to seek up to $100,000 in damages against those who register domain names with the sole intent of selling</c>
<d>the Anti-Cybersquatting Consumer Protection Act, which was passed in 1999, and it allows companies to seek up to $100,000 in damages against those who register domain names with the sole intent to sell</d>
<e>the Anti-Cybersquatting Consumer Protection Act, passed in 1999 and allowing companies to seek up to $100,000 in damages against those who register domain names with the sole intent of selling</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28225-!-item-!-188;#058&003542</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>It is unclear whether chimpanzees are unique among nonhuman species in their ability to learn behaviors from one another, or if, when other animals are studied in as much depth, similar patterns would be found.</content>
<a>if, when other animals are studied in as much depth, similar patterns would be found</a>
<b>if other animals were studied with as much depth they would exhibit similar patterns</b>
<c>would similar patterns be found in other animals if they were studied in as much depth</c>

<d>whether similar patterns would be exhibited in other animals that were studied with as much depth</d>
<e>whether other animals would exhibit similar patterns if they were studied in as much depth</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28271-!-item-!-188;#058&003560</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Paper production accounts for approximately 40 percent of the world's industrial use of wood, and the market for paper is growing faster than it is for all major wood products.</content>
<a>the market for paper is growing faster than it is for all</a>

<b>the market for paper is growing faster than the market for all other</b>
<c>the market for it is growing faster than it is for all other</c>
<d>its market is growing faster than the market for all</d>
<e>its market is growing faster than it is for all other</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28317-!-item-!-188;#058&003604</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Broccoli thrives in moderate to cool climates and propagated by seeds, either sown directly in the field or in plant beds designed for producing transplants.</content>
<a>propagated by seeds, either sown directly in the field or in plant beds designed for producing</a>
<b>propagated by seeds, sown either directly in the field or sown in plant beds designed so as to produce</b>
<c>is propagated by seeds either sown directly in the field or in plant beds designed so that they produce</c>
<d>is propagated by seeds sown either directly in the field or in plant beds designed to produce</d>
<e>is propagated by seeds, sown either directly in the field or sown in plant beds designed for producing</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28363-!-item-!-188;#058&003615</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Evolutionary psychology holds that the human mind is not a "blank slate," but instead that it comprises specialized mental mechanisms that were developed as a way of solving specific problems human ancestors faced millions of years ago.</content>
<a>the human mind is not a "blank slate," but instead that it comprises specialized mental mechanisms that were developed as a way of solving</a>
<b>the human mind is not a "blank slate" but instead comprises specialized mental mechanisms that were developed to solve</b>
<c>the human mind, instead of a "blank slate," it comprises specialized mental mechanisms that have been developed to solve</c>
<d>rather than it being a "blank slate," the human mind comprises specialized mental mechanisms that have been developed as a way of solving</d>
<e>rather than the human mind's being a "blank slate," that it comprises specialized mental mechanisms that were developed as a way of solving</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28457-!-item-!-188;#058&003634</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Paleontologist Stephen Jay Gould has argued that many biological traits are not the products of natural selection, favored due to their enhancement of reproduction or survival, but that they are simply random by-products of other evolutionary developments.</content>
<a>due to their enhancement of reproduction or survival, but that they are</a>
<b>due to the reproduction or survival they enhance, but they are</b>
<c>because they enhance reproduction or survival, but</c>

<d>because they enhance reproduction or survival, but are</d>
<e>because of enhancing reproduction or survival, but are</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28503-!-item-!-188;#058&003635</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Beneath the soil of the Malheur National Forest in eastern Oregon, a fungus has for centuries been slowly weaving its way through the roots of trees, to become the largest living single organism known to humans.</content>
<a>has for centuries been slowly weaving its way through the roots of trees, to become</a>

<b>has slowly woven its way through the roots of trees for centuries, and so becoming</b>
<c>that has been slowly weaving its way through the roots of trees for centuries has become</c>
<d>that has for centuries slowly woven its way through the roots of trees and has become</d>
<e>that, having slowly woven its way through the roots of trees for centuries, to become</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28597-!-item-!-188;#058&003702</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>By recording the noise of crinkled wrappers as they were slowly stretched out in an otherwise silent chamber, and then digitizing and analyzing the sound emissions on computers, a team of scientists found the noise not continuous but consisted of individual bursts or pops just thousandths of a second long.</content>
<a>digitizing and analyzing the sound emissions on computers, a team of scientists found the noise not</a>
<b>digitizing and analyzing the sound emissions on computers, a team of scientists found that the noise was not</b>
<c>digitizing and analyzing the sound emissions on computers, a team of scientists found the noise not to be</c>
<d>the sound emissions were digitized and analyzed on computers, a team of scientists found that the noise was not</d>
<e>the sound emissions were digitized and analyzed on computers, a team of scientists found the noise not to be</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28643-!-item-!-188;#058&003706</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Scientists have found signs that moving water changed the chemical makeup of the surface of Mars in recent eras, therefore concluding that its crust is harboring up to three times as much water than was previously thought.</content>
<a>eras, therefore concluding that its crust is harboring up to three times as much water than was</a>
<b>eras, therefore concluding that the planet's crust harbors up to three times as much water or more as was</b>
<c>eras and have therefore concluded that the planet's crust harbors up to three times as much water as</c>
<d>eras and they have concluded, therefore, that its crust harbors up to three times as much water, or more, than</d>
<e>eras and concluded, therefore, that the planet's crust is harboring up to three times more water as was</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28689-!-item-!-188;#058&003708</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The cottontail rabbit population in Orange County, California, has increased unchecked in recent years as a result of the removal of the native fox population and the clearing of surrounding woodlands.</content>
<a>years as a result of the removal of</a>
<b>years as a result of removing</b>
<c>years, resulting from the removing of</c>

<d>years, which is a result of removing</d>
<e>years, which is a result of the removal of</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28735-!-item-!-188;#058&003712</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Shipwrecks are more likely to be found undisturbed at great depths than in shallow coastal waters, which exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and makes them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether they be archaeologist, treasure hunter, or sport diver.</content>
<a>than in shallow coastal waters, which exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and makes them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether they be</a>

<b>than in shallow coastal waters, where archaeological remains are exposed to turbulence and are accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether</b>
<c>as opposed to shallow waters along the coast, where archaeological remains are exposed to turbulence and accessible to anyone in scuba gear, including</c>
<d>instead of in shallow waters along the coast, which exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and making them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, including an</d>
<e>instead of shallow coastal waters, because it exposes archaeological remains to turbulence and makes them accessible to anyone in scuba gear, whether</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28781-!-item-!-188;#058&003734</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Changes in sea level are not only a result of changes in water temperature, affecting water density, but of melting glaciers as well.</content>
<a>are not only a result of changes in water temperature, affecting water density, but of melting glaciers as well</a>
<b>not only result from changes in water temperature, which affect water density, but also when glaciers melt</b>
<c>are a result not only of changes in water temperature, which affect water density, but also the melting glaciers</c>
<d>result not only from changes in water temperature, which affect water density, but also from the melting of glaciers</d>
<e>result from not only changes in water temperature, affecting water density, but as well as when glaciers melt</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28875-!-item-!-188;#058&003751</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In the major cities of industrialized countries at the end of the nineteenth century, important public places such as theaters, restaurants, shops, and banks had installed electric lighting, but electricity was in less than one percent of homes, where lighting was still provided mainly by candles or gas.</content>
<a>electricity was in less than one percent of homes, where lighting was still</a>
<b>electricity was in less than one percent of homes and lighting still</b>
<c>there were less than one percent of homes with electricity, where lighting was still being</c>
<d>there was less than one percent of homes that had electricity, having lighting that was still</d>
<e>less than one percent of homes had electricity, where lighting had still been</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28921-!-item-!-188;#058&003760</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Each year companies in the United States could save as much as $58 billion annually by preventing illness among employees and gain as much as $200 billion through improving performance of workers if they simply provided offices with cleaner air.</content>
<a>annually by preventing illness among employees and gain as much as $200 billion through improving performance of workers if they simply provided</a>
<b>annually if they prevented employee illness and gain as much as $200 billion through worker performance improved by simply providing</b>
<c>annually in employee illness prevention and gain as much as $200 billion through worker performance improved by simply providing</c>

<d>in employee illness prevention and gain as much as $200 billion through improving performance of workers if they simply provided</d>
<e>by preventing illness among employees and gain as much as $200 billion through improved worker performance if they simply provided</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28967-!-item-!-188;#058&003792</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Stock levels for domestic crude oil are far lower than in past years, leaving domestic oil prices vulnerable to any hints of oil supplies being disrupted in the Middle East or to any unexpected consumer demand growth possibly prompted by colder-than-normal temperatures.</content>
<a>leaving domestic oil prices vulnerable to any hints of oil supplies being disrupted in the Middle East or to any unexpected consumer demand growth possibly</a>

<b>leaving domestic oil prices vulnerable to any hints of oil supply disruptions in the Middle East or any unexpected growth in consumer demand that might be</b>
<c>leaving domestic oil prices vulnerable to any hints of oil supplies that are disrupted in the Middle East or to any unexpected growth in consumer demand as was possibly</c>
<d>resulting in the fact that domestic oil prices are vulnerable to any hints of oil supplies being disrupted in the Middle East or to any unexpected consumer demand growth possibly</d>
<e>resulting in the fact of domestic oil prices that are vulnerable to any hints of oil supply disruptions in the Middle East or to any unexpected growth in consumer demand that might be</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29013-!-item-!-188;#058&003802</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Nobel Prize in chemistry was awarded to three scientists for their discovery that plastic can be made electrically conductive--an advance that has led to improvements in film, television screens, and windows.</content>
<a>that plastic can be made electrically conductive--an advance that has led</a>
<b>that plastic can be made electrically conductive--this advance leading</b>
<c>that plastic can be made to be electrically conductive, and this advance led</c>
<d>of plastic's ability to be made electrically conductive, with this advance leading</d>
<e>of plastic being able to be made electrically conductive--an advance that has led</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29059-!-item-!-188;#058&003806</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In 1945, after a career as First Lady in which she shattered expectations more audaciously than either Abigail Adams or Dolly Madison ever had been, Eleanor Roosevelt was appointed a delegate to the United Nations General Assembly by President Harry S Truman.</content>
<a>more audaciously than either Abigail Adams or Dolly Madison ever had been, Eleanor Roosevelt was appointed a delegate to the United Nations General Assembly by President Harry S Truman</a>
<b>more audaciously than either Abigail Adams or Dolly Madison, President Harry S Truman had Eleanor Roosevelt appointed to be a delegate to the United Nations General Assembly</b>
<c>with an audacity never matched in the case of Abigail Adams or Dolly Madison, President Harry S Truman had Eleanor Roosevelt appointed as a delegate to the United Nations General Assembly</c>
<d>with an audacity never matched by Abigail Adams or Dolly Madison, Eleanor Roosevelt was appointed a delegate to the United Nations General Assembly by President Harry S Truman</d>
<e>with an audacity never matched either in the case of Abigail Adams or of Dolly Madison's, Eleanor Roosevelt was appointed to be a delegate to the United Nations General Assembly by President Harry S Truman</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29201-!-item-!-188;#058&003882</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>An international team of astronomers working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres estimated to have 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter, the solar system's largest planet.</content>
<a>astronomers working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres estimated to have 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter</a>
<b>astronomers working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres estimated to be 5 to 15 times Jupiter's mass</b>
<c>astronomers is working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain, having detected at least 18 huge gas spheres that are estimated at 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter</c>

<d>astronomers, working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain, and has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres estimated at 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter</d>
<e>astronomers, working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain, has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres they have estimated to be 5 to 15 times Jupiter's mass</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29247-!-item-!-188;#058&003883</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Results of a United States study published in the Annals of Internal Medicine have shown college-educated women and women living in the South and West to be significantly more likely to be using supplemental hormones as women living in the Northeast and Midwest.</content>
<a>college-educated women and women living in the South and West to be significantly more likely to be using supplemental hormones as women living</a>

<b>college-educated women and women living in the South and West as significantly more likely to use supplemental hormones than if they are living</b>
<c>college-educated women and those living in the South and West being significantly more likely to use supplemental hormones than if they lived</c>
<d>that college-educated women and women who live in the South and West are significantly more likely to be using supplemental hormones as were women that lived</d>
<e>that college-educated women and women living in the South and West are significantly more likely to use supplemental hormones than women living</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29293-!-item-!-188;#058&003892</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recent study has found amoxicillin, long a standard treatment for ear infections, as being about as effective as newer, more expensive antibiotics and causing fewer side effects.</content>
<a>amoxicillin, long a standard treatment for ear infections, as being about as effective as newer, more expensive antibiotics and causing</a>
<b>amoxicillin, long a standard treatment for ear infections, to be about as effective compared to newer, more expensive antibiotics and with</b>
<c>amoxicillin, long a standard treatment for ear infections, to be about as effective as newer, more expensive antibiotics and that it causes</c>
<d>that amoxicillin, long a standard treatment for ear infections, is about as effective as newer, more expensive antibiotics and causes</d>
<e>that amoxicillin, long a standard treatment for ear infections, is about as effective compared to newer, more expensive antibiotics and with</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29339-!-item-!-188;#058&003906</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Methane, which has long been counted among the greenhouse gases that are implicated in global warming, comes both from natural sources such as bogs and from a host of human sources, including coal mines, leaking pipelines, landfills, and rice paddies.</content>
<a>that are implicated in global warming, comes both from</a>
<b>that are implicated in global warming, coming from both</b>
<c>being implicated in global warming, comes from both</c>
<d>implicated in global warming and coming both from</d>
<e>implicated in global warming, that come both from</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29385-!-item-!-188;#058&003910</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Archaeologists in Egypt have excavated a 5,000-year-old wooden hull that is the earliest surviving example of a "built" boat--in other words, a boat constructed out of planks fitted together--and that thus represents a major advance, in terms of boat-building technology, over the dugout logs and reed vessels of more ancient vintage.</content>
<a>together--and that thus represents</a>
<b>together--and this has represented</b>
<c>together, and it represents</c>

<d>together that was representing</d>
<e>together to represent</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29431-!-item-!-188;#058&003914</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Although they are more temperamental and far more expensive than transistor-driven amplifiers, many audiophiles and audio professionals prefer the warmer, richer tones produced by vacuum-tube-driven amplifiers.</content>
<a>many audiophiles and audio professionals prefer the warmer, richer tones produced by vacuum-tube-driven amplifiers</a>

<b>many audiophiles and audio professionals think the warmer, richer tones produced by vacuum-tube-driven amplifiers make them preferable</b>
<c>warmer, richer tones are produced by vacuum-tube-driven amplifiers and they are thus preferred by many audiophiles and audio professionals</c>
<d>vacuum-tube-driven amplifiers are preferred because they produce warmer, richer tones by many audiophiles and audio professionals</d>
<e>vacuum-tube-driven amplifiers are preferred by many audiophiles and audio professionals because these amplifiers produce warmer, richer tones</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29477-!-item-!-188;#058&003926</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Research has shown that when speaking, individuals who have been blind from birth and have thus never seen anyone gesture nonetheless make hand motions just as frequently and in the same way as sighted people do, and that they will gesture even when conversing with another blind person.</content>
<a>have thus never seen anyone gesture nonetheless make hand motions just as frequently and in the same way as sighted people do, and that</a>
<b>have thus never seen anyone gesture but nonetheless make hand motions just as frequently and in the same way that sighted people do, and</b>
<c>have thus never seen anyone gesture, that they nonetheless make hand motions just as frequently and in the same way as sighted people do, and</c>
<d>thus they have never seen anyone gesture, but nonetheless they make hand motions just as frequently and in the same way that sighted people do, and that</d>
<e>thus they have never seen anyone gesture nonetheless make hand motions just as frequently and in the same way that sighted people do, and</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29523-!-item-!-188;#058&003931</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Both the complexity of the phenomenon known as extinction and the vastness of the biosphere, having prompted many scientists to call for a large increase in the number of biologists working both in the field and in laboratories to clarify the relationships among the planet's many endangered life-forms.</content>
<a>and the vastness of the biosphere, having prompted many scientists to call for a large increase in the number of biologists working both</a>
<b>and the vastness of the biosphere has prompted many scientists calling for a large increase in the number of biologists both working</b>
<c>and the vastness of the biosphere have prompted many scientists to call for a large increase in the number of biologists working both</c>
<d>as well as the vastness of the biosphere have prompted many scientists to call for a large increase in the number of biologists who both work</d>
<e>as well as the vastness of the biosphere has prompted many scientists to call for a large increase in the number of biologists who work both</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29569-!-item-!-188;#058&003953</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The decline of the mountain yellow-legged frog in the high reaches of the Sierra Nevada has become severe enough for the United States Fish and Wildlife Service quite possibly to list it as an endangered species in the near future.</content>
<a>severe enough for the United States Fish and Wildlife Service quite possibly to list it</a>
<b>severe enough so that the United States Fish and Wildlife Service could well list them</b>
<c>severe enough for it quite possibly to be listed by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service</c>

<d>so severe that the United States Fish and Wildlife Service could well list it</d>
<e>so severe that they could well be listed by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29615-!-item-!-188;#058&003960</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike frogs that metamorphose from tadpoles into adults within a one-year period, it takes three to four years for the mountain yellow-legged frog of the Sierra Nevada to reach adulthood, and so they are restricted to deeper bodies of water that do not dry up in summer or freeze solid in winter.</content>
<a>it takes three to four years for the mountain yellow-legged frog of the Sierra Nevada to reach adulthood, and so they are</a>

<b>it takes the mountain yellow-legged frog of the Sierra Nevada three to four years until it reaches adulthood, and therefore it is</b>
<c>in the Sierra Nevada, mountain yellow-legged tree frogs take three to four years to reach adulthood, thus being</c>
<d>mountain yellow-legged frogs of the Sierra Nevada take three to four years until they reach adulthood, thus</d>
<e>mountain yellow-legged frogs of the Sierra Nevada take three to four years to reach adulthood, and so they are</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29661-!-item-!-188;#058&003962</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In some species of cricket, the number of chirps per minute used by the male for attracting females rise and fall in accordance with the surrounding temperature, and they can in fact serve as an approximate thermometer.</content>
<a>for attracting females rise and fall in accordance with the surrounding temperature, and they can in fact serve</a>
<b>for attracting females rises and falls in accordance with the surrounding temperature, which can in fact serve</b>
<c>in attracting females rise and fall in accordance with the surrounding temperature, in fact possibly serving</c>
<d>to attract females rises and falls in accordance with the surrounding temperature, and it can in fact serve</d>
<e>to attract females rises and falls in accordance with the surrounding temperature, in fact possibly serving</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29707-!-item-!-188;#058&003977</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Industrialization and modern methods of insect control have improved the standard of living around the globe while at the same time they have introduced some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants, having gone virtually unregulated since they were developed more than 50 years ago.</content>
<a>while at the same time they have introduced some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants, having</a>
<b>while at the same time introducing some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants that have</b>
<c>while they have introduced some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants at the same time, which have</c>
<d>but introducing some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants at the same time that have</d>
<e>but at the same time introducing some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants, having</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29753-!-item-!-188;#058&003991</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A decade after initiating the nation's most comprehensive and aggressive antismoking program, per capita consumption of cigarettes in California declined from over 125 packs annually per person to about 60, a drop more than twice as great as in the nation as a whole.</content>
<a>per capita consumption of cigarettes in California declined from over 125 packs annually per person to about 60, a drop more than twice as great as</a>
<b>annual per capita consumption of cigarettes in California declined from over 125 packs to about 60, more than twice as great as that</b>
<c>California's annual per capita consumption of cigarettes declined from over 125 packs per person to about 60, more than twice as great as the drop</c>

<d>California has seen per capita consumption of cigarettes decline from over 125 packs annually to about 60, a drop more than twice as great as that</d>
<e>California has seen annual per capita consumption of cigarettes decline from over 125 packs per person to about 60, more than twice as great as that</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29799-!-item-!-188;#058&004009</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A study of food resources in the North Pacific between 1989 and 1996 revealed that creatures of the seabed were suffering from dwindling food supplies, possibly resulting from increasing sea surface temperatures during the same period.</content>
<a>that creatures of the seabed were suffering from dwindling food supplies, possibly resulting from increasing</a>

<b>that creatures of the seabed were suffering because food supplies were dwindling, possibly as a result of an increase in</b>
<c>that creatures of the seabed were suffering because of food supplies, which were dwindling possibly as a result of increasing</c>
<d>creatures of the seabed that were suffering from food supplies that were dwindling, possibly resulting from an increase in</d>
<e>creatures of the seabed that were suffering because food supplies were dwindling, which possibly resulted from increasing</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29845-!-item-!-188;#058&004015</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>To help counteract the adverse effects of trout stocking on the amphibian populations in certain mountain lakes, biologists are recommending cutting back on trout stocking on the part of some states and even their being removed from some popular fishing lakes.</content>
<a>cutting back on trout stocking on the part of some states and even their being removed</a>
<b>cutting back on trout stocking on the part of some states and even that they remove them</b>
<c>that trout stocking be cut back in some states and they even remove the trout</c>
<d>that some states cut back on trout stocking and even their being removed</d>
<e>that some states cut back on trout stocking and even remove the trout</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29891-!-item-!-188;#058&004023</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Many environmentalists, and some economists, say that free trade encourages industry to relocate to countries with ineffective or poorly enforced antipollution laws, mostly in the developing world, and that, in order to maintain competitiveness, rich nations have joined this downward slide toward more lax attitudes about pollution.</content>
<a>that, in order to maintain competitiveness, rich nations have joined this downward slide toward more lax attitudes about pollution</a>
<b>that, for maintaining competitiveness, rich nations join in this downward slide toward more lax attitudes about pollution</b>
<c>that rich nations join this downward slide toward more lax attitudes about pollution because of wanting to maintain competitiveness</c>
<d>that in rich nations, joining this downward slide toward more lax attitudes about pollution is a result of wanting to maintain competition</d>
<e>that wanting to maintain competition is making rich nations join in this downward slide toward an attitude about pollution that is more lax</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29937-!-item-!-188;#058&004052</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Recent breakthroughs in technology have made it possible that high-definition digital video cameras are able to capture material with a degree of fidelity that nearly compares to 35-millimeter film and to project it digitally in theaters with no resulting loss of image quality.</content>
<a>it possible that high-definition digital video cameras are able to capture material with a degree of fidelity that nearly compares to</a>
<b>it possible to have high-definition digital video cameras that can capture material at a degree of fidelity almost like that with</b>
<c>it possible for high-definition digital video cameras to capture material with a degree of fidelity nearly comparable to that of</c>

<d>possible high-definition digital video cameras that can capture material at a degree of fidelity almost like</d>
<e>possible high-definition digital video cameras able to capture material with a degree of fidelity that nearly compares to that with</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29983-!-item-!-188;#058&004080</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Simply because they are genetically engineered does not make it any more likely for plants to become an invasive or persistent weed, according to a decade-long study published in the journal Nature.</content>
<a>because they are genetically engineered does not make it any more likely for plants to</a>

<b>because it is genetically engineered does not make a plant any more likely to</b>
<c>being genetically engineered does not make it any more likely that plants will</c>
<d>being genetically engineered does not make a plant any more likely to</d>
<e>being genetically engineered does not make a plant any more likely that it will become</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30029-!-item-!-188;#058&004082</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In Britain, "pig" refers to any member of the class of domestic swine, but the United States uses the term when referring only to younger swine not yet ready for market and weighing less than 82 kilograms (180 pounds).</content>
<a>the United States uses the term when referring</a>
<b>the United States term refers</b>
<c>in the United States the term refers</c>
<d>in the United States they use the term as it refers</d>
<e>it is used in the United States when referring</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30075-!-item-!-188;#058&004088</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Even though it was not illegal for the bank to share its customers' personal and financial information with an outside marketing company in return for a commission on sales, the state's attorney general accused the bank of engaging in deceptive business practices by failing to honor its promise to its customers to keep records private.</content>
<a>by failing to honor its promise to its customers to keep</a>
<b>by its failure of honoring its promise to its customers to keep</b>
<c>in its failing to honor its promise to its customers of keeping</c>
<d>because of its failure in honoring its promise to its customers in keeping</d>
<e>because of its failure to honor its promise to its customers of keeping</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30121-!-item-!-188;#058&004107</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Officials at the United States Mint believe that the Sacagawea dollar coin will be used more as a substitute for four quarters rather than for the dollar bill because its weight, only 8.1 grams, is far less than four quarters, which weigh 5.67 grams each.</content>
<a>more as a substitute for four quarters rather than for the dollar bill because its weight, only 8.1 grams, is far less than</a>
<b>more as a substitute for four quarters than the dollar bill because it weighs only 8.1 grams, far lighter than</b>
<c>as a substitute for four quarters more than for the dollar bill because it weighs only 8.1 grams, far less than</c>

<d>as a substitute for four quarters more than the dollar bill because its weight of only 8.1 grams is far lighter than it is for</d>
<e>as a substitute more for four quarters rather than for the dollar bill because its weight, only 8.1 grams, is far less than it is for</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30167-!-item-!-188;#058&004112</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Women are expected to be the majority of students entering law school this fall, a trend ultimately placing more women in leadership positions in politics and business.</content>
<a>Women are expected to be the majority of students entering law school this fall, a trend ultimately placing</a>

<b>The majority of students entering law school this fall are expected to be women, a trend that will ultimately place</b>
<c>The majority of students entering law school this fall are expected to be women, which will ultimately place</c>
<d>It is expected that the majority of students entering law school this fall will be women, a trend ultimately placing</d>
<e>It is expected for women to be the majority of students entering law school this fall, which will ultimately place</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30213-!-item-!-188;#058&004113</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to a new report by the surgeon general, women with less than a high school education had three times the likelihood that they would begin smoking as women who went to college.</content>
<a>had three times the likelihood that they would begin smoking</a>
<b>had three times the likelihood of beginning smoking</b>
<c>were three times more likely to begin to smoke</c>
<d>were three times more likely that they would begin to smoke</d>
<e>were three times as likely to begin smoking</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30307-!-item-!-188;#058&004171</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The discovery of glass being expandable and able to be shaped by human breath revolutionized glassworking to such an extent that today "glassblowing" has become the generic term for all glassworking, whether the glass is blown or formed by other techniques.</content>
<a>of glass being expandable and able to be</a>
<b>of glass that is capable of expansion and</b>
<c>of glass being capable of expansion and that it can be</c>
<d>that glass can be expanded and it is able to be</d>
<e>that glass can be expanded and</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30353-!-item-!-188;#058&004189</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The federal immigration station on Ellis Island, which was first opened in 1892, then rebuilt in 1900, processing nearly three quarters of all immigrants entering the United States in the first quarter of the twentieth century.</content>
<a>The federal immigration station on Ellis Island, which was first opened in 1892, then rebuilt in 1900, processing nearly three quarters of all immigrants entering the United States in the first quarter of the twentieth century.</a>
<b>Having processed nearly three quarters of all immigrants who enter the United States in the first quarter of the twentieth century, the federal immigration station on Ellis Island first opened in 1892 and then was rebuilt in 1900.</b>
<c>Processing nearly three quarters of all immigrants to enter the United States in the first quarter of the twentieth century, the federal immigration station on Ellis Island first opened in 1892, being rebuilt in 1900.</c>

<d>First opened in 1892, then rebuilt in 1900, the federal immigration station on Ellis Island processed nearly three quarters of all immigrants entering the United States in the first quarter of the twentieth century.</d>
<e>Of all immigrants to enter the United States in the first quarter of the twentieth century, the federal immigration station on Ellis Island processed nearly three quarters of them, having first opened in 1892 and rebuilt in 1900.</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30399-!-item-!-188;#058&004205</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Hans Christian Andersen wrote fairy tales, which have been some of the most frequently translated works in literary history, while he wrote plays, novels, poems, and travel books, as well as several autobiographies, which remained almost unknown outside his native Denmark.</content>
<a>Hans Christian Andersen wrote fairy tales, which have been some of the most frequently translated works in literary history, while he wrote plays, novels, poems, and travel books, as well as several autobiographies, which remained</a>

<b>Hans Christian Andersen wrote fairy tales, which, while among the most frequently translated works in literary history, his plays, novels, poems, and travel books, as well as several autobiographies remain</b>
<c>Even as Hans Christian Andersen's fairy tales have been among the most frequently translated works in literary history, still his plays, novels, poems, and travel books, as well as several autobiographies, remain</c>
<d>Unlike the fairy tales written by Hans Christian Andersen, which are some of the most frequently translated works in literary history, he wrote plays, novels, poems, and travel books, as well as several autobiographies, which remained</d>
<e>Although Hans Christian Andersen wrote fairy tales that are among the most frequently translated works in literary history, his plays, novels, poems, and travel books, as well as several autobiographies, remain</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30445-!-item-!-188;#058&004235</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Though certain breeds of dog are renowned for their sense of smell, there is often a greater difference in scenting ability between two members of a single breed as there is between members of different breeds.</content>
<a>is often a greater difference in scenting ability between two members of a single breed as there is</a>
<b>is often more difference in scenting ability between two members of a single breed as to find one</b>
<c>is often a greater difference in scenting ability between two members of a single breed than</c>
<d>are often greater differences in scenting ability between two members of a single breed as there are</d>
<e>are often greater differences in scenting ability between two members of a single breed than there is</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30491-!-item-!-188;#058&004240</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Thunderclouds form when warm, moist air rises into cooler air above, because either the ground is warmer than usually or because the interaction of two air masses, one warm and one cold, forces warm air to rise.</content>
<a>because either the ground is warmer than usually or because</a>
<b>because either the ground is warmer than usual or because of</b>
<c>because of either the ground being warmer than usual or because</c>
<d>either because of the ground's being warmer than usually or because of</d>
<e>either because the ground is warmer than usual or because</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30537-!-item-!-188;#058&004273</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A study on couples' retirement transitions found that women who took new jobs after retiring from their primary careers reported high marital satisfaction, more than when retiring completely.</content>
<a>more than when retiring</a>
<b>more than if they were to retire</b>
<c>more so than those who retired</c>

<d>which was more so than those retiring</d>
<e>which was more than if they had retired</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30583-!-item-!-188;#058&004275</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Many population studies have linked a high-salt diet to high rates of hypertension and shown that in societies where they consume little salt, their blood pressure typically does not rise with age.</content>
<a>shown that in societies where they consume little salt, their</a>

<b>shown that in societies that have consumed little salt, their</b>
<c>shown that in societies where little salt is consumed,</c>
<d>they showed that in societies where little salt is consumed,</d>
<e>they showed that in societies where they consume little salt, their</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30629-!-item-!-188;#058&004284</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>India, like Italy and China, has no single dominant cuisine:  Indian food comprises many different styles of cooking, with each a product of their regional influences, from the fiery vegetarian dishes of the south to the Portuguese-influenced Goan cooking of the west, to the more familiar Mogul food of the north.</content>
<a>with each a product of their</a>
<b>with each as a product of its</b>
<c>each products of their</c>
<d>each a product of</d>
<e>each products of</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30675-!-item-!-188;#058&004285</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The population of India has been steadily increasing for decades, and it will probably have what is estimated as 1.6 billion people by 2050 and surpass China as the world's most populous nation.</content>
<a>it will probably have what is estimated as</a>
<b>they are likely to have</b>
<c>the country will probably have</c>
<d>there will probably be</d>
<e>there will be an estimated</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30721-!-item-!-188;#058&004288</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>It was only after Katharine Graham became publisher of The Washington Post in 1963 that it moved into the first rank of American newspapers, and it was under her command that the paper won high praise for its unrelenting reporting of the Watergate scandal.</content>
<a>It was only after Katharine Graham became publisher of The Washington Post in 1963 that it moved into the first rank of American newspapers, and it was under her command that the paper won high praise</a>
<b>It was only after Katharine Graham's becoming publisher of The Washington Post in 1963 that it moved into the first rank of American newspapers, and under her command it had won high praise</b>
<c>Katharine Graham became publisher of The Washington Post in 1963, and only after that did it move into the first rank of American newspapers, having won high praise under her command</c>

<d>Moving into the first rank of American newspapers only after Katharine Graham became its publisher in 1963, The Washington Post, winning high praise under her command</d>
<e>Moving into the first rank of American newspapers only after Katharine Graham's becoming its publisher in 1963, The Washington Post won high praise under her command</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30767-!-item-!-188;#058&004308</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Due to automobile-related jobs in the 1920's employing one of every eight workers, the automobile industry dominated the American economy.</content>
<a>Due to automobile-related jobs in the 1920's employing one of every eight workers, the automobile industry dominated the American economy.</a>

<b>One out of every eight workers were employed in automobile-related jobs in the 1920's, with the American economy being dominated by the automobile industry.</b>
<c>The automobile industry dominated the American economy in the 1920's, with one of every eight workers having been employed in automobile-related jobs.</c>
<d>In the 1920's, the automobile industry had dominated the American economy, when one out of every eight workers was employed in an automobile-related job.</d>
<e>In the 1920's, the automobile industry dominated the American economy, with one out of every eight workers employed in an automobile-related job.</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30813-!-item-!-188;#058&004319</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like any star of similar mass would do, once the Sun has exhausted the hydrogen in its core, it expands into a red giant, eventually ejecting its outer envelope of gases to become a white dwarf.</content>
<a>Like any star of similar mass would do, once the Sun has exhausted the hydrogen in its core, it expands into a red giant, eventually ejecting</a>
<b>Like any star of similar mass, once the hydrogen in the Sun's core is exhausted, then it expands into a red giant and eventually ejects</b>
<c>As in the case of any star of similar mass, once the hydrogen in the Sun's core is exhausted, it will expand into a red giant, and eventually ejecting</c>
<d>As any star of similar mass would, once the hydrogen in the Sun's core is exhausted it will expand into a red giant and will eventually eject</d>
<e>As would be the case with any star of similar mass, once the Sun exhausts the hydrogen in its core, it will expand into a red giant and eventually eject</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30859-!-item-!-188;#058&004335</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>When the temperature of a gas is increased, it is either accompanied by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container, or an increase in volume if the gas is able to expand.</content>
<a>When the temperature of a gas is increased, it is either accompanied by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container, or</a>
<b>When the temperature of a gas is increased, it is accompanied either by an increase in pressure if it is enclosed in a container or</b>
<c>When the temperature of a gas is increased, the increase is either accompanied by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container or by</c>
<d>Any increase in the temperature of a gas is either accompanied by an increase in pressure if it is enclosed in a container, or by</d>
<e>Any increase in the temperature of a gas is accompanied either by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container or by</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30905-!-item-!-188;#058&004341</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Surveys have shown that in up to 40 percent of elderly people living independently in affluent countries, the consumption of one or more essential nutrients is insufficient or they have deficient levels of these nutrients in their blood.</content>
<a>in up to 40 percent of elderly people living independently in affluent countries, the consumption of one or more essential nutrients is insufficient or they have</a>
<b>in up to 40 percent of elderly people who live independently in affluent countries, they consume one or more essential nutrients insufficiently or have</b>
<c>in up to 40 percent of elderly people who live independently in affluent countries, one or more essential nutrients are consumed insufficiently or having</c>

<d>up to 40 percent of elderly people living independently in affluent countries who consume insufficient amounts of one or more essential nutrients or who have</d>
<e>up to 40 percent of elderly people who live independently in affluent countries consume insufficient amounts of one or more essential nutrients or have</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30951-!-item-!-188;#058&004354</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to two teams of paleontologists, recent fossil discoveries in Pakistan show that whales, porpoises, and dolphins are more closely related to some of the oldest known even-toed ungulates--a group of hoofed mammals that today includes cows, camels, pigs, and hippos--than to any other mammals.</content>
<a>that whales, porpoises, and dolphins are more closely related to some of the oldest known even-toed ungulates--a group of hoofed mammals that today includes cows, camels, pigs, and hippos--than</a>

<b>that whales, porpoises, and dolphins are more closely related to some of the oldest known even-toed ungulates--a group of hoofed mammals that today include cows, camels, pigs, and hippos--as</b>
<c>whales, porpoises, and dolphins to be more closely related to some of the oldest known even-toed ungulates--a group of hoofed mammals that today include cows, camels, pigs, and hippos--than they are</c>
<d>whales, porpoises, and dolphins as being more closely related to some of the oldest known even-toed ungulates--a group of hoofed mammals that today includes cows, camels, pigs, and hippos--as they are</d>
<e>whales, porpoises, and dolphins as more closely related to some of the oldest known even-toed ungulates--a group of hoofed mammals that today include cows, camels, pigs, and hippos--than</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30997-!-item-!-188;#058&004357</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Whereas the use of synthetic fertilizers has greatly expanded agricultural productivity in many parts of the world, an increase in their use can create serious environmental problems such as water pollution, and their substitution for more traditional fertilizers may accelerate soil structure deterioration and soil erosion.</content>
<a>an increase in their use can create serious environmental problems such as water pollution, and their substitution for more traditional fertilizers</a>
<b>an increase in their use can create serious environmental problems like water pollution, and if substituted for more traditional fertilizers, it</b>
<c>if these fertilizers are used increasingly, they can create serious environmental problems such as water pollution, and if used as substitutions for more traditional fertilizers, they</c>
<d>the increased usage of these fertilizers can create serious environmental problems such as water pollution, while if substituted for more traditional fertilizers, this substitution</d>
<e>the increased usage of these fertilizers can create serious environmental problems like water pollution, while their substitution for more traditional fertilizers</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>31091-!-item-!-188;#058&004372</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The computer company registered a $16 million net loss for the year, largely because it was profitable only overseas, where much of their profits were used for paying higher taxes, while continuing to lose money in North America.</content>
<a>where much of their profits were used for paying higher taxes, while continuing</a>
<b>where much of their profits went to pay higher taxes, as they continued</b>
<c>where much of its profit went to pay higher taxes, while it continued</c>
<d>with much of their profits going to pay higher taxes, while continuing</d>
<e>with much of the profit used for paying higher taxes, as it continued</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31137-!-item-!-188;#058&004397</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The agreement, the first to formally require industrialized countries to cut emissions of gases linked to global warming, is a formal protocol by which 38 industrialized countries must reduce emissions of these gases by 2012 or face heavy penalties.</content>
<a>by which</a>
<b>for which</b>
<c>under which</c>

<d>such that</d>
<e>wherein</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31183-!-item-!-188;#058&004404</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>After decreasing steadily in the mid-1990's, the percentage of students in the United States finishing high school or having earned equivalency diplomas increased in the last three years of the decade, up to 86.5 percent in 2000 from 85.9 percent in 1999 and 84.8 percent in 1998.</content>
<a>finishing high school or having earned equivalency diplomas increased in the last three years of the decade, up to 86.5 percent in 2000 from 85.9 percent in 1999 and</a>

<b>finishing high school or earning equivalency diplomas, increasing in the last three years of the decade, rising to 86.5 percent in 2000 from 85.9 percent in 1999 and from</b>
<c>having finished high school or earning an equivalency diploma increased in the last three years of the decade, and rose to 86.5 percent in 2000 from 85.9 percent in 1999 and from</c>
<d>who either finished high school or they earned an equivalency diploma, increasing in the last three years of the decade, rose to 86.5 percent in 2000 from 85.9 percent in 1999 and</d>
<e>who finished high school or earned equivalency diplomas increased in the last three years of the decade, to 86.5 percent in 2000 from 85.9 percent in 1999 and</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31278-!-item-!-188;#058&004418</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to a study published in The New England Journal of Medicine, aspirin prevents blood clots just as well as a commonly used and more expensive blood-thinning drug does.</content>
<a>prevents blood clots just as well as a commonly used and more expensive blood-thinning drug does</a>
<b>prevents blood clots just as well as does a commonly used and a more expensive blood-thinning drug</b>
<c>prevents blood clots just as well as will a commonly used and more expensive blood-thinning drug</c>
<d>works just as well as a commonly used and more expensive blood-thinning drug at the prevention of blood clots</d>
<e>works just as well as does a commonly used blood-thinning drug, which is also more expensive, at preventing blood clots</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>31324-!-item-!-188;#058&004419</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In addition to her work on the Miocene hominid fossil record, Mary Leakey contributed to archaeology through her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and through her painstaking documentation of East African cave paintings.</content>
<a>Mary Leakey contributed to archaeology through her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and through her painstaking documentation of</a>
<b>Mary Leakey contributed to archaeology by her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstakingly documenting</b>
<c>Mary Leakey was a contributor to archaeology by discovering the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and with her painstaking documentation of</c>
<d>Mary Leakey's contributions to archaeology include her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstakingly documenting</d>
<e>Mary Leakey's contributions to archaeology include her discovering the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstaking documentation of</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31370-!-item-!-188;#058&004475</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Industrialization and modern methods of insect control have improved the standard of living around the globe while at the same time they have introduced some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants, having gone virtually unregulated since they were developed more than 50 years ago.</content>
<a>while at the same time they have introduced some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants, having</a>
<b>while at the same time introducing some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants that have</b>
<c>while they have introduced some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants at the same time, and have</c>

<d>but introducing some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants at the same time that have</d>
<e>but at the same time introduce some 100,000 dangerous chemical pollutants, having</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31416-!-item-!-188;#058&004490</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The particular design of muscles and bones in the neck and limbs of the turtle allow that it can draw in its exposed parts such that an attacker can find nothing but hard shell to bite.</content>
<a>allow that it can draw in its exposed parts such that</a>

<b>allow it to draw in its exposed parts, and so</b>
<c>allows for it to draw in its exposed parts and that</c>
<d>allows that it can draw in its exposed parts, and so</d>
<e>allows it to draw in its exposed parts, so that</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31462-!-item-!-188;#058&004501</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recent review of pay scales indicates that CEO's now earn an average of 419 times more pay than blue-collar workers, compared to a ratio of 42 times in 1980.</content>
<a>that CEO's now earn an average of 419 times more pay than blue-collar workers, compared to a ratio of 42 times</a>
<b>that, on average, CEO's now earn 419 times the pay of blue-collar workers, a ratio that compares to 42 times</b>
<c>that, on average, CEO's now earn 419 times the pay of blue-collar workers, as compared to 42 times their pay, the ratio</c>
<d>CEO's who now earn on average 419 times more pay than blue-collar workers, as compared to 42 times their pay, the ratio</d>
<e>CEO's now earning an average of 419 times the pay of blue-collar workers, compared to the ratio of 42 times</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>31556-!-item-!-188;#058&004545</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In the past several years, astronomers have detected more than 80 massive planets, most of them as large or larger than Jupiter, which circle other stars.</content>
<a>most of them as large or larger than Jupiter, which circle</a>
<b>most of them as large or larger than Jupiter and circling</b>
<c>most of them at least as large as Jupiter, circling</c>
<d>mostly at least as large as Jupiter, which circle</d>
<e>mostly as large or larger than Jupiter, circling</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31602-!-item-!-188;#058&004586</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Among lower-paid workers, union members are less likely than nonunion members to be enrolled in lower-end insurance plans imposing stricter limits on medical services and requiring doctors to see more patients, and spend less time with each.</content>
<a>imposing stricter limits on medical services and requiring doctors to see more patients, and spend</a>
<b>imposing stricter limits on medical services, requiring doctors to see more patients, and spending</b>
<c>that impose stricter limits on medical services, require doctors to see more patients, and spend</c>

<d>that impose stricter limits on medical services and require doctors to see more patients, spending</d>
<e>that impose stricter limits on medical services, requiring doctors to see more patients and spending</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31696-!-item-!-188;#058&004702</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>At one time, the majestic American chestnut was so prevalent that it was said a squirrel could jump from tree to tree without once touching the ground between New York State and Georgia.</content>

<a>so prevalent that it was said a squirrel could</a>
<b>so prevalent that a squirrel was said that it could</b>
<c>so prevalent for a squirrel to be said to be able to</c>
<d>prevalent enough that it was said a squirrel could</d>
<e>prevalent enough for a squirrel to be said to be able to</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31742-!-item-!-188;#058&004710</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>It seems likely that a number of astronomical phenomena, such as the formation of planetary nebulas, may be caused by the interaction where two stars orbit each other at close range.</content>
<a>may be caused by the interaction where two stars orbit each other</a>
<b>may be caused by the interaction between two stars that each orbit the other</b>
<c>are because of the interaction between two stars that orbit each other</c>
<d>are caused by the interaction of two stars where each is orbiting the other</d>
<e>are caused by the interaction of two stars orbiting each other</e>
<answer>E</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32028-!-item-!-188;#058&005735</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Swedish warship Vasa, sunk in 1628 and raised in 1961, was preserved in the cold water of Stockholm harbor, where low salinity inhibits the growth of marine borers that in most seas devour every exposed scrap of a sunken ship's wooden hull.</content>
<a>was preserved in the cold water of Stockholm harbor, where low salinity inhibits</a>
<b>being preserved in the cold water of Stockholm harbor, because the low salinity there is able to inhibit</b>
<c>and preserved in the cold water of Stockholm harbor, the low salinity there inhibits</c>
<d>having been preserved in the cold water of Stockholm harbor, whose low salinity inhibits</d>

<e>had been preserved in the cold water of Stockholm harbor, because of low salinity there inhibiting</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32170-!-item-!-188;#058&006029</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to scientists at the University of Alaska, while the surface temperature of the globe has risen over the last century by about one degree Fahrenheit, the surface temperature in Alaska, Siberia, and northwestern Canada has increased in the previous thirty years by about five degrees.</content>
<a>the surface temperature in Alaska, Siberia, and northwestern Canada has increased in the previous thirty years by about five degrees</a>
<b>the surface temperature in Alaska, Siberia, and northwestern Canada has increased over the last thirty years by about five degrees</b>

<c>there was an increase in the last thirty years by about five degrees in Alaska, Siberia, and northwestern Canada</c>
<d>it had increased in Alaska, Siberia, and northwestern Canada by about five degrees over the previous thirty years</d>
<e>it has increased in Alaska, Siberia, and northwestern Canada over the previous thirty years by about five degrees</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32216-!-item-!-188;#058&006031</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>On Earth, among the surest indications of sunspot cycles are believed to be the rate that trees grow, as seen in the rings visible in the cross sections of their trunks.</content>

<a>On Earth, among the surest indications of sunspot cycles are believed to be the rate that trees grow</a>
<b>On Earth, among the surest indications of sunspot cycles are, it is believed, the rate of tree growth</b>
<c>On Earth, the rate at which trees grow is believed to be among the surest indications of sunspot cycles</c>
<d>Among the surest indications on Earth of sunspot cycles, believed to be the tree growth rate</d>
<e>Among the surest indications on Earth of sunspot cycles is believed to be the rate at which trees grow</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32262-!-item-!-188;#058&006043</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>In human hearing, subtle differences in how the two ears hear a given sound help the listener determine the qualities of that sound.</content>
<a>in how the two ears hear a given sound help the listener determine</a>
<b>in the two ears hearing a given sound help the listener in determining</b>
<c>in how a sound is heard by the two ears helps the listener determine</c>
<d>between how the two ears hear a given sound helps the listener in determining</d>
<e>between how a sound is heard by the two ears help the listener in determining</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32308-!-item-!-188;#058&006094</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The federal rules aimed at protecting human subjects of medical experiments were established to ensure that patients must be warned of potential risks and an independent panel would evaluate the experiment before it was conducted.</content>
<a>must be warned of potential risks and an independent panel would</a>
<b>must be warned of potential risks and that an independent panel</b>
<c>are warned about potential risks and that an independent panel</c>
<d>will be warned about potential risks and an independent panel would</d>

<e>would be warned of potential risks and that an independent panel would</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32450-!-item-!-188;#058&006160</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to a 1996 study published in the Journal of Human Resources, Americans of Middle Eastern descent were twice as likely as was the national average to be self-employed.</content>
<a>as was the national average to be self-employed</a>
<b>as the average American to be self-employed</b>

<c>as the national average that they would be self-employed</c>
<d>to be self-employed than was the average American</d>
<e>that they would be self-employed than was the national average</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32496-!-item-!-188;#058&006253</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Despite there being no fundamental difference in shipbuilding traditions in Viking-Age Scandinavia from the ones in other parts of Northern Europe, archaeological evidence shows that Viking ships were lighter, slimmer, faster, and thus probably more seaworthy than the heavier vessels used by the English at that time.</content>

<a>Despite there being no fundamental difference in shipbuilding traditions in Viking-Age Scandinavia from the ones</a>
<b>Despite no fundamental difference between the shipbuilding traditions in Viking-Age Scandinavia from those</b>
<c>With shipbuilding traditions in Viking-Age Scandinavia not fundamentally different from those</c>
<d>With the shipbuilding traditions in Viking-Age Scandinavia having no fundamental difference from the ones</d>
<e>Although shipbuilding traditions in Viking-Age Scandinavia were not fundamentally different from those</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32542-!-item-!-188;#058&006254</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>To protect English manufacturers of woolen goods both against American and Irish competition, England passed the Woolens Act of 1698, which prohibited the export of woolen cloth beyond a colony's borders.</content>
<a>To protect English manufacturers of woolen goods both against American and Irish competition, England passed the Woolens Act of 1698</a>
<b>In order to protect English manufacturers of woolen goods against both American and Irish competition, England passed the Woolens Act of 1698</b>
<c>In order to protect English manufacturers of woolen goods against American, as well as against Irish, competition, the Woolens Act of 1698 was passed by England</c>
<d>For protecting English manufacturers of woolen goods against American, as well as Irish, competition, England passed the Woolens Act of 1698</d>
<e>For the protection of English manufacturers of woolen goods against both American and Irish competition, the Woolens Act of 1698, passed by England</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32588-!-item-!-188;#058&006258</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>When the temperature of a gas is increased, it is either accompanied by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container, or an increase in volume if the gas is able to expand.</content>
<a>When the temperature of a gas is increased, it is either accompanied by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container, or</a>
<b>When the temperature of a gas is increased, it is accompanied either by an increase in pressure if it is enclosed in a container or</b>
<c>When the temperature of a gas is increased, the increase is either accompanied by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container or by</c>
<d>Any increase in the temperature of a gas is accompanied by either an increase in pressure if it is enclosed in a container, or by</d>

<e>Any increase in the temperature of a gas is accompanied either by an increase in pressure if the gas is enclosed in a container or by</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32634-!-item-!-188;#058&006269</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Often billed as "The Genius," American pianist, singer, composer, and bandleader Ray Charles is credited with soul music's early development, a genre based on melding gospel, rhythm and blues, and jazz.</content>
<a>Charles is credited with soul music's early development, a genre based on melding</a>
<b>Charles is credited with the early development of soul music, being a genre based on melding</b>

<c>Charles is credited with the early development of soul music, a genre based on a melding of</c>
<d>Charles, credited with soul music's early development, a genre that was based on a melding of</d>
<e>Charles, who is credited with the early development of soul music, a genre based on melding</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32680-!-item-!-188;#058&006281</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>By pressing a tiny amount of nitrogen between two diamonds to a pressure of 25 million pounds per square inch, scientists not only were able to transform the gas into a solid, but they also created a semiconductor similar to silicon.</content>

<a>not only were able to transform the gas into a solid, but they also created</a>
<b>not only were able to transform the gas into a solid but also creating</b>
<c>were able not only to transform the gas into a solid but to create</c>
<d>were able not only to transform the gas into a solid but also creating</d>
<e>were not only able to transform the gas into a solid, but they were also able to create</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32726-!-item-!-188;#058&006292</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>In contrast to some fish eggs requiring months to incubate, the Rio Grande silvery minnow produces eggs that hatch in about 24 hours, yielding larvae that can swim in just three to four days.</content>
<a>some fish eggs requiring months to incubate</a>
<b>some fish, whose eggs require months to incubate</b>
<c>some fish that have eggs requiring months to incubate</c>
<d>the requirement of months of incubation for some fish eggs</d>
<e>requiring months of incubation, as some fish eggs do</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32773-!-item-!-188;#058&006296</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Until Berta and Ernst Scharrer established the concept of neurosecretion in 1928, scientists believed that either cells secreted hormones, which made them endocrine cells and thus part of the endocrine system, or conducted electrical impulses, in which case they were nerve cells and thus part of the nervous system.</content>
<a>either cells secreted hormones, which made them</a>
<b>either cells secreted hormones, making them</b>
<c>either cells secreted hormones and were</c>
<d>cells either secreted hormones, in which case they were</d>

<e>cells either secreted hormones, which made them</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32963-!-item-!-188;#058&006488</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The computer company has announced that it will purchase the color-printing division of a rival company for $950 million, which is part of a deal that will make it the largest manufacturer in the office color-printing market.</content>
<a>million, which is part of a deal that will make</a>
<b>million, a part of a deal that makes</b>

<c>million, part of a deal making</c>
<d>million as a part of a deal to make</d>
<e>million as part of a deal that will make</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33009-!-item-!-188;#058&006530</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like the thorny ballooning of a frightened pufferfish or the sudden appearance of angry sapphire hoops for which the blue-ringed octopus is named, so the California newt's display of its red underbelly is a clear warning that predators ignore at their peril.</content>

<a>so the California newt's display of its red underbelly is a clear warning that predators ignore at their peril</a>
<b>so it is at their peril that predators ignore the California newt's display of its red underbelly, a clear warning</b>
<c>the California newt's displaying its red underbelly is a clear warning for predators, so they ignore it at their peril</c>
<d>the California newt's display of its red underbelly is a clear warning that predators ignore at their peril</d>
<e>it is at their peril that predators ignore the California newt's display of its red underbelly, a clear warning</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33055-!-item-!-188;#058&006544</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Recent research indicates that two popular arthritis drugs are possibly not as safe as they initially believed.</content>
<a>that two popular arthritis drugs are possibly not as safe as they initially believed</a>
<b>that two popular arthritis drugs may not be as safe as they were initially believed to be</b>
<c>two popular arthritis drugs to possibly not be as safe as it was initially believed</c>
<d>the safety of two popular arthritis drugs may not be as great as it was initially believed</d>
<e>the safety of two popular arthritis drugs not to be as great as they were initially believed to be</e>
<answer>B</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33101-!-item-!-188;#058&006547</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recent United States Census Bureau report shows that there are more than three times as many households where the children and grandchildren are living in their grandparents' home as compared to households where the grandparents are living in their children's or grandchildren's home.</content>
<a>as compared to households where the</a>
<b>as there are households where the</b>
<c>as those whose</c>
<d>than compared to those where the</d>

<e>than there are whose</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33147-!-item-!-188;#058&006555</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Some patients who do not respond to therapies for depression may simply have received inadequate treatment, having, for example, been prescribed a drug at a dosage too low to be effective or having been taken off a drug too soon.</content>
<a>having, for example, been prescribed a drug at a dosage too low to be effective or having been</a>
<b>having, for example, a drug prescription that was ineffective because the dosage was too low, or being</b>

<c>as, for example, having too low of a dosage of a prescribed drug for it to be effective, or being</c>
<d>when they have, for example, been prescribed too low a drug dosage to be effective, or were</d>
<e>for example, when they have a drug prescription with a dosage too low to be effective, or been</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33193-!-item-!-188;#058&006626</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A different variety of giant tortoise can be found on every island in the Galapagos, each with its own style of oversized dome and comically scrawny neck.</content>

<a>each with its own style of oversized dome and comically scrawny neck</a>
<b>each with their own styles of oversized domes and comically scrawny necks</b>
<c>each having their own style of oversized dome and comically scrawny neck</c>
<d>all having their own styles of oversized domes and comically scrawny necks</d>
<e>all with their own style of oversized dome and comically scrawny neck</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33239-!-item-!-188;#058&006636</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>Like English and Italian, each of which have elaborate rules for forming words and sentences, so sign languages have rules for individual signs and signed sentences.</content>
<a>Like English and Italian, each of which have elaborate rules for forming</a>
<b>Similar to the elaborate rules that English and Italian have to form</b>
<c>Just as English and Italian have elaborate rules for forming</c>
<d>As with English and Italian, both having elaborate rules to form</d>
<e>In the same way that there are elaborate rules used to form English and Italian</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33285-!-item-!-188;#058&006648</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Joachim Raff and Giacomo Meyerbeer are examples of the kind of composer who receives popular acclaim while living, often goes into decline after death, and never regains popularity again.</content>
<a>often goes into decline after death, and never regains popularity again</a>
<b>whose reputation declines after death and never regains its status again</b>
<c>but whose reputation declines after death and never regains its former status</c>
<d>who declines in reputation after death and who never regained popularity again</d>

<e>then has declined in reputation after death and never regained popularity</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33331-!-item-!-188;#058&006672</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The largest trade-book publisher in the United States has announced the creation of a new digital imprint division, under which it will publish about 20 purely digital works to be sold online as either electronic books or downloadable copies that can be printed upon purchase.</content>
<a>works to be sold online as either electronic books or</a>
<b>works to sell them online, either as electronic books or</b>

<c>works and it will sell them online as either electronic books or as</c>
<d>works, and selling them online as either electronic books or as</d>
<e>works, and it will sell them online either as electronic books or</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33377-!-item-!-188;#058&006720</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>As the former chair of the planning board for 18 consecutive years and a board member for 28 years, Joan Philkill attended more than 400 meetings and reviewed more than 700 rezoning applications.</content>

<a>As the former</a>
<b>The former</b>
<c>Former</c>
<d>She was</d>
<e>As the</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33521-!-item-!-188;#058&006923</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>She was an educator, a builder of institutions and organizations, and a major figure in the Black church and secular feminist movements as well, so one of the best-known and most well-respected African Americans of the early twentieth century was Nannie Helen Burroughs.</content>
<a>She was an educator, a builder of institutions and organizations, and a major figure in the Black church and secular feminist movements as well, so one of the best-known and most well-respected African Americans of the early twentieth century was Nannie Helen Burroughs.</a>
<b>She was an educator, a builder of institutions and organizations, and a major figure in the Black church and secular feminist movements, and Nannie Helen Burroughs also was one of the best-known and well-respected African Americans of the early twentieth century.</b>
<c>As an educator, a builder of institutions and organizations, and a major figure in the Black church and secular feminist movements, Nannie Helen Burroughs was one of the best-known and most well-respected African Americans of the early twentieth century.</c>
<d>As an educator, a builder of institutions and organizations, and a major figure in the Black church and secular feminist movements, one of the best-known and well-respected African Americans of the early twentieth century was Nannie Helen Burroughs.</d>
<e>Being an educator, a builder of institutions and organizations, and a major figure in the Black church and secular feminist movements, one of the best-known and most well-respected African Americans of the early twentieth century was Nannie Helen Burroughs.</e>
<answer>C</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33567-!-item-!-188;#058&006988</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike the other major planets, Pluto has a highly eccentric orbit, which is thus closer to the Sun than Neptune is for 20 years out of every 230-year cycle, even though it is commonly described as the remotest planet in the solar system.</content>
<a>Pluto has a highly eccentric orbit, which is thus closer to the Sun than Neptune is</a>
<b>Pluto has a highly eccentric orbit and is thus closer to the Sun than Neptune is</b>
<c>Pluto's orbit is highly eccentric and is thus closer to the Sun than Neptune</c>
<d>the orbit of Pluto is highly eccentric and thus closer to the Sun than Neptune</d>

<e>the orbit of Pluto is highly eccentric, thus closer to the Sun than Neptune is</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33613-!-item-!-188;#058&007011</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The government predicts that, for consumers and businesses that make a large number of long-distance calls, the Federal Communications Commission's recent telephone rate cuts will greatly reduce costs, though some consumer groups disagree with the government's estimates, suggesting they are too optimistic.</content>
<a>The government predicts that, for consumers and businesses that make a large number of long-distance calls, the Federal Communications Commission's recent telephone rate cuts will greatly reduce costs</a>
<b>The government predicts that costs will be greatly reduced for consumers and businesses that make a large number of long-distance calls by the Federal Communications Commission's recent telephone rate cuts</b>

<c>The government's prediction is, for consumers and businesses making a large number of long-distance calls, costs will be greatly reduced by the recent telephone rate cuts made by the Federal Communications Commission</c>
<d>For consumers and businesses that make a large number of long-distance calls, the government's prediction that the Federal Communications Commission's recent telephone rate cuts will greatly reduce costs</d>
<e>For consumers and businesses making a large number of long-distance calls, the government predicts that the recent telephone rate cuts that the Federal Communications Commission has made will greatly reduce costs</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33659-!-item-!-188;#058&007012</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The British sociologist and activist Barbara Wootton once noted as a humorous example of income maldistribution that the elephant that gave rides to children at the Whipsnade Zoo was earning annually exactly what she then earned as director of adult education for London.</content>

<a>that the elephant that gave rides to children at the Whipsnade Zoo was earning</a>
<b>that the elephant, giving rides to children at the Whipsnade Zoo, had been earning</b>
<c>that there was an elephant giving rides to children at the Whipsnade Zoo, and it earned</c>
<d>the elephant that gave rides to children at the Whipsnade Zoo and was earning</d>
<e>the elephant giving rides to children at the Whipsnade Zoo and that it earned</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33705-!-item-!-188;#058&007028</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>One automobile manufacturer has announced plans to increase the average fuel efficiency of its sport utility vehicles by 25 percent over the next five years, amounting to roughly five miles per gallon, and representing the first significant change in the fuel efficiency of any class of passenger vehicle in almost two decades.</content>
<a>amounting to roughly five miles per gallon, and representing</a>
<b>amounting to roughly five miles per gallon, and it would represent</b>
<c>an increase that would amount to roughly five miles per gallon and it would represent</c>
<d>an increase that would amount to roughly five miles per gallon and would represent</d>
<e>which is an increase amounting to roughly five miles per gallon, representing</e>
<answer>D</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33751-!-item-!-188;#058&007036</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Due to poaching and increased cultivation in their native habitats, researchers have determined that there are fewer than 100 Arabian leopards left in the wild, and that these leopards are thus many times as rare as China's giant pandas.</content>
<a>Due to poaching and increased cultivation in their native habitats, researchers have determined that there are fewer than 100 Arabian leopards left in the wild, and that these leopards are thus many times as rare as</a>
<b>Due to poaching and increased cultivation in their native habitats, there are fewer than 100 Arabian leopards left in the wild, researchers have determined, making them many times more rare than</b>
<c>There are fewer than 100 Arabian leopards left in the wild due to poaching and increased cultivation in their native habitats, researchers have determined, which makes the leopards many times more rare compared to</c>
<d>Researchers have determined that, because of being poached and increased cultivation in their native habitats, there are fewer than 100 Arabian leopards left in the wild, thus making them many more times as rare as</d>

<e>Researchers have determined that, because of poaching and increased cultivation in their native habitats, there are fewer than 100 Arabian leopards left in the wild, and that these leopards are thus many times more rare than</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33893-!-item-!-188;#058&007190</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Shrinking faster than any other nation's, the projected decline of Japan's population is 17 percent during the next half century.</content>
<a>Shrinking faster than any other nation's, the projected decline of Japan's population is</a>
<b>Shrinking faster than any other nation, Japan's population has a projected decline of</b>

<c>The population of Japan is shrinking faster than that of any other nation and is projected to decline by</c>
<d>The Japanese population is shrinking faster than any other nation, and it has a projected decline at</d>
<e>Japan's population is shrinking faster than that of any other nation, with a projected decline at</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>33939-!-item-!-188;#058&007191</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>It is possible that, like the Volkswagen, whose unchanging exterior over decades concealed many changes in its internal machinery, the evolution of many prehistoric microbes occurred with no significant modification to their sheaths.</content>

<a>the evolution of many prehistoric microbes occurred with no significant modification to their sheaths</a>
<b>the evolution of many prehistoric microbes was occurring without significant modification of their sheaths</b>
<c>no significant modification was made to the sheaths of many prehistoric microbes as they were evolving</c>
<d>the sheaths of many prehistoric microbes went without significant modification during their evolution</d>
<e>many prehistoric microbes evolved without significant modification of their sheaths</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>34081-!-item-!-188;#058&007212</mark>

</item>

<item>
<content>An international team of astronomers working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres estimated to have 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter, the solar system's largest planet.</content>
<a>astronomers working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres estimated to have 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter</a>
<b>astronomers working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres that are at an estimated 5 to 15 times Jupiter's mass</b>
<c>astronomers is working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain, having detected at least 18 huge gas spheres that are estimated at 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter</c>
<d>astronomers, working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain, and has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres estimated at 5 to 15 times the mass of Jupiter</d>
<e>astronomers, working at telescopes in the Canary Islands and Spain, has detected at least 18 huge gas spheres they have estimated as being 5 to 15 times Jupiter's mass</e>
<answer>A</answer>

<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>34127-!-item-!-188;#058&007222</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Part of the proposed increase in state education spending is due to higher enrollment, since the number of students in public schools have grown steadily since the mid-1980's and, at nearly 47 million, are at a record high.</content>
<a>enrollment, since the number of students in public schools have grown steadily since the mid-1980's and, at nearly 47 million, are at</a>
<b>enrollment, with a number of students in public schools growing steadily since the mid-1980's and, at nearly 47 million, reaching</b>
<c>enrollment: since students in public schools have grown steadily in number since the mid-1980's and, at nearly 47 million, have reached</c>
<d>enrollment: the number of students in public schools has grown steadily since the mid-1980's and, at nearly 47 million, has reached</d>

<e>enrollment: students in public schools have grown steadily in number since the mid-1980's and, at nearly 47 million, are at</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>34173-!-item-!-188;#058&007252</mark>
</item>


<item>
<content>Since the start of the space age, more and more littering has occurred in orbits near Earth, often because the intentional discarding of lens caps, packing material, fuel tanks, and payload covers.</content>
<a>more and more littering has occurred in orbits near Earth, often because</a>
<b>orbits near Earth have become more and more littered, often from</b>
<c>orbits near Earth became littered more and more, often resulting from</c>
<d>there have been more and more littering of orbits near Earth, often because of</d>
<e>there had been littering more and more of orbits near Earth, often with</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24163-!-item-!-188;#058&001054</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In the Louisiana Purchase of 1803, the United States acquired 828,000 square miles for about four cents an acre, which more than doubled the country's size and that brought its western border within reach of the Pacific Ocean.</content>
<a>In the Louisiana Purchase of 1803, the United States acquired 828,000 square miles for about four cents an acre, which more than doubled the country's size and that brought</a>
<b>For about four cents an acre the United States acquired, in the Louisiana Purchase of 1803, 828,000 square miles, more than doubling the country's size and it brought</b>
<c>With the Louisiana Purchase in 1803, the United States acquired 828,000 square miles for about four cents an acre, more than doubling its size and bringing</c>

<d>The United States, in the Louisiana Purchase of 1803, for about four cents an acre, acquired 828,000 square miles, more than doubling the country's size, bringing</d>
<e>Acquiring 828,000 square miles in the Louisiana Purchase of 1803, the United States bought it for about four cents an acre, more than doubling the country's size and bringing</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24209-!-item-!-188;#058&001071</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Defying efforts by policymakers on both sides of the Atlantic at restraining it, the United States dollar, continuing its rise, reaching its highest level in six years against the German mark.</content>
<a>at restraining it, the United States dollar, continuing its rise, reaching</a>

<b>at restraining it, the rise of the United States dollar continued, to reach</b>
<c>at restraining it, the United States dollar continued rising, and it reached</c>
<d>to restrain it, the United States dollar continued its rise, reaching</d>
<e>to restrain it, the United States dollar is continuing its rise, and to reach</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24543-!-item-!-188;#058&001465</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>As well as heat and light, the Sun is the source of a continuous stream of atomic particles known as the solar wind.</content>
<a>As well as heat and light, the Sun is the source of a continuous stream</a>
<b>Besides heat and light, also the Sun is the source of a continuous stream</b>
<c>Besides heat and light, the Sun is also the source of a continuous streaming</c>
<d>The Sun is the source not only of heat and light, but also of a continuous stream</d>
<e>The Sun is the source of not only heat and light but, as well, of a continuous streaming</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>24589-!-item-!-188;#058&001492</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like their male counterparts, women scientists are above average in terms of intelligence and creativity, but unlike men of science, their female counterparts have had to work against the grain of occupational stereotyping to enter a "man's world."</content>
<a>their female counterparts have had to work</a>
<b>their problem is working</b>
<c>one thing they have had to do is work</c>
<d>the handicap women of science have had is to work</d>
<e>women of science have had to work</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24635-!-item-!-188;#058&001505</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>From studies of the bony house of the brain, which is the cranium, located in the back of the skull, come what scientists know about dinosaur brains.</content>
<a>From studies of the bony house of the brain, which is the cranium, located in the back of the skull, come what scientists know about dinosaur brains.</a>
<b>The knowledge that scientists know about dinosaur brains comes from studies of the bony house of the brain, located in the back of the skull, that is, the cranium.</b>
<c>The knowledge of dinosaur brains that scientists have come from studies of the bony house of the brain, which is located in the back of the skull and is called the cranium.</c>

<d>What scientists know about dinosaur brains comes from studies of the cranium, the bony house of the brain located in the back of the skull.</d>
<e>Located in the back of the skull is the cranium, the bony house of the brain, and it is from studies of this that scientists know what they know about dinosaur brains.</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24681-!-item-!-188;#058&001533</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>So-called green taxes, which exact a price for the use of polluting or nonrenewable fuels, are having a positive effect on the environment and natural resource base of countries as varied as China, the Netherlands, and Hungary.</content>
<a>as varied as</a>

<b>as varied as are</b>
<c>as varied as those of</c>
<d>that are as varied as</d>
<e>that are varied as are</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24727-!-item-!-188;#058&001574</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Ozone, a special form of oxygen that screens out harmful ultraviolet rays, reaches high concentrations twelve miles above Earth, where it has long appeared that it was immune from human influence; we have now realized, though, that emissions of industrial chlorofluorocarbons deplete the ozone layer.</content>
<a>has long appeared that it was immune from</a>
<b>has long appeared to have been immune from</b>
<c>has long appeared as being immune to</c>
<d>had long appeared immune to</d>
<e>had long appeared that it was immune to</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>24773-!-item-!-188;#058&001691</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Environmental Protection Agency frequently puts mandatory controls on toxic substances that present as little risk as one in a million chances to cause cancer.</content>
<a>as little risk as one in a million chances to cause</a>
<b>as little risk as one chance in a million of causing</b>
<c>as little risk as one chance in a million that it will cause</c>
<d>a risk as little as one chance in a million for causing</d>
<e>a risk as little as one chance in a million for it to cause</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>24819-!-item-!-188;#058&001693</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The rise of the Incan empire rested not only on the Incas' military might and the ability of their rulers but also they imposed a highly organized economic and political system on many different ethnic groups and permitting them to retain many of their customs and often their own leaders.</content>
<a>they imposed a highly organized economic and political system on many different ethnic groups and permitting them</a>
<b>on their imposition of a highly organized economic and political system on many different ethnic groups, who were permitted</b>
<c>because of their imposition of a highly organized economic and political system on many different ethnic groups, who they permitted</c>

<d>on their imposing of a highly organized economic and political system on many different ethnic groups and they permitted them</d>
<e>imposing a highly organized economic and political system on many different ethnic groups, permitting them</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25013-!-item-!-188;#058&001959</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Nine months after the county banned jet skis and other water bikes from the tranquil waters of Puget Sound, a judge overturned the ban on the ground of violating state laws for allowing the use of personal watercraft on common waterways.</content>
<a>of violating state laws for allowing</a>

<b>of their violating state laws to allow</b>
<c>that it violates state laws that allowed</c>
<d>that it violated state laws allowing</d>
<e>that state laws were being violated allowing</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25059-!-item-!-188;#058&002009</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Performing a risky maneuver that required precision flying, not only did space shuttle astronauts retrieve an orbiting satellite, it was done simultaneously while avoiding being rear-ended by a passing ultraviolet telescope.</content>
<a>not only did space shuttle astronauts retrieve an orbiting satellite, it was done simultaneously while avoiding</a>
<b>not only was an orbiting satellite retrieved by space shuttle astronauts, but they also simultaneously avoided</b>
<c>an orbiting satellite was retrieved by space shuttle astronauts who also avoided simultaneously</c>
<d>space shuttle astronauts retrieved an orbiting satellite, simultaneously while avoiding</d>
<e>space shuttle astronauts retrieved an orbiting satellite and simultaneously avoided</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25105-!-item-!-188;#058&002139</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>One of the earliest known birds with a beak and contour feathers, Confuciusornis sanctus, with large clawlike "thumbs" on its wings, which probably helped them to climb up to a launching position for flight.</content>
<a>with large clawlike "thumbs" on its wings, which probably helped them to</a>
<b>with large clawlike "thumbs" on their wings, which probably helped it to</b>
<c>had large clawlike "thumbs" on its wings, which probably helped them</c>
<d>had large clawlike "thumbs" on its wings, probably to help it</d>
<e>had large clawlike "thumbs" on their wings, probably to help it</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25151-!-item-!-188;#058&002234</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Three out of every four automobile owners in the United States also own a bicycle.</content>
<a>Three out of every four automobile owners in the United States also own a bicycle.</a>
<b>Out of every four, three automobile owners in the United States also owns a bicycle.</b>
<c>Bicycles are owned by three out of every four owners of automobiles in the United States.</c>

<d>In the United States, three out of every four automobile owners owns bicycles.</d>
<e>Out of every four owners of automobiles in the United States, bicycles are also owned by three.</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25197-!-item-!-188;#058&002294</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In the mid-1920s the Hawthorne Works of the Western Electric Company was the scene of an intensive series of experiments that would investigate changes in working conditions as to their effects on workers' performance.</content>
<a>that would investigate changes in working conditions as to their effects on workers' performance</a>

<b>investigating the effects that changes in working conditions would have on workers' performance</b>
<c>for investigating what the effects on workers' performance are that changes in working conditions would cause</c>
<d>that investigated changes in working conditions' effects on workers' performance</d>
<e>to investigate what the effects changes in working conditions would have on workers' performance</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25243-!-item-!-188;#058&002297</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The single-family house constructed by the Yana, a Native American people who lived in what is now northern California, was conical in shape, its framework of poles overlaid with slabs of bark, either cedar or pine, and banked with dirt to a height of three to four feet.</content>
<a>banked with dirt to a height of</a>
<b>banked with dirt as high as that of</b>
<c>banked them with dirt to a height of</c>
<d>was banked with dirt as high as</d>
<e>was banked with dirt as high as that of</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25289-!-item-!-188;#058&002314</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The success of the program to eradicate smallpox has stimulated experts to pursue what they had not previously considered possible--better control, if not eradication, of the other infections such as measles and yaws.</content>
<a>what they had not previously considered possible--better control, if not eradication, of the other infections such as</a>
<b>what they had not previously considered a possibility--better control, if not eradication, of such infections like</b>
<c>something they had not previously considered possible-better control, if not eradication, of such infections as</c>
<d>something not considered a previous possibility--better control and perhaps eradication, of other infections such as</d>
<e>the possibility of what they had not previously considered--better control and possibly eradication of infections like</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25335-!-item-!-188;#058&002335</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Although the first pulsar, or rapidly spinning collapsed star, to be sighted was in the summer of 1967 by graduate student Jocelyn Bell, it had not been announced until February, 1968.</content>
<a>Although the first pulsar, or rapidly spinning collapsed star, to be sighted was in the summer of 1967 by graduate student Jocelyn Bell, it had not been announced until February, 1968.</a>
<b>Although not announced until February, 1968, in the summer of 1967 graduate student Jocelyn Bell observed the first pulsar, or rapidly spinning collapsed star, to be sighted.</b>
<c>Although observed by graduate student Jocelyn Bell in the summer of 1967, the discovery of the first sighted pulsar, or rapidly spinning collapsed star, had not been announced before February, 1968.</c>

<d>The first pulsar, or rapidly spinning collapsed star, to be sighted was observed in the summer of 1967 by graduate student Jocelyn Bell, but the discovery was not announced until February, 1968.</d>
<e>The first sighted pulsar, or rapidly spinning collapsed star, was not announced until February, 1968, while it was observed in the summer of 1967 by graduate student Jocelyn Bell.</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25381-!-item-!-188;#058&002338</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Some anthropologists regard the early hominids' manner of walking as being less efficient than in modern human beings.</content>
<a>as being less efficient than in</a>

<b>as less efficient than it is in</b>
<c>as less efficient than that of</c>
<d>to be less efficient than that of</d>
<e>to have been less efficient than it is in</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25427-!-item-!-188;#058&002348</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The human nervous system and a telephone system superficially resemble each other, not only because the former carries information in the form of electrical impulses and because all of its neural pathways converge in the brain and spinal cord, which together form a kind of central exchange.</content>
<a>The human nervous system and a telephone system superficially resemble each other, not only because the former carries</a>
<b>The human nervous system and a telephone system bear a superficial resemblance because they both carry</b>
<c>The human nervous system bears a superficial resemblance to a telephone system both because the former carries</c>
<d>Superficially, a telephone system resembles the human nervous system both because they carry</d>
<e>There is a superficial resemblance between a telephone system and the human nervous system, not only because they both carry</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25474-!-item-!-188;#058&002354</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Before scientists learned how to make a synthetic growth hormone, removing it painstakingly in small amounts from the pituitary glands of human cadavers.</content>
<a>scientists learned how to make a synthetic growth hormone, removing it painstakingly</a>
<b>scientists had learned about making a synthetic growth hormone, they had to remove it painstakingly</b>
<c>scientists learned how to synthesize the growth hormone, it had to be painstakingly removed</c>
<d>learning how to make a synthetic growth hormone, scientists had to remove it painstakingly</d>
<e>learning how to synthesize the growth hormone, it had to be painstakingly removed by scientists</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25520-!-item-!-188;#058&002357</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The direction in which the Earth and the other solid planets--Mercury, Venus, and Mars--spins were determined from collisions with giant celestial bodies in the early history of the Solar System.</content>
<a>spins were determined from</a>
<b>spins were determined because of</b>
<c>spins was determined through</c>

<d>spin was determined by</d>
<e>spin was determined as a result of</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25566-!-item-!-188;#058&002406</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Scientists believe that unlike the males of most species of moth, the male whistling moths of Nambung, Australia, call female moths to them by the use of acoustical signals, but not olfactory ones, and they attract their mates during the day, rather than at night.</content>
<a>by the use of acoustical signals, but not olfactory ones, and they attract</a>

<b>by the use of acoustical signals instead of using olfactory ones, and attracting</b>
<c>by using acoustical signals, not using olfactory ones, and by attracting</c>
<d>using acoustical signals, rather than olfactory ones, and attract</d>
<e>using acoustical signals, but not olfactory ones, and attracting</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25612-!-item-!-188;#058&002525</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The new image of Stone Age people as systematic hunters of large animals, rather than merely scavenging for meat, have emerged from the examination of tools found in Germany, including three wooden spears that archaeologists believe to be about 400,000 years old.</content>
<a>merely scavenging for meat, have emerged from the examination of tools found in Germany, including</a>
<b>as merely scavenging for meat, have emerged from examining tools found in Germany, which include</b>
<c>as mere meat scavengers, has emerged from examining tools found in Germany that includes</c>
<d>mere scavengers of meat, has emerged from the examination of tools found in Germany, which includes</d>
<e>mere scavengers of meat, has emerged from the examination of tools found in Germany, including</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25658-!-item-!-188;#058&002529</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>There is a widespread belief in the United States and Western Europe that young people have a smaller commitment to work and a career than their parents and grandparents and that the source of the change lies in the collapse of the "work ethic."</content>
<a>a smaller commitment to work and a career than their parents and grandparents</a>
<b>less of a commitment to work and a career than their parents and grandparents</b>
<c>a smaller commitment to work and a career than that of their parents and grandparents</c>
<d>less of a commitment to work and a career than their parents and grandparents had</d>
<e>a lessening of the commitment to work and a career that their parents and grandparents had</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25704-!-item-!-188;#058&002607</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A team of scientists has recently provided evidence of Earth being bombarded daily with as many as 40,000 small comets, vaporizing in the upper atmosphere to fall to Earth as rain.</content>
<a>of Earth being bombarded daily with as many as 40,000 small comets, vaporizing in the upper atmosphere to</a>
<b>of Earth's being daily bombarded with as many as 40,000 small comets, vaporizing in the upper atmosphere and that</b>
<c>that as much or more than 40,000 small comets daily bombard Earth, vaporizing in the upper atmosphere, and</c>

<d>that daily Earth is bombarded with as much or more than 40,000 small comets that vaporize in the upper atmosphere and that</d>
<e>that Earth is bombarded daily with as many as 40,000 small comets that vaporize in the upper atmosphere and</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25798-!-item-!-188;#058&002669</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In an effort to increase profits, the company moved itself from emphasizing its chemicals business to expand into high-growth pharmaceuticals and futuristic biotechnologies.</content>
<a>itself from emphasizing its chemicals business to expand</a>

<b>itself from emphasizing its chemicals business then to expanding</b>
<c>from an emphasis on its chemicals business and to expanding</c>
<d>from an emphasis on its chemicals business and to expand</d>
<e>from emphasizing its chemicals business to expanding</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>25844-!-item-!-188;#058&002767</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In 1997, despite an economy that marked its sixth full year of uninterrupted expansion with the lowest jobless rate in a quarter century, the number of United States citizens declaring themselves bankrupt has jumped by almost 20 percent, at 1.34 million.</content>
<a>declaring themselves bankrupt has jumped by almost 20 percent, at</a>
<b>declaring themselves bankrupt jumped by almost 20 percent, to</b>
<c>who declared themselves bankrupt has jumped by almost 20 percent, to</c>
<d>who declared themselves bankrupt jumped almost by 20 percent, at</d>
<e>to declare themselves bankrupt jumped almost by 20 percent, at</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>25890-!-item-!-188;#058&002817</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike many United States cities, where a river is no longer the focal point of urban life, the river in San Antonio winds through the middle of the business district, and the River Walk, or Paseo del Rio, is the city's most popular attraction.</content>
<a>Unlike many United States cities, where a river is no longer the focal point of urban life, the river in San Antonio</a>
<b>Unlike the river in many cities in the United States, which is no longer the focal point of urban life, in San Antonio the river</b>
<c>Today the river in many cities in the United States is no longer the focal point of urban life, unlike San Antonio, where it</c>
<d>In few United States cities today, a river is the focal point of urban life, but the river in San Antonio</d>
<e>No longer do many cities in the United States have a river as the focal point of urban life, but in San Antonio the river</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26032-!-item-!-188;#058&002964</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Most of the purported health benefits of tea comes from antioxidants--compounds also found in beta carotene, vitamin E, and vitamin C that inhibit the formation of plaque along the body's blood vessels.</content>
<a>comes from antioxidants--compounds also found in beta carotene, vitamin E, and vitamin C that</a>
<b>comes from antioxidants--compounds that are also found in beta carotene, vitamin E, and vitamin C, and they</b>
<c>come from antioxidants--compounds also found in beta carotene, vitamin E, and vitamin C, and</c>

<d>come from antioxidants--compounds that are also found in beta carotene, vitamin E, and vitamin C and that</d>
<e>come from antioxidants--compounds also found in beta carotene, vitamin E, and vitamin C, and they</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26078-!-item-!-188;#058&002967</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Gone are the sharp edges and jutting planes of styles from former eras; instead, designers of everything from cars to computer monitors have adopted a cornerless style of smooth surfaces and curves that is more ergonomic, conforming to the shape of the body rather than flaunting shape for its own sake.</content>
<a>more ergonomic, conforming to the shape of the body rather than flaunting shape</a>

<b>more ergonomic, conformed to the body's shape and not to flaunting shape</b>
<c>ergonomic, more conformed to the shape of the body and not to shape flaunted</c>
<d>ergonomic, conforming more to the body's shape rather than shape flaunted</d>
<e>ergonomic, conforming more to the shape of the body than flaunting shape</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26124-!-item-!-188;#058&002968</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Chicago and Calumet Rivers originally flowed into the St. Lawrence by way of Lake Michigan, but having been redirected by constructing canals so that the water now empties into the Mississippi by way of the Illinois River.</content>
<a>Rivers originally flowed into the St. Lawrence by way of Lake Michigan, but having been redirected by constructing</a>
<b>Rivers had originally flowed into the St. Lawrence by way of Lake Michigan, but they have been redirected by constructing</b>
<c>Rivers, which originally flowed into the St. Lawrence by way of Lake Michigan but have been redirected by the construction of</c>
<d>Rivers, originally flowing into the St. Lawrence by way of Lake Michigan, but having been redirected by the construction of</d>
<e>Rivers, originally flowing into the St. Lawrence by way of Lake Michigan, have been redirected through the construction of</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26170-!-item-!-188;#058&003042</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like the great navigators who first sailed around the Earth, to gather information about its size and curvature of its surface, new observations have been made by astronomers that show with startling directness the large-scale geometry of the universe.</content>
<a>Like the great navigators who first sailed around the Earth, to gather information about its size and curvature of its surface, new observations have been made by astronomers</a>
<b>Like the great navigators who first sailed around the Earth for gathering information about its size and also the curvature of its surface, new observations have been made by astronomers</b>
<c>Similar to the great navigators who first sailed around the Earth, where they gathered information about its size and the curvature of its surface, astronomers have made new observations</c>
<d>Like the great navigators who first sailed around the Earth gathering information about its size and the curvature of its surface, astronomers have made new observations</d>
<e>Just as with the great navigators who first sailed around the Earth, gathering information about its size and curvature of the surface, astronomers have made new observations</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26216-!-item-!-188;#058&003085</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Besides adding complementary flavors to many foods, hot sauces stimulate the release of endorphins in the brain, just as exercise does, and these have a pain-relieving effect like morphine's.</content>
<a>hot sauces stimulate the release of endorphins in the brain, just as exercise does, and these have a pain-relieving effect like morphine's</a>
<b>hot sauces stimulate the release of endorphins in the brain, like exercise, and they have a pain-relieving effect that is like morphine</b>
<c>hot sauces and exercise both stimulate the release of endorphins in the brain, and they have a pain-relieving effect like morphine</c>

<d>the release of endorphins in the brain is stimulated both by hot sauces and exercise, and they have a pain-relieving effect like morphine's</d>
<e>the release of endorphins in the brain is stimulated by hot sauces, just as with exercise, and these have a pain-relieving effect like that of morphine</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26262-!-item-!-188;#058&003094</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike the steam locomotive, which required an hour or two of firing up before it was possible to move under its own power, nearly full power could be summoned almost instantly from the cold engine of a diesel locomotive.</content>
<a>it was possible to move under its own power, nearly full power could be summoned almost instantly from the cold engine of a diesel locomotive</a>

<b>it was possible to move under its own power, the diesel locomotive's engine, when cold, could produce nearly full power almost instantly</b>
<c>it could move under its own power, the diesel locomotive could summon nearly full power from a cold engine almost instantly</c>
<d>moving under its own power, the cold engine of the diesel locomotive could produce nearly full power almost instantly</d>
<e>moving under its own power, almost instantly a diesel locomotive could summon nearly full power from a cold engine</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26308-!-item-!-188;#058&003128</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A group of paleontologists recently announced that a site in Utah has yielded fossils of some of the biggest armored dinosaurs ever found, and that they were at least 25 million years older than any similar dinosaur type previously found in North America.</content>
<a>and that they were at least 25 million years older than any similar dinosaur type previously</a>
<b>and they are at least 25 million years older than those of any similar dinosaur type that previously was</b>
<c>and the fossils are at least 25 million years older than any similar dinosaur types that previously were</c>
<d>fossils that are at least 25 million years older than those of any similar dinosaur type previously</d>
<e>fossils at least 25 million years older than similar dinosaur types previously</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26354-!-item-!-188;#058&003133</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Using technology as new as space-age fabrics and as ordinary as common dry-cleaning chemicals, scientists and historians, in their attempt at cleaning and preserving the American flag that flew over Fort McHenry in Baltimore in 1814, are hoping that it will then last another 200 years.</content>
<a>and as ordinary as common dry-cleaning chemicals, scientists and historians, in their attempt at cleaning and preserving the American flag that flew over Fort McHenry in Baltimore in 1814, are hoping</a>
<b>and as ordinary as common dry-cleaning chemicals, scientists and historians are attempting to clean and preserve the American flag that flew over Fort McHenry in Baltimore in 1814, hoping</b>
<c>and as ordinary as common dry-cleaning chemicals, an attempt by scientists and historians to clean and preserve the American flag that flew over Fort McHenry in Baltimore in 1814 is being made in the hope</c>
<d>but also as ordinary as common dry-cleaning chemicals, scientists and historians who are attempting to clean and preserve the American flag that flew over Fort McHenry in Baltimore in 1814, hoping</d>
<e>but also as ordinary as common dry-cleaning chemicals, an attempt by scientists and historians at cleaning and preserving the American flag that flew over Fort McHenry in Baltimore in 1814 in hopes</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26400-!-item-!-188;#058&003135</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Like those of the African white and black rhinos, the Sumatran rhino has two horns, but the front one is generally less than a foot long and the second is so small that it often appears to be missing.</content>
<a>Like those of the African white and black rhinos</a>
<b>Similar to that of the African white and black rhinos</b>
<c>Like that of the African white and black rhinos</c>

<d>As with the African white and black rhinos'</d>
<e>Like the African white and black rhinos</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26446-!-item-!-188;#058&003144</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>As it is with traditional pharmacies, on-line drugstores rely on prescriptions to be successful, since it is primarily prescriptions that attract the customers, who then also buy other health-related items.</content>
<a>As it is with traditional pharmacies, on-line drugstores rely on prescriptions to be successful</a>

<b>As with the case of traditional pharmacies, on-line drugstores rely on prescriptions to have success</b>
<c>As is the case with traditional pharmacies, prescriptions are the cornerstone of a successful on-line drugstore</c>
<d>As traditional pharmacies, so on-line drugstores rely on prescriptions to be successful</d>
<e>Like traditional pharmacies, the cornerstone of a successful on-line drugstore is prescriptions</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26492-!-item-!-188;#058&003168</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>According to one expert, the cause of genetic irregularities in many breeds of dog is not so much that dogs are being bred for looks or to meet other narrow criteria as that the breeds have relatively few founding members.</content>
<a>the cause of genetic irregularities in many breeds of dog is not so much that dogs are being bred for looks or to meet other narrow criteria</a>
<b>the cause of genetic irregularities in many breeds of dog is not as much their being bred for looks or meeting other narrow criteria as much</b>
<c>it is not so much the cause of genetic irregularities in many breeds of dog that they are being bred for looks or meeting other narrow criteria as much</c>
<d>it is not so much that the cause of genetic irregularities in many breeds of dog is their being bred for looks or meeting other narrow criteria so much</d>
<e>it is not so much the cause of genetic irregularities in many breeds of dog to be bred for looks or to meet other narrow criteria</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26538-!-item-!-188;#058&003184</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Scientific evidence suggests that the benefits arising from consumption of alcohol are greatest with alcohol that is taken with meals on a moderate, regular basis than when it is consumed on binges.</content>
<a>with alcohol that is taken with meals on a moderate, regular basis than when it is consumed</a>
<b>with taking alcohol with meals on a moderate, regular basis as opposed to its consumption</b>
<c>when alcohol is taken with meals on a moderate, regular basis, rather than consuming it</c>
<d>when alcohol is taken with meals on a moderate, regular basis rather than consumed</d>
<e>when alcohol, taken with meals on a moderate, regular basis, and not consumed</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26584-!-item-!-188;#058&003206</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>During the same period in which the Maya were developing a hieroglyphic system of writing, the Aztec people also developed a written language, but it was not as highly sophisticated as that of the Maya and was more pictographic in nature.</content>
<a>but it was not as highly sophisticated as that of the Maya and was</a>
<b>but it was not as highly sophisticated as the Maya, being</b>
<c>but, not as highly sophisticated as the Maya's, was</c>

<d>not as highly sophisticated as that of the Maya, however, being</d>
<e>not as highly sophisticated as the Maya's however, it was</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26630-!-item-!-188;#058&003212</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Although ice particles in the upper atmosphere benefit Earth in that they reflect and absorb solar radiation, acting as a global thermostat and thus keeping Earth from either burning up or freezing over, they also accelerate the destruction of the ozone layer by reacting with chlorofluorocarbons (CFC's).</content>
<a>acting as a global thermostat and thus keeping Earth from either burning up or freezing over, they also accelerate</a>

<b>acting as a global thermostat and thus keeping Earth either from burning up or freezing over, while also accelerating</b>
<c>act as a global thermostat and thus keep Earth from either burning up or freezing over, while also accelerating</c>
<d>they act as a global thermostat that thus keeps Earth either from burning up or freezing over, even though it also accelerates</d>
<e>they act as a global thermostat to thus keep Earth from either burning up or freezing over, but they also accelerate</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26724-!-item-!-188;#058&003285</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The survival of coral colonies, which are composed of innumerable tiny polyps living in a symbiotic relationship with brilliantly colored algae, are being threatened, experts say, not only by pollutants like agricultural runoff, oil slicks, and trash, but also by dropped anchors, probing divers, and global warming.</content>
<a>are being threatened, experts say, not only by pollutants like</a>
<b>are being threatened, experts say, by not only pollutants such as</b>
<c>is not only being threatened, experts say, by pollutants such as</c>
<d>is not only being threatened, experts say, by pollutants like</d>
<e>is being threatened, experts say, not only by pollutants such as</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>26770-!-item-!-188;#058&003314</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recent poll indicates that many people in the United States hold a combination of conservative and liberal political views; i.e., they denounce big government, saying government is doing too much and has become too powerful, while at the same time supporting many specific government programs for health care, education, and the environment.</content>
<a>they denounce big government, saying government is doing too much and has become too powerful, while at the same time supporting</a>
<b>they denounce big government--they say that government is doing too much and has become too powerful--but supporting at the same time</b>
<c>they denounce big government, they say that government is doing too much and it has become too powerful, while they support at the same time</c>
<d>while they denounce big government, saying that government is doing too much and has become too powerful, at the same time supporting</d>
<e>while they are denouncing big government--they say that government is doing too much and it has become too powerful-- supporting at the same time</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26816-!-item-!-188;#058&003335</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Genetic engineering sometimes entails plant or animal genes' getting spliced into other species' DNA, either to improve crop yields or for warding off insects or disease.</content>
<a>plant or animal genes' getting spliced into other species' DNA, either to improve crop yields or for warding off</a>
<b>plant or animal genes that get spliced into the DNA of other species, either for improving crop yields or the warding off of</b>
<c>the splicing of plant or animal genes into other species' DNA, to either improve crop yields or to ward off</c>

<d>splicing plant or animal genes into the DNA of other species, either to improve crop yields or to ward off</d>
<e>splicing of plant or animal genes into the DNA of other species, for either the improvement of crop yields or to ward off</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>26958-!-item-!-188;#058&003387</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Those skeptical of the extent of global warming argue that short-term temperature data are an inadequate means of predicting long-term trends and point out that the scientific community remains divided on whether significant warming will occur and what impact will it have if it does.</content>
<a>on whether significant warming will occur and what impact will it have if it does</a>

<b>on whether warming that occurs will be significant and the impact it would have</b>
<c>as to whether significant warming will occur or the impact it would have if it did</c>
<d>over whether there will be significant warming or the impact it will have</d>
<e>over whether significant warming will occur and what impact it would have</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27004-!-item-!-188;#058&003398</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Once made exclusively from the wool of sheep that roam the Isle of Lewis and Harris off the coast of Scotland, Harris tweed is now made only with wools that are imported, sometimes from the mainland and sometimes they come--as a result of a 1996 amendment to the Harris Tweed Act--from outside Scotland.</content>
<a>sometimes from the mainland and sometimes they come</a>
<b>sometimes from the mainland and sometimes</b>
<c>that come sometimes from the mainland or sometimes</c>
<d>from the mainland sometimes, or sometimes it comes</d>
<e>from the mainland sometimes, or sometimes coming</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27050-!-item-!-188;#058&003400</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Since 1990 the global economy has grown more than it did during the 10,000 years from the beginning of agriculture to 1950.</content>
<a>Since 1990 the global economy has grown more than it did during the 10,000 years from the beginning of agriculture</a>
<b>Since 1990 the growth of the global economy has been more than that during 10,000 years, from when agriculture began</b>
<c>The growth of the global economy since 1990 exceeds that which had been for 10,000 years from the beginning of agriculture</c>
<d>The growth of the global economy since 1990 exceeds what it has been for 10,000 years, from when agriculture began</d>
<e>The growth of the global economy since 1990 exceeds what it did for the 10,000 years from the beginning of agriculture</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27096-!-item-!-188;#058&003405</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>With no natural predators and expanses of green suburban neighborhoods that allow no hunting, wildlife officials estimate the New Jersey deer population to have grown to exceed 175,000.</content>
<a>With no natural predators and expanses of green suburban neighborhoods that allow no hunting, wildlife officials estimate the New Jersey deer population to have</a>
<b>With no natural predators and with expanses of green suburban neighborhoods that do not allow hunting, wildlife officials' estimate of the deer population in New Jersey has</b>
<c>With no natural predators and with expanses of green suburban neighborhoods where there is no hunting, the deer population in New Jersey, wildlife officials estimate, has</c>

<d>Without natural predators and no hunting allowed in expanses of green suburban neighborhoods, New Jersey has a deer population that wildlife officials estimate to have</d>
<e>Without natural predators and with expanses of green suburban neighborhoods where there is no hunting, wildlife officials in New Jersey estimate a deer population that has</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27142-!-item-!-188;#058&003455</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Studies that have compared the different types of insects in coffee plantations and tropical forests have reported either finding a similar or a greater variety in plantations.</content>
<a>and tropical forests have reported either finding a similar or a</a>

<b>with those of tropical forests have either reported finding a similar or</b>
<c>with those in tropical forests have reported finding either a similar or a</c>
<d>to tropical forests have either reported finding a similar or</d>
<e>to those of tropical forests have reported either finding a similar or</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27188-!-item-!-188;#058&003462</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The two oil companies agreed to merge their refining and marketing operations in the Midwest and the West, forming a new company for controlling nearly fifteen percent of the nation's gasoline sales.</content>
<a>forming a new company for controlling</a>
<b>forming a new company that would control</b>
<c>which would form a new company that controlled</c>
<d>which formed a new company for controlling</d>
<e>which formed a new company that would control</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27234-!-item-!-188;#058&003466</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Britain's economic growth was slower in the mid-1970's and its decline much more rapid in the subsequent recession than the United States.</content>
<a>Britain's economic growth was slower in the mid-1970's and its decline much more rapid in the subsequent recession than the United States.</a>
<b>The economic growth of Britain was slower in the mid-1970's and it declined much more rapidly in the subsequent recession than the United States did.</b>
<c>Britain's economy, which grew more slowly in the mid-1970's, also had declined much more rapidly in the subsequent recession than the United States did.</c>
<d>The economy of Britain grew more slowly in the mid-1970's and declined much more rapidly in the subsequent recession than did the economy of the United States.</d>
<e>Britain's economy grew more slowly in the mid-1970's and its decline was much more rapid during the subsequent recession than the economy of the United States.</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27280-!-item-!-188;#058&003467</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Greatly influenced by the Protestant missionary Samuel Kirkland, the Oneida was the only one of the five-nation Iroquois League who sided with the colonists during the American Revolution.</content>
<a>was the only one of the five-nation Iroquois League who sided</a>
<b>was alone of the five-nation Iroquois League when they sided</b>
<c>alone among the five nations of the Iroquois League sided</c>

<d>were the only ones out of the five nations of the Iroquois League in siding</d>
<e>only of the five-nation Iroquois League had sided</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27326-!-item-!-188;#058&003502</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>With a new park, stadium, and entertainment complex along the Delaware River, Trenton, New Jersey, is but one of a large number of communities that is looking to use its waterfront as a way for it to improve the quality of urban life and attract new businesses.</content>
<a>is looking to use its waterfront as a way for it to improve the quality of urban life and attract</a>

<b>is looking at using its waterfront to improve the quality of urban life and attract</b>
<c>are looking to use their waterfronts to improve the quality of urban life and attract</c>
<d>are looking to use its waterfront as a way of improving the quality of urban life and attracting</d>
<e>are looking at using their waterfronts as a way of improving the quality of urban life and attract</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27372-!-item-!-188;#058&003503</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike crested wheatgrass, an alien species from Siberia that forms only shallow roots and produces tall above-ground shoots, native North American grasses develop an extensive root system, allowing for greater enrichment of the soil, but do not grow to be very tall.</content>
<a>native North American grasses develop an extensive root system, allowing for greater enrichment of the soil, but do not grow to be very</a>
<b>native North American grasses develop an extensive root system, which allows for their greater enrichment of the soil, but without growing to be that</b>
<c>the root system of native North American grasses is extensive, allowing for greater enrichment of the soil, but they do not grow to be very</c>
<d>the root system of native North American grasses is more extensive, allowing for the greater enrichment of the soil, but these grasses do not grow to be very</d>
<e>the extensiveness of the root system of native North American grasses allows for their greater enrichment of the soil, but they do not grow to be that</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27418-!-item-!-188;#058&003510</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The ecosystems of barrier islands are extremely vulnerable--whether from natural processes like shoreline recession, rising sea levels, and destructive hurricanes, or the ever-increasing pressures of development.</content>
<a>whether from natural processes like shoreline recession, rising sea levels, and destructive hurricanes, or</a>
<b>whether from natural processes such as shoreline recession, rising sea levels, and destructive hurricanes, or also</b>
<c>to processes that are natural like shoreline recession, rising sea levels, and destructive hurricanes, and also</c>
<d>to processes that are natural ones like shoreline recession, rising sea levels, and destructive hurricanes, as well as to</d>
<e>to natural processes such as shoreline recession, rising sea levels, and destructive hurricanes, as well as to</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27464-!-item-!-188;#058&003513</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>If current trends continue, by the year 2010 carbon emissions in the United States will soar to a level more than one-third higher than were those in 1990, according to official projections.</content>
<a>will soar to a level more than one-third higher than were those</a>
<b>will soar to a level more than one-third higher than that</b>
<c>would soar to a level more than one-third higher than it was</c>

<d>would soar to a level more than one-third higher than those</d>
<e>would soar to a level more than one-third higher than they were</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27510-!-item-!-188;#058&003569</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>An international group of more than 2,000 scientists project an average global warming that will be between 1.8 and 6.3 degrees Fahrenheit by the year 2000.</content>
<a>project an average global warming that will be between 1.8 and</a>

<b>project an average global warming to be from 1.8 to</b>
<c>project global warming that will average between 1.8 and</c>
<d>projects global warming to average from 1.8 to</d>
<e>projects an average global warming of between 1.8 and</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27556-!-item-!-188;#058&003603</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Pioneered by scientists at Los Alamos National Laboratory, BEAM robots are not programmed to walk; instead they use brainlike circuits called neural networks to learn to walk through trial and error.</content>
<a>BEAM robots are not programmed to walk; instead they use brainlike circuits called neural networks to learn to walk through trial and error</a>
<b>BEAM robots learn to walk through trial and error by using brainlike circuits called neural networks instead of by programming them</b>
<c>BEAM robots are not being programmed to walk but instead using brainlike circuits called neural networks and learning to walk through trial and error</c>
<d>brainlike circuits called neural networks are used instead of programming for BEAM robots learning to walk through trial and error</d>
<e>brainlike circuits called neural networks are being used for BEAM robots that learn to walk through trial and error instead of being programmed</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27602-!-item-!-188;#058&003606</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Researchers in Germany have unearthed 400,000-year-old wooden spears from what it appears was an ancient lakeshore hunting ground as stunning evidence of human ancestors who systematically hunted big game much earlier than believed.</content>
<a>it appears was an ancient lakeshore hunting ground as stunning evidence of human ancestors who</a>
<b>it appears had been an ancient lakeshore hunting ground and is stunning evidence that human ancestors</b>
<c>it appears to have been an ancient lakeshore hunting ground and is stunning evidence that human ancestors</c>
<d>appears to be an ancient lakeshore hunting ground, stunning evidence that human ancestors</d>
<e>appears that it is an ancient lakeshore hunting ground, stunning evidence of human ancestors who</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27648-!-item-!-188;#058&003611</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A survey of 765 working women over eighteen years of age found that 60 percent of them worked 40 or more hours a week and for married women with children under eighteen it was more likely that they would work different shifts from their husbands.</content>
<a>for married women with children under eighteen it was more likely that they would work different shifts from their husbands</a>
<b>for married women whose children were under eighteen, they were more likely than other married women to work shifts different from their husbands'</b>
<c>when married women had children under eighteen it was more likely for them to be working different shifts from those of their husbands'</c>

<d>that married women with children under eighteen were more likely than other married women to work shifts different from their husbands'</d>
<e>that when married women had children under eighteen they were more likely to be working shifts that differed from their husbands</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27694-!-item-!-188;#058&003624</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Compared to those who do not, running three days a week saves an average of 14.1 percent on health-care costs each year in the United States.</content>
<a>Compared to those who do not, running three days a week saves</a>

<b>Compared with nonrunners, people who run three days a week save</b>
<c>Compared to not running, those running for three days a week save</c>
<d>When compared with those who do not, people running three days a week save</d>
<e>When compared to nonrunners, running three days a week saves</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27740-!-item-!-188;#058&003625</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The majority of scientists believe that to reduce and stabilize atmospheric concentrations of carbon dioxide, emissions must be cut at the source by fossil fuels that are burned more efficiently and, in some cases, by alternatives such as hydrogen fuel cells that can replace fossil fuels altogether.</content>
<a>fossil fuels that are burned more efficiently and, in some cases, by alternatives such as hydrogen fuel cells that can replace fossil fuels altogether</a>
<b>fossil fuels that are burned more efficiently and, in some cases, those that are replaced altogether with alternatives such as hydrogen fuel cells</b>
<c>burning fossil fuels more efficiently and, in some cases, by replacing fossil fuels altogether with alternatives such as hydrogen fuel cells</c>
<d>more efficiency in the burning of fossil fuels and, in some cases, by alternatives such as hydrogen fuel cells that can replace fossil fuels altogether</d>
<e>the more efficient burning of fossil fuels and, in some cases, by fossil fuels that are replaced altogether with alternatives such as hydrogen fuel cells</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>27882-!-item-!-188;#058&003676</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A group of paleontologists recently announced that a site in Utah has yielded fossils of some of the biggest armored dinosaurs ever found, and they are at least 25 million years older than those of any similar dinosaur type that previously was found in North America.</content>
<a>and they are at least 25 million years older than those of any similar dinosaur type that previously was</a>
<b>and that they were at least 25 million years older than any similar dinosaur type previously</b>
<c>and the fossils are at least 25 million years older than any similar dinosaur types that previously were</c>
<d>fossils that are at least 25 million years older than those of any similar dinosaur type previously</d>
<e>fossils at least 25 million years older than similar dinosaur types that were previously</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27928-!-item-!-188;#058&003732</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In addition to her work on the Miocene hominid fossil record, Mary Leakey contributed to archaeology with her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstakingly documenting East African cave paintings.</content>
<a>Leakey contributed to archaeology with her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstakingly documenting</a>
<b>Leakey contributed to archaeology by her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and by painstakingly documenting</b>
<c>Leakey was a contributor to archaeology with her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and with her painstaking documentation of</c>

<d>Leakey's contributions to archaeology include her discovery of the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and her painstaking documentation of</d>
<e>Leakey's contributions to archaeology include her discovering the earliest direct evidence of hominid activity and painstaking documentation of</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>27974-!-item-!-188;#058&003736</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A pair of architects in Britain, who say that giant arches, bridges, and walls made of artificial bone could be easier to design and build than conventional structures, and already designed a number of structures, including a bridge, for showing how their idea would work.</content>
<a>build than conventional structures, and already designed a number of structures, including a bridge, for showing</a>

<b>build than conventional structures, and they have already designed a number of structures, which includes a bridge, to show</b>
<c>build than conventional structures, have already designed a number of structures, including a bridge, to show</c>
<d>also to build than conventional structures, already designed a number of structures, including a bridge, which shows</d>
<e>to build than with conventional structures, have already designed a number of structures, including a bridge, which shows</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28020-!-item-!-188;#058&003766</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Whereas heat transferred between the ocean and the atmosphere occurs more rapidly when the ocean is warmer than the air, it is slow when the ocean is colder.</content>
<a>Whereas heat transferred between the ocean and the atmosphere occurs more rapidly when the ocean is warmer than the air, it is slow when the ocean is colder.</a>
<b>Unlike the slow process of heat transfer between the ocean and the atmosphere when the ocean is colder than the air, heat transfers more rapidly when the ocean is warmer.</b>
<c>The transfer of heat between the ocean and the atmosphere is slow when the ocean is colder than the air and more rapid when the ocean is warmer.</c>
<d>Transferring heat between the ocean and the atmosphere occurs slowly when the ocean is colder than the air and more rapidly when it is warmer.</d>
<e>When the ocean is colder than the atmosphere, heat transferred between them occurs slowly, unlike the more rapid transfer occurring when the ocean is warmer.</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28066-!-item-!-188;#058&003795</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Sixty-five million years ago, according to some scientists, an asteroid bigger than Mount Everest slammed into North America, which, causing plant and animal extinctions, marks the end of the geologic era known as the Cretaceous Period.</content>
<a>which, causing plant and animal extinctions, marks</a>
<b>which caused the plant and animal extinctions marking</b>
<c>and causing plant and animal extinctions that mark</c>
<d>an event that caused plant and animal extinctions, and it marks</d>
<e>an event that caused the plant and animal extinctions that mark</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28208-!-item-!-188;#058&003886</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Results from the 1998 National Demographic and Health Survey confirm that, even when compared with densely populated countries like Thailand and Indonesia, the Philippine nation's fertility rates consistently exceed all of its Southeast Asian neighbors.</content>
<a>like Thailand and Indonesia, the Philippine nation's fertility rates consistently exceed all of</a>
<b>like Thailand and Indonesia, the Philippine nation consistently exhibits fertility rates exceeding all</b>
<c>such as Thailand and Indonesia, the fertility rates exhibited by the Philippine nation are consistently exceeding those of all</c>

<d>such as Thailand and Indonesia, the Philippine nation's fertility rates consistently exceed all those of</d>
<e>such as Thailand and Indonesia, the Philippine nation consistently exhibits fertility rates that exceed those of all</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28254-!-item-!-188;#058&003934</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike other Mayan cities, Canc??n's commercial power throughout the lowlands seems to be from using its strategic position at the foot of the highlands, which were a source of jade, obsidian, and other valuable commodities.</content>
<a>Canc??n's commercial power throughout the lowlands seems to be from using its strategic position at the foot of the highlands, which were a source of jade, obsidian, and other valuable commodities</a>

<b>Canc??n's commercial power throughout the lowlands seems to have come from using its strategic position at the foot of the highlands, a source of jade, obsidian, and other valuable commodities</b>
<c>the commercial power of Canc??n throughout the lowlands seemed to have come from using its strategic position at the foot of the highlands, a source of jade, obsidian, and other valuable commodities</c>
<d>Canc??n seemed to be using its strategic position at the foot of the highlands, which was a source of jade, obsidian, and other valuable commodities, in becoming a commercial power throughout the lowlands</d>
<e>Canc??n seems to have used its strategic position at the foot of the highlands, a source of jade, obsidian, and other valuable commodities, to become a commercial power throughout the lowlands</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28349-!-item-!-188;#058&003951</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Several educational research groups are denouncing the mayor's proposal of a system by which individual teachers would be given raises or bonuses should it be that test scores show their students' mastery of reading skills having improved over a nine-month period.</content>
<a>should it be that test scores show their students' mastery of reading skills having</a>
<b>should it be that test scores show their students' mastery of reading skills have</b>
<c>should test scores showing their students' mastery of reading skills has</c>
<d>if test scores showing their students' mastery of reading skills having</d>
<e>if test scores show that their students' mastery of reading skills has</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28395-!-item-!-188;#058&003974</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Radiocarbon dating of fossils taken from caves on islands along southeastern Alaska's coast suggest that at least a portion of the area was remaining ice-free during the last ice age.</content>
<a>suggest that at least a portion of the area was remaining</a>
<b>suggest at least a portion of the area remaining</b>
<c>suggests that a least a portion of the area remained</c>
<d>suggests at least a portion of the area that had remained</d>
<e>suggests at least a portion of the area to have remained</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28441-!-item-!-188;#058&003975</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Thirteen states from all regions of the country announced a plan to impose new controls on pollution from truck and bus engines in that they will jointly adopt emission limits that would be far stricter than the federal rules.</content>
<a>to impose new controls on pollution from truck and bus engines in that they will jointly adopt</a>
<b>to impose new controls on truck and bus engines' pollution by the joint adoption of</b>
<c>to impose new controls on pollution from truck and bus engines by jointly adopting</c>

<d>for imposing new controls on pollution from truck and bus engines, and jointly adopting</d>
<e>for imposing new controls on truck and bus engine pollution in the joint adoption of</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28487-!-item-!-188;#058&003987</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Some patients who do not respond to therapies for depression may simply have received inadequate treatment, having, for example, been prescribed a drug at a dosage too low to be effective or having been taken off a drug too soon.</content>
<a>having, for example, been prescribed a drug at a dosage too low to be effective or having been</a>

<b>having, for example, a drug prescription that was ineffective because the dosage was too low, or being</b>
<c>as, for example, having too low of a dosage of a prescribed drug for it to be effective, or being</c>
<d>when they have, for example, been prescribed too low a drug dosage for it to be effective, or were</d>
<e>for example, when they have a drug prescription with a dosage too low to be effective, or been</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28533-!-item-!-188;#058&003994</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recent poll indicates that many people in the United States hold a combination of conservative and liberal political views; i.e., they denounce big government, saying government is doing too much and has become too powerful, while at the same time supporting many specific government programs for health care, education, and the environment.</content>
<a>they denounce big government, saying government is doing too much and has become too powerful, while at the same time supporting</a>
<b>they denounce big government--they say that government is doing too much and has become too powerful--but supporting at the same time</b>
<c>they denounce big government, say that government is doing too much and it has become too powerful, while they support at the same time</c>
<d>while they denounce big government, saying that government is doing too much and has become too powerful, at the same time supporting</d>
<e>while they are denouncing big government--they say that government is doing too much and it has become too powerful-- supporting at the same time</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28579-!-item-!-188;#058&003996</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Anasazi settlements at Chaco Canyon were built on a spectacular scale with more than 75 carefully engineered structures, of up to 600 rooms each, were connected by a complex regional system of roads.</content>
<a>with more than 75 carefully engineered structures, of up to 600 rooms each, were</a>
<b>with more than 75 carefully engineered structures, of up to 600 rooms each,</b>
<c>of more than 75 carefully engineered structures of up to 600 rooms, each that had been</c>
<d>of more than 75 carefully engineered structures of up to 600 rooms and with each</d>
<e>of more than 75 carefully engineered structures of up to 600 rooms, each had been</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28625-!-item-!-188;#058&004000</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>First discovered more than 30 years ago, Lina's sunbird, a four-and-a-half-inch animal found in the Philippines and that resembles a hummingbird, has shimmering metallic colors on its head; a brilliant orange patch, bordered with red tufts, in the center of its breast; and a red eye.</content>
<a>found in the Philippines and that resembles</a>
<b>found in the Philippines and that, resembling</b>
<c>found in the Philippines and resembling</c>

<d>that is found in the Philippines and it resembles</d>
<e>that is found in the Philippines, resembling</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28671-!-item-!-188;#058&004007</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike battery-powered electric cars, automakers say that cars with fuel cells, which supply them with electricity, can provide driving range and performance similar to the internal combustion engine.</content>
<a>Unlike battery-powered electric cars, automakers say that cars with fuel cells, which supply them with electricity, can provide driving range and performance similar to</a>

<b>Unlike battery-powered electric cars, automakers say that cars with electricity supplied by fuel cells can exhibit driving range and performance similar to those provided by</b>
<c>Unlike battery-powered electric cars, fuel cells that supply cars with electricity can provide driving range and performance that automakers say is similar to</c>
<d>Automakers say that unlike battery-powered electric cars, fuel cells that supply cars with electricity can provide driving range and performance similar to</d>
<e>Automakers say that unlike battery-powered electric cars, cars with electricity supplied by fuel cells can exhibit driving range and performance similar to those provided by</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28717-!-item-!-188;#058&004013</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Although at one time children's programming had been limited to a few hours a week, now, however, there are at least four cable networks that dedicate themselves entirely to shows produced specifically for children.</content>
<a>Although at one time children's programming had been limited to a few hours a week, now, however, there are at least four cable networks that dedicate themselves</a>
<b>With children's programming having been limited at one time to a few hours a week, now at least four cable networks have dedicated themselves</b>
<c>Once limited to a few hours a week, there are now at least four cable networks with children's programming that dedicate themselves</c>
<d>Children's programming was once limited to a few hours a week, but now there are at least four cable networks dedicated</d>
<e>While children's programming had once been limited to a few hours a week, at least four cable networks are now dedicated</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28763-!-item-!-188;#058&004022</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Both the caribou and the reindeer belong to the species Rangifer tarandus, but after 7,000 years of domestication in Eurasia, reindeer have developed a tendency to circle in tight groups, while caribou tend to spread far and wide.</content>
<a>belong to the species Rangifer tarandus, but after 7,000 years of domestication in Eurasia, reindeer have developed a tendency to circle in tight groups, while caribou tend</a>
<b>belong to the same species, Rangifer tarandus, but about 7,000 years of domestication in Eurasia have developed reindeer's tendency to circle in tight groups, which is different from caribou that tend</b>
<c>belong to the species Rangifer tarandus, but being domesticated in Eurasia for about 7,000 years has developed reindeer's tendency to circle in tight groups, and that is different from caribou tending</c>
<d>are the same species, Rangifer tarandus, but about 7,000 years of domestication in Eurasia have developed reindeer's tendency to circle in tight groups, while the tendency is for caribou</d>
<e>are the same species, Rangifer tarandus, but being domesticated in Eurasia for about 7,000 years has developed the reindeer's tendency to circle in tight groups, which differs from caribou tending</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28809-!-item-!-188;#058&004029</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In a blow to those who still harbored the illusion that E-mail exchanges are private, a watchdog group recently uncovered a trick for enabling an interloper to rig an E-mail message so that this person will be privy to any comments that a recipient had added as the message is forwarded to others or sent back and forth.</content>
<a>who still harbored the illusion that E-mail exchanges are private, a watchdog group recently uncovered a trick for enabling an interloper to rig an E-mail message so that this person will be privy to any comments that a recipient had added</a>
<b>who had still been harboring the illusion that E-mail exchanges are private, a watchdog group recently uncovered a trick for enabling an interloper to rig an E-mail message so that this person was privy to any comments that a recipient might have added</b>
<c>who still were harboring the illusion that E-mail exchanges are private, a watchdog group recently uncovered a trick enabling an interloper to rig an E-mail message so that this person is privy to any comments that a recipient would add</c>

<d>still harboring the illusion that E-mail exchanges are private, a watchdog group recently uncovered a trick that enables an interloper to rig an E-mail message so that this person will be privy to any comments that a recipient might add</d>
<e>still harboring the illusion that E-mail exchanges had been private, a watchdog group recently uncovered a trick that will enable an interloper to rig an E-mail message so that this person was privy to any comments that a recipient might add</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28855-!-item-!-188;#058&004055</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The number of plant and animal species that humans are known to have forced to extinction in the last half millennium is over 800.</content>
<a>humans are known to have forced to extinction</a>

<b>humans are known as having forced to become extinct</b>
<c>humans are known for forcing to become extinct</c>
<d>are known that humans forced to become extinct</d>
<e>are known as having been forced to extinction by humans</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>28949-!-item-!-188;#058&004110</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Critics of the research study claimed that monkeys are different enough from human beings that comparing the two species can be as questionable--or as useless--as comparisons between humans and mice.</content>
<a>different enough from human beings that comparing the two species can</a>
<b>different enough from human beings so that comparing the two species can</b>
<c>different enough from human beings for comparing the two species to</c>
<d>so different from human beings that comparisons between the two species can</d>
<e>so different from human beings for comparisons between the two species to</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>28995-!-item-!-188;#058&004115</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Now that so much data travels via light--i.e., is carried in glass fibers rather than by electrical current--one goal of semiconductor research is to develop a silicon chip that can transmit and receive light signals directly, a development that may one day lead to smaller, faster semiconductors.</content>
<a>to develop a silicon chip that can transmit and receive light signals directly, a development that may one day lead</a>
<b>to develop a silicon chip with the capability of transmitting and receiving light signals directly, which may one day lead</b>
<c>the development of a silicon chip that has the capability of transmitting and receiving light signals directly, a development maybe one day leading</c>
<d>developing a silicon chip that can transmit and receive light signals directly, which may one day lead</d>
<e>developing a silicon chip with the ability to transmit and receive light signals directly, with this development maybe one day leading</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29041-!-item-!-188;#058&004148</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Just as the free computer operating system Linux has of late become even more crash resistant, so support for it within the computer industry has been growing.</content>
<a>as the free computer operating system Linux has of late become even more crash resistant, so</a>
<b>as with the free computer operating system Linux that has of late become even more crash resistant, so the</b>
<c>as the free computer operating system Linux has of late become even more crash resistant, so it has been that</c>

<d>like with the free computer operating system Linux becoming even more crash resistant of late, so</d>
<e>like the free computer operating system Linux that has of late become even more crash resistant, so it is that</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29087-!-item-!-188;#058&004182</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Exceeding even the figures predicted by the most optimistic financial analysts, the automobile company had earnings in the first quarter that more than doubled the previous quarter.</content>
<a>company had earnings in the first quarter that more than doubled</a>

<b>company earned more than double in the first quarter what they were in</b>
<c>company had first quarter earnings that more than doubled those in</c>
<d>company's earnings in the first quarter were more than double</d>
<e>company's earnings in the first quarter were more than double those of</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29133-!-item-!-188;#058&004212</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Because Miranda, the smallest moon of Uranus, has a large number of different surface features, including craters, mountains, valleys, and fractures, some astronomers suggest that at one time repeated impacts broke the surface apart, and after which the fragments were subsequently rejoined because of mutual gravitational attraction.</content>
<a>repeated impacts broke the surface apart, and after which the fragments were subsequently rejoined because of</a>
<b>repeated impacts on the surface broke it apart, after which the fragments having rejoined with</b>
<c>through repeated impacts that the surface broke apart, after which the fragments subsequently rejoined by</c>
<d>the surface broke apart with repeated impacts, after which the fragments having rejoined through</d>
<e>the surface broke apart as a result of repeated impacts, after which the fragments rejoined through</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29179-!-item-!-188;#058&004217</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Complex human traits such as artistic talent or social skill are likely to be shaped by thousands, if not tens of thousands, of the 80,000 or so genes in the human genome.</content>
<a>such as artistic talent or social skill are likely to be shaped by thousands, if not tens of thousands, of the 80,000 or so</a>
<b>such as artistic talent or social skill are likely shaped by thousands, if not tens of thousands, of 80,000 or so of the</b>
<c>such as artistic talent or social skill is likely to be shaped by thousands, if not tens of thousands, of 80,000 or so of the</c>
<d>like artistic talent or social skill is likely to be shaped by thousands, if not tens of thousands, of the 80,000 or so</d>
<e>like artistic talent or social skill are likely shaped by thousands, if not tens of thousands, of the 80,000 or so</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29225-!-item-!-188;#058&004220</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Diesel engines burn as much as 30 percent less fuel than gasoline engines of comparable size, as well as emitting far less carbon dioxide gas and far fewer of the other gases that have been implicated in global warming.</content>
<a>of comparable size, as well as emitting far less carbon dioxide gas and far fewer of the other gases that have</a>
<b>of comparable size, as well as emit far less carbon dioxide gas and far fewer of the other gases having</b>
<c>of comparable size, and also they emit far fewer carbon dioxide and other gases that have</c>

<d>that have a comparable size, and also they emit far less carbon dioxide gas and other gases that have</d>
<e>that have a comparable size, as well as emitting far fewer carbon dioxide and other gases having</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29271-!-item-!-188;#058&004232</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The spectacular disintegration of a comet last year in full view of ground- and space-based telescopes provided new insights into how comets form and may thus force a rethinking of the role of comets in the delivery of organic compounds to the evolving Earth.</content>
<a>The spectacular disintegration of a comet last year in full view of ground- and space-based telescopes provided new insights into how comets form and may thus force</a>

<b>The spectacular disintegration of a comet last year in full view of ground- as well as space-based telescopes, provided new insights into how comets form and thus possibly forcing</b>
<c>When a comet's spectacular disintegration occurred in full view of ground- and space-based telescopes last year, it provided new insights into how comets form and thus may possibly force</c>
<d>Last year, in full view of ground- and space-based telescopes, a comet's spectacular disintegration provided new insights into how comets form and thus possibly forcing</d>
<e>Last year, in full view of ground- as well as space-based telescopes, the spectacular disintegration of a comet has provided new insights into how comets form and may thus force</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29317-!-item-!-188;#058&004234</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Strawberries, unlike picking bananas that are green and can be ripened artificially, must be picked when they are fully ripe, and they remain at peak flavor for only four or five days after that.</content>
<a>Strawberries, unlike picking bananas that are green and can be ripened artificially, must be picked</a>
<b>Picking strawberries, unlike with green bananas that can be ripened artificially, must be done</b>
<c>Unlike bananas, which can be picked green and ripened artificially, strawberries must be picked</c>
<d>Unlike with green bananas, which can be picked and ripened artificially, strawberry picking must be done</d>
<e>Unlike picking bananas, strawberries cannot be picked green and ripened artificially, but must be picked</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29363-!-item-!-188;#058&004260</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A study on couples' retirement transitions found that, different from men who took new jobs after retiring from their primary careers, women who did so were more likely than those who retired completely to report high marital satisfaction.</content>
<a>different from</a>
<b>unlike with</b>
<c>unlike</c>
<d>unlike the results for</d>
<e>compared to the results for</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29409-!-item-!-188;#058&004276</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Even though her career was cut short when she was in her prime and the fifteen recordings she made were disappointing artistically as well as technically, Olive Fremstad (1871-1951) has never been entirely forgotten by opera aficionados.</content>
<a>though her career was cut short when she was in her prime and the fifteen recordings she made were</a>
<b>though her career was cut short while in her prime, with the fifteen recordings she made</b>
<c>as her career had been cut short when she was in her prime, with the fifteen recordings she had made</c>

<d>with her career having been cut short when she was in her prime, and the fifteen recordings she made were</d>
<e>with her career cut short while in her prime, and that the fifteen recordings she made were</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29455-!-item-!-188;#058&004298</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Officials in Atlanta's public schools, as do many districts across the United States, have eliminated recess in the elementary grades, calling it a waste of time that would be better spent on academics.</content>
<a>as do</a>

<b>as with</b>
<c>similar to</c>
<d>like those in</d>
<e>as they have in</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29501-!-item-!-188;#058&004299</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>There are hopeful signs that we are shifting away from our heavy reliance on fossil fuels:  more than ten times as much energy is generated through wind power now than it was in 1990.</content>
<a>generated through wind power now than it was</a>
<b>generated through wind power now as it was</b>
<c>generated through wind power now as was the case</c>
<d>now generated through wind power as it was</d>
<e>now generated through wind power than was the case</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29547-!-item-!-188;#058&004302</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The arrest of a programmer accused of violating an American digital copyright law has stirred significant opposition, against both the law itself and against the software company that had initiated the case.</content>
<a>against both the law itself and against the software company that had</a>
<b>against both the law itself and also the software company having</b>
<c>against both the law itself and the software company that</c>
<d>both against the law itself and the software company that had</d>
<e>both against the law itself and also against the software company having</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29593-!-item-!-188;#058&004309</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Born into poverty and sent by her father into servitude at the age of seven, Martha Matilda Harper created America's first retail franchise network, a radical new business model that enabled women in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries to own their own businesses and gain financial independence.</content>
<a>Martha Matilda Harper created America's first retail franchise network, a radical new business model that enabled women in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries to own</a>
<b>Martha Matilda Harper created America's first retail franchise network, a radical new business model that enabled ownership by women in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries of</b>
<c>Martha Matilda Harper's creation of America's first retail franchise network was a radical new business model that enabled women in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries to own</c>

<d>America's first retail franchise network was created by Martha Matilda Harper, a radical new business model that enabled women in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries to own</d>
<e>America's first retail franchise network was created by Martha Matilda Harper, a radical new business model that enabled ownership by women in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries of</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29639-!-item-!-188;#058&004327</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Frederick Winslow Taylor, a machinist and engineer who worked in the early twentieth century, believed that the productivity of a job could be improved if one were to separate the components of a task into its individual motions and found the best way to perform each motion, then redesign the job so that each motion could be done as efficiently as possible.</content>
<a>if one were to separate the components of a task into its individual motions and found the best way to perform each motion, then redesign</a>

<b>if one separated the components of a task into individual motions, found the best way to perform the motions, and then redesigning</b>
<c>if the components of a task were separated into individual motions, finding the best way of performing the motions, and then redesigned</c>
<d>by separating the components of a task into individual motions, finding the best way to perform each motion, and then redesigning</d>
<e>by separating the components of a task into individual motions, finding the best way of performing each motion, then redesign</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29685-!-item-!-188;#058&004361</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Patience Lovell Wright, whose traveling waxworks exhibit preceded Madame Tussaud's work by 30 years, became well known as much because of having an eccentric personality as for having skillfully rendered popular public figures in wax.</content>
<a>well known as much because of having an eccentric personality as for having skillfully rendered popular public figures in wax</a>
<b>well known as much for having an eccentric personality as for her skillful wax renderings of popular public figures</b>
<c>well known as much because of her eccentric personality as she was for her skillful wax renderings of popular public figures</c>
<d>as well known for having an eccentric personality as having skillfully rendered popular public figures in wax</d>
<e>as well known for her eccentric personality as for her skillful wax renderings of popular public figures</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29731-!-item-!-188;#058&004378</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The electronics company has unveiled what it claims to be the world's smallest network digital camcorder, the length of which is that of a handheld computer, and it weighs less than 11 ounces.</content>
<a>to be the world's smallest network digital camcorder, the length of which is that of a handheld computer, and it weighs</a>
<b>to be the smallest network digital camcorder in the world, which is as long as a handheld computer, weighing</b>
<c>is the smallest network digital camcorder in the world, which is as long as a handheld computer, and it weighs</c>
<d>is the world's smallest network digital camcorder, which is as long as a handheld computer and weighs</d>
<e>is the world's smallest network digital camcorder, the length of which is that of a handheld computer, weighing</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29777-!-item-!-188;#058&004380</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike a female grizzly bear in the Rockies, which typically occupies a range of 50 to 300 square miles, a male's range will cover 200 to 500 and occasionally as many as 600.</content>
<a>Unlike a female grizzly bear in the Rockies, which typically occupies a range of 50 to 300 square miles, a male's range will cover 200 to 500 and occasionally as</a>
<b>Unlike the range of a female grizzly bear in the Rockies, typically occupying 50 to 300 square miles, a male will cover 200 to 500 and occasionally so</b>
<c>While the typical range of a female grizzly bear in the Rockies is 50 to 300 square miles, with males, their range can cover 200 to 500 square miles and occasionally so</c>

<d>Whereas a female grizzly bear in the Rockies typically occupies a range of 50 to 300 square miles, a male will cover 200 to 500 and occasionally as</d>
<e>The typical range of a female grizzly bear in the Rockies is 50 to 300 square miles, unlike males, which will cover 200 to 500 square miles and occasionally as</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29823-!-item-!-188;#058&004383</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The parachutelike membranes of Africa's scaly-tailed flying squirrels differ from those of the flying squirrels in the family Sciuridae because they are attached to a cartilage rod at the elbow instead of the wrist.</content>
<a>because they are attached to a cartilage rod at the elbow instead of</a>

<b>because of being attached to a cartilage rod at the elbow rather than at</b>
<c>in their attachment to a cartilage rod at the elbow instead of being attached at</c>
<d>in that they are attached to a cartilage rod at the elbow rather than at</d>
<e>in their being attached to a cartilage rod at the elbow instead of</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29869-!-item-!-188;#058&004446</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The yield per acre of coffee berries varies enormously in that a single tree, depending on both its size and on climate and altitude, could produce enough berries to make between one and twelve pounds of dried beans a year.</content>
<a>enormously in that a single tree, depending on both its size and on climate and altitude, could produce</a>
<b>enormously in that a single tree, dependent on its size and also on climate and altitude, is able to produce</b>
<c>enormously, because a single tree, depending on its size and on climate and altitude, is able to produce</c>
<d>enormously, because a single tree, being dependent on its size, climate, and altitude, is capable of producing</d>
<e>enormously, because a single tree, dependent both on its size as well as on climate and altitude, could produce</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>29915-!-item-!-188;#058&004465</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>2001 proved to be the automaker's first losing year since 1992, when the company had lost $7.4 billion, which was primarily because of almost $7 billion in accounting charges.</content>
<a>when the company had lost $7.4 billion, which was primarily because of</a>
<b>when the company had lost $7.4 billion, primarily resulting from</b>
<c>when the company lost $7.4 billion, primarily because of</c>
<d>which is when the company lost $7.4 billion, and that was primarily because of</d>
<e>which is when the company lost $7.4 billion, primarily resulting from</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>29961-!-item-!-188;#058&004575</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>As with those of humans, the DNA of grape plants contains sites where certain unique sequences of nucleotides are repeated over and over.</content>
<a>As with those of humans, the DNA of grape plants contains sites where</a>
<b>As human DNA, the DNA of grape plants contain sites in which</b>
<c>As it is with human DNA, the DNA of grape plants, containing sites in which</c>

<d>Like humans, the DNA of grape plants contain sites where</d>
<e>Like human DNA, the DNA of grape plants contains sites in which</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30007-!-item-!-188;#058&004599</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Galileo did not invent the telescope, but on hearing, in 1609, that such an optical instrument had been made, he quickly built his own device from an organ pipe and spectacle lenses.</content>
<a>Galileo did not invent the telescope, but on hearing, in 1609, that such an optical instrument had been made, he</a>

<b>Galileo had not invented the telescope, but when he heard, in 1609, of such an optical instrument having been made,</b>
<c>Galileo, even though he had not invented the telescope, on hearing, in 1609, that such an optical instrument had been made, he</c>
<d>Even though Galileo did not invent the telescope, on hearing, in 1609, that such an optical instrument had been made,</d>
<e>Even though Galileo did not invent the telescope, but when he heard, in 1609, of such an optical instrument being made, he</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30053-!-item-!-188;#058&004625</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In the United States, while the number of foreign-born residents and their children is higher than ever, the percentage of the population they represent is not; in 1910 this group made up 35 percent of the population when compared to 20 percent in 2000.</content>
<a>population when compared to 20 percent in 2000</a>
<b>population as compared to 2000, when it was 20 percent</b>
<c>population, comparing it with 20 percent in 2000</c>
<d>population, unlike 2000, with 20 percent</d>
<e>population, compared with 20 percent in 2000</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30099-!-item-!-188;#058&004651</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Unlike psychiatrists, who are trained as medical doctors, psychologists have historically been forbidden from prescribing their patients drugs, but in 2002 New Mexico began to grant the privilege of prescribing to licensed, doctoral level psychologists who complete an additional training and certification program.</content>
<a>psychologists have historically been forbidden from prescribing their patients drugs, but in 2002 New Mexico began to grant the privilege of prescribing</a>
<b>psychologists have historically been forbidden to prescribe drugs for their patients, but in 2002 New Mexico began granting prescribing privileges</b>
<c>psychologists have historically been forbidden to prescribe their patients drugs, but in 2002 in New Mexico, the privilege to prescribe began to be granted</c>
<d>historically psychologists have been forbidden from prescribing their patients drugs, but in 2002 New Mexico began to grant the privilege of prescribing</d>
<e>historically psychologists have been forbidden from prescribing drugs for their patients, but in 2002 in New Mexico, they began granting prescribing privileges</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30145-!-item-!-188;#058&004686</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The ivory-billed woodpecker, once the largest woodpecker in North America at a striking 20 inches tall, has moved in and out of the extinct category, with scientists consistently unable to find solid proof for the bird to still exist.</content>
<a>for the bird to still exist</a>
<b>for the bird as still existing</b>
<c>for the bird's continued existence</c>

<d>that the bird still exists</d>
<e>of the bird and its continued existence</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30191-!-item-!-188;#058&004698</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Astronomers have uncovered evidence that a star that was as bright as the full moon exploding into view 340,000 years ago, emitting dazzling radiation that could have disrupted Earth's protective ozone layer and sunburned our Stone Age ancestors.</content>
<a>that a star that was as bright as the full moon exploding into view 340,000 years ago, emitting</a>

<b>that a star as bright as the full moon exploded into view 340,000 years ago, emitting</b>
<c>of a star that was as bright as the full moon exploding into view 340,000 years ago and that it emitted</c>
<d>of a star as bright as the full moon, exploding into view 340,000 years ago and emitting</d>
<e>of a star as bright as the full moon that exploded into view 340,000 years ago and that emitted</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30237-!-item-!-188;#058&004708</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>In hoping to restrain economic growth, interest rates were raised by British policymakers, making it more expensive to borrow for businesses and consumers.</content>
<a>In hoping to restrain economic growth, interest rates were raised by British policymakers, making it more expensive to borrow for businesses and consumers.</a>
<b>Making it more expensive for businesses and consumers to borrow, interest rates were raised by British policymakers, in hopes of their restraining economic growth.</b>
<c>In making borrowing for businesses and consumers more expensive, British policymakers, in hopes they will restrain economic growth, had raised interest rates.</c>
<d>Hopefully restraining economic growth, British policymakers raised interest rates, making more expensive borrowing by businesses and consumers.</d>
<e>Hoping to restrain economic growth, British policymakers raised interest rates, making it more expensive for businesses and consumers to borrow.</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30283-!-item-!-188;#058&005246</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>During the last interglacial period, the climate on the Earth was warmer than it is today, and the consequent melting of the polar ice caps caused the sea level to raise about 60 feet over and above what its height presently is now.</content>
<a>sea level to raise about 60 feet over and above what its height presently is now</a>
<b>sea level to be raised over its height presently about 60 feet</b>
<c>sea level to rise about 60 feet above its present height</c>
<d>level of the seas to rise over and above its present height about 60 feet</d>
<e>level of the seas to be raised over their height, now about 60 feet</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30329-!-item-!-188;#058&005247</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>While Hans Holbein the Younger is most often identified with his English portraits, scholars have long been recognizing him as a superb draftsman and a remarkably versatile artist and who was fundamental in synthesizing the novelties of the Italian Renaissance with the rational tradition of Northern Europe.</content>
<a>been recognizing him as a superb draftsman and a remarkably versatile artist and who</a>
<b>been recognizing him for being a superb draftsman and a remarkably versatile artist and he</b>
<c>recognized him as a superb draftsman and a remarkably versatile artist who</c>

<d>recognized him as a superb draftsman and a remarkably versatile artist and he</d>
<e>recognized him for being a superb draftsman and a remarkably versatile artist and who</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30375-!-item-!-188;#058&005280</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Regardless of their form or function, all aerodynamically enhanced, curved objects made for throwing have been called boomerangs by non-Australians ever since 1788, when Europeans saw Dharug-speaking men tossing "bumariny" in the area later known as Sydney.</content>
<a>Regardless of their form or function, all aerodynamically enhanced, curved objects made for throwing have been called boomerangs by non-Australians ever since 1788,</a>

<b>Regardless of their form or function, any aerodynamically enhanced, curved object made for throwing has been called a boomerang by non-Australians ever since 1788,</b>

<c>Ever since 1788, non-Australians have called all aerodynamically enhanced, curved objects made for throwing boomerangs, regardless of their form or function, from</c>
<d>Ever since 1788, any aerodynamically enhanced, curved object made for throwing has been called a boomerang by non-Australians, regardless of its form or function, from</d>
<e>Non-Australians have called all aerodynamically enhanced, curved objects made for throwing boomerangs ever since 1788, regardless of their form or function, from</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30421-!-item-!-188;#058&005366</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>George Washington Carver dedicated his life to the economic strengthening of the South with improvement of soil and diversification of crops.</content>
<a>the economic strengthening of the South with improvement of soil and diversification of crops</a>
<b>strengthening the economy in the South with soil improvement and the diversification of crops</b>
<c>strengthening the economy of the South through soil improvement and crop diversification</c>
<d>the strengthening of the economy of the South through improving soil and crop diversifying</d>
<e>the economic strengthening in the South with improving soil and diversifying crops</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30709-!-item-!-188;#058&005763</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Constructed at least as early as the Sui dynasty (A.D. 581-618), the Altar of Heaven is the oldest known altar used in Chinese state religious practice, more than 1,000 years older than a similar one in Beijing, it is the only altar found so far that predates the Qing dynasty (A.D. 1644-1912).</content>
<a>Constructed at least as early as the Sui dynasty (A.D. 581-618), the Altar of Heaven is the oldest known altar used in Chinese state religious practice, more than 1,000 years older than a similar one in Beijing, it is</a>
<b>Constructed at least as early as the Sui dynasty (A.D. 581-618), the Altar of Heaven, the oldest known altar used in Chinese state religious practice, is more than 1,000 years older than a similar one in Beijing and is</b>
<c>The Altar of Heaven, having been constructed at least as early as the Sui dynasty (A.D. 581-618) and the oldest known altar used in Chinese state religious practice, is more than 1,000 years older than a similar one in Beijing and</c>
<d>The Altar of Heaven, which was constructed at least as early as the Sui dynasty (A.D. 581-618) and is the oldest known altar used in Chinese state religious practice, more than 1,000 years older than a similar one in Beijing and is</d>
<e>The oldest known altar used in Chinese state religious practice, more than 1,000 years older than a similar one in Beijing, the Altar of Heaven, which was constructed at least as early as the Sui dynasty (A.D. 581-618) and is</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30755-!-item-!-188;#058&005865</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Scientists have found new evidence of people initially registering emotions like sadness or anger in much the same way as heartburn--by monitoring what's going on within their bodies.</content>
<a>of people initially registering emotions like sadness or anger in much the same way as</a>
<b>of people initially registering emotions such as sadness or anger much the same as experiencing</b>
<c>that people initially register emotions such as sadness or anger in much the same way as they experience</c>

<d>that a person initially registers emotions such as sadness or anger much the same way as experiencing</d>
<e>that a person initially registers emotions like sadness or anger much the same as</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30801-!-item-!-188;#058&005879</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>After determining the levels of calcium carbonate and the types of fossilized algae present in core samples taken from the bottom of Lake Titicaca in the Andes, a group of scientists was able to reconstruct the history of precipitation in tropical South America over the past 25,000 years.</content>
<a>the types of fossilized algae present in core samples taken from the bottom of Lake Titicaca in the Andes, a group of scientists was able</a>

<b>the types of fossilized algae that are present in core samples taken from the bottom of Lake Titicaca in the Andes, it was possible for a group of scientists</b>
<c>the types of fossilized algae that had been present in core samples taken from the bottom of Lake Titicaca in the Andes, that made it possible for a group of scientists</c>
<d>what types of fossilized algae had been present in core samples taken from the bottom of Lake Titicaca in the Andes, it was possible for a group of scientists</d>
<e>what the types of fossilized algae were that were present in core samples taken from the bottom of Lake Titicaca in the Andes, a group of scientists was able</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30847-!-item-!-188;#058&005883</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Although the turtle has been toothless for more than 150 million years, in some contemporary turtle species the moderately sharp and jagged edges of their horny jaws function for teeth.</content>
<a>their horny jaws function for teeth</a>
<b>its horny jaws function for teeth</b>
<c>its horny jaws function as do teeth</c>
<d>the horny jaws function as teeth do</d>
<e>the horny jaws function as teeth</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>30893-!-item-!-188;#058&005903</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Changes in the composition of the light of a supernova--an exploding star--reveals not only the chemical elements in the explosion but also the speed of expanding the outer layers of stellar gas.</content>
<a>reveals not only the chemical elements in the explosion but also the speed of expanding the outer layers of stellar gas</a>
<b>reveals not only what chemical elements are in the explosion but also the speed at which the outer layers of stellar gas are expanding</b>
<c>not only reveal the chemical elements in the explosion but also the speed of the expanding outer layers of stellar gas</c>
<d>not only reveal what chemical elements are in the explosion but also the speed of the outer layers of stellar gas when they are expanding</d>
<e>reveal not only the chemical elements in the explosion but also the speed at which the outer layers of stellar gas are expanding</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30939-!-item-!-188;#058&005937</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The features of the floor of the Kasei Valles on Mars look just like those at the base of Antarctic ice streams, so it suggests that possibly it was flowing ice that carved the giant Martian channels previously attributed to cataclysmic floods.</content>
<a>so it suggests that possibly it was flowing ice that</a>
<b>a suggestion that flowing ice may have</b>
<c>to suggest flowing ice as possibly having</c>

<d>suggesting that flowing ice may have</d>
<e>which is suggestive of flowing ice having possibly</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>30985-!-item-!-188;#058&005940</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Vivien Thomas, who had no formal medical training, in struggling against overwhelming odds, he became a cardiac surgeon and eventually to receive an honorary doctorate from Johns Hopkins University.</content>
<a>who had no formal medical training, in struggling against overwhelming odds, he became</a>

<b>having had no formal medical training, in struggling against overwhelming odds to become</b>
<c>who, having no formal medical training, he struggled against overwhelming odds in becoming</c>
<d>who, having had no formal medical training and struggled against overwhelming odds, became</d>
<e>who had no formal medical training, struggled against overwhelming odds to become</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31031-!-item-!-188;#058&005972</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Strawberries, unlike picking bananas that are green and can be ripened artificially, must be picked when they are fully ripe, and they remain at peak flavor for only four or five days after that.</content>
<a>Strawberries, unlike picking bananas that are green and can be ripened artificially, must be picked</a>
<b>Picking strawberries, unlike picking green bananas that can be ripened artificially, must be done</b>
<c>Unlike bananas, which can be picked green and ripened artificially, strawberries must be picked</c>
<d>Unlike with green bananas, which can be picked and ripened artificially, strawberry picking must be done</d>
<e>Unlike picking bananas, strawberries cannot be picked green and ripened artificially, but must be picked</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>31077-!-item-!-188;#058&006010</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Ranked among great mathematical scientists such as Archimedes, Kepler, and Newton, Abu Ali al-Hasan ibn al-Haytham, who was born in Iraq in 965 C.E., had experimented extensively with light and vision, laying the foundation for modern optics and also the notion of science being based on experiment as well as on philosophical arguments.</content>
<a>al-Haytham, who was born in Iraq in 965 C.E., had experimented extensively with light and vision, laying the foundation for modern optics and also the notion of science being based on experiment as well as</a>
<b>al-Haytham, born in Iraq in 965 C.E., experimented extensively with light and vision, laying the foundation for modern optics and for the notion that science should be based on experiment as well as</b>
<c>al-Haytham, born in Iraq in 965 C.E. and who experimented extensively with light and vision, thereby laid the foundation for modern optics and also for the notion that science should be based on not only experiment but also</c>
<d>al-Haytham was born in Iraq in 965 C.E. and had experimented extensively with light and vision, laying the foundation for modern optics and for the notion that science should be based on not only experiment but also</d>
<e>al-Haytham was born in Iraq in 965 C.E., experimenting extensively with light and vision and laying the foundation for modern optics and for the notion of science being based on experiment as well as</e>

<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31123-!-item-!-188;#058&006046</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Because she knew many of the leaders of colonial America and the American Revolution personally, Mercy Otis Warren was continually at or near the center of political events from 1765 to 1789, a vantage point combining with her talent for writing to make her one of the most valuable historians of the era.</content>
<a>a vantage point combining with her talent for writing to make</a>
<b>a vantage point, when combined with her talent for writing, that made</b>
<c>a vantage point that combined with her talent for writing, and it made</c>

<d>and this vantage point, which combined with her talent for writing to make</d>
<e>and this vantage point, combined with her talent for writing, made</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31217-!-item-!-188;#058&006093</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The army cutworm moth is a critical source of fat for as many as a third of Yellowstone National Park's grizzly bears; they overturn rocks to find them, as many as 40,000 per bear in a single day.</content>
<a>bears; they overturn rocks to find them, as many as</a>

<b>bears; overturning rocks to find the insects, up to</b>
<c>bears, overturning rocks to find them, as many as</c>
<d>bears, and they overturn rocks to find them, up to</d>
<e>bears, which overturn rocks to find the insects, as many as</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31359-!-item-!-188;#058&006263</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A Food and Drug Administration rule implemented in December 2000 mandates that any new drug that they intend to be used both by adults and children must undergo pediatric study and that its manufacturers list children's doses on the label.</content>
<a>drug that they intend to be used both by adults and children must</a>
<b>drug whose intended use is for adults and children as well</b>
<c>drug intended for use by both adults and children</c>
<d>drug, if they intend that it be used by adults and also children, must</d>
<e>drug, if intended for use both by adults and children, must</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>31405-!-item-!-188;#058&006278</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Turtles, as with other reptiles, can endure long fasts because they can survive on weekly or even monthly feedings; however, when food is readily available, they may eat frequently and grow very fat.</content>
<a>as with other reptiles</a>
<b>as other reptiles are able to</b>
<c>as other reptiles do</c>
<d>like other reptiles</d>
<e>like other reptiles are able to do</e>

<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31451-!-item-!-188;#058&006301</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The 151 member governments of the World Bank are expected to increase the bank's funding by $75 billion, though some United States legislators cite an obstacle to congressional passage being the concern that the bank's loans will help foreign producers compete with American businesses.</content>
<a>an obstacle to congressional passage being the concern</a>
<b>a concern as an obstacle to congressional passage</b>
<c>as an obstacle to congressional passage the concern</c>

<d>the concern, an obstacle to congressional passage,</d>
<e>as an obstacle for Congress to pass it the concern</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31689-!-item-!-188;#058&006499</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Today's technology allows manufacturers to make small cars more fuel-efficient now than at any time in their production history.</content>
<a>small cars more fuel-efficient now than at any time in their</a>

<b>small cars that are more fuel-efficient than they were at any time in their</b>
<c>small cars that are more fuel-efficient than those at any other time in</c>
<d>more fuel-efficient small cars than those at any other time in their</d>
<e>more fuel-efficient small cars now than at any time in</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31735-!-item-!-188;#058&006516</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A study published in the British Medical Journal showed that women who ate nuts more than five times a week were about one third less likely to suffer from coronary heart disease as those who ate no nuts at all.</content>
<a>as those who ate</a>
<b>as women who ate</b>
<c>as those eating</c>
<d>than women eating</d>
<e>than were those who ate</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>31781-!-item-!-188;#058&006523</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A recently published report indicates that the salaries of teachers continue to lag far behind other college-educated professionals, because they make an average of nearly $8,000 a year less at the start of their careers and almost $24,000 less a year by the time they reach the age of 50.</content>
<a>other college-educated professionals, because they make an average of nearly $8,000 a year less at the start of their careers and almost $24,000 less</a>
<b>other college-educated professionals, by an average of nearly $8,000 a year at the start of their careers, to almost $24,000</b>
<c>what other college-educated professionals are paid--making an average of nearly $8,000 a year less at the start of their careers and almost $24,000 less</c>
<d>those of other college-educated professionals--by an average of nearly $8,000 a year at the start of their careers to almost $24,000 less</d>
<e>those of other college-educated professionals--by an average of nearly $8,000 a year at the start of their careers, and by almost $24,000</e>

<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31827-!-item-!-188;#058&006534</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>If a drug that is already on the market has the potential to help adults and children who have the same disease, or if it is widely used in children and the absence of labeling seems dangerous, the FDA can require that the drug undergo pediatric study.</content>
<a>that the drug undergo</a>
<b>that the drug undergoes</b>
<c>that the drug is to undergo</c>

<d>the drug undergoing</d>
<e>the drug to have to undergo</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31873-!-item-!-188;#058&006542</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Whereas high speeds generally cannot be achieved by ramjets without their initially being assisted by a rocket, a scramjet, or supersonic combustion ramjet, can attain high speeds by reducing airflow compression at the entrance of the engine and letting air pass through at supersonic speeds.</content>
<a>Whereas high speeds generally cannot be achieved by ramjets without their initially being assisted by</a>

<b>Whereas a ramjet generally cannot achieve high speeds without the initial assistance of</b>
<c>With ramjets, high speeds generally are not able to be achieved without initially being assisted by</c>
<d>Unlike with ramjets, generally unable to achieve high speeds without the initial assistance of</d>
<e>Although a ramjet generally does not have the capability of achieving high speeds without the initial assistance from</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>31919-!-item-!-188;#058&006548</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The computer company reported strong second-quarter earnings that surpassed Wall Street's estimates and announced the first in a series of price cuts intended to increase sales further.</content>
<a>The computer company reported strong second-quarter earnings that surpassed Wall Street's estimates and announced the first in a series of price cuts intended to increase sales further.</a>
<b>The report of the computer company showed strong second-quarter earnings, surpassing Wall Street's estimates, and they announced the first in a series of price cuts that they intend to increase sales further.</b>
<c>Surpassing Wall Street's estimates, the report of the computer company showed strong second-quarter earnings, and, for the purpose of increasing sales further, they announced the first in a series of price cuts.</c>
<d>The computer company reported strong second-quarter earnings, while announcing the first in a series of price cuts for the purpose of increasing sales further that surpass Wall Street's estimates.</d>
<e>The computer company, surpassing Wall Street's estimates, reported strong second-quarter earnings, while announcing that to increase sales further, there would be the first in a series of price cuts.</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>31965-!-item-!-188;#058&006588</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Blaming its recent troubles on a widening recession and slow rate of technology spending, the computer company announced that it would cut 10 percent of its workforce--more than 2,000 jobs--and expected to report a loss in its third quarter.</content>
<a>company announced that it would cut 10 percent of its workforce--more than 2,000 jobs--and expected to report a</a>
<b>company announced that there would be a cut--10 percent of its workforce, which was more than 2,000 jobs--and expected a reported</b>
<c>company announced the cutting of its workforce by 10 percent, more than 2,000 jobs, and it expected a reported</c>
<d>company's announcement included the cutting of its workforce by 10 percent, or more than 2,000 jobs, and expecting to report a</d>
<e>company's announcement included cutting its workforce--which is more than 2,000 jobs--and expecting there to be a reported</e>

<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32011-!-item-!-188;#058&006592</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A middleweight black hole weighs in at roughly 500 solar masses, hundreds of times more massive than the lightweight black holes produced by the collapse of individual stars, but thousands or even millions of times less in its mass as the heavyweight giants that lurk in the centers of galaxies.</content>
<a>thousands or even millions of times less in its mass as</a>
<b>it is thousands or even millions of times less massive as</b>
<c>thousands or even millions of times less massive than</c>

<d>yet it is thousands or even millions times less massive than</d>
<e>yet it is thousands or even millions of times less in its mass than</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32057-!-item-!-188;#058&006635</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Taste buds are onion-shaped structures with between 50 and 100 taste cells, each of them has fingerlike projections poking through the opening located at the top of the taste bud called the taste pore.</content>
<a>them has fingerlike projections poking through the opening located at the top of the taste bud called the taste pore</a>

<b>them that have fingerlike projections that poke through an opening located at the top of the taste bud, which they call the taste pore</b>
<c>which has fingerlike projections poking through the opening, called the taste pore, located at the top of the taste bud</c>
<d>which having fingerlike projections that poke through an opening, which is called the taste pore, located at the top of the taste bud</d>
<e>which have fingerlike projections that are poking through an opening located at the top of the taste bud called the taste pore</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32103-!-item-!-188;#058&006640</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>By offering lower prices and a menu of personal communications options, such as caller identification and voice mail, the new telecommunications company has not only captured customers from other phone companies but also forced them to offer competitive prices.</content>
<a>has not only captured customers from other phone companies but also forced them</a>
<b>has not only captured customers from other phone companies, but it also forced them</b>
<c>has not only captured customers from other phone companies but also forced these companies</c>
<d>not only has captured customers from other phone companies but also these companies have been forced</d>
<e>not only captured customers from other phone companies, but it also has forced them</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>32197-!-item-!-188;#058&006684</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Lenders and building managers in the southwestern section of the city report that because of the rental market in the area being renewed, as well as the willingness of the banks to lend money being increased, apartment buildings are being rehabilitated at a pace unseen for a decade.</content>
<a>of the rental market in the area being renewed, as well as the willingness of the banks to lend money being increased</a>
<b>of the renewed rental market in the area, as well as the willingness of banks to lend money increasing</b>
<c>of the renewed rental market in the area and the increased willingness of banks to lend money</c>
<d>the rental market in the area renewed and the willingness of banks to lend money increased, therefore</d>
<e>the rental market in the area was being renewed and banks were increasingly willing to lend money, so</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32243-!-item-!-188;#058&006686</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The ability of scientists to provide models of the atmosphere's complex responses to changing conditions, like seasonal and daily cycles or different planetary conjunctions, have become ever more accurate.</content>
<a>The ability of scientists to provide models of the atmosphere's complex responses to changing conditions, like seasonal and daily cycles or different planetary conjunctions, have become ever more accurate.</a>
<b>The ability of scientists has become ever more accurate in providing models of the atmosphere's complex responses to changing conditions, such as seasonal and daily cycles or different planetary conjunctions.</b>
<c>Scientists have become able to provide ever more accurate models of the atmosphere's complex responses to such changing conditions as seasonal and daily cycles or different planetary conjunctions.</c>

<d>Scientists have become ever more accurate in their ability for providing models of the atmosphere's complex responses to changing conditions, like seasonal and daily cycles or different planetary conjunctions.</d>
<e>Scientists' ability to provide models of the atmosphere's complex responses to such changing conditions as seasonal and daily cycles or different planetary conjunctions have become ever more accurate.</e>
<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32337-!-item-!-188;#058&006899</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Although the vast constellation of small islands that dot the South Pacific has a population of only a few million people, it is home to about a sixth of the world's 6,000 or so languages.</content>
<a>Pacific has a population of only a few million people, it is</a>

<b>Pacific has a population of only a few million people, they are</b>
<c>Pacific is populated by a only a few million people, and it is</c>
<d>Pacific, having a population of only a few million people, is nonetheless</d>
<e>Pacific, populated by only a few million people, yet they are</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32383-!-item-!-188;#058&006902</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Meteor showers and individual streaks of light that flash across the sky every night are generated when tiny flecks of celestial detritus, often no larger than grains of sand or of pebbles, burn up speeding through the atmosphere.</content>
<a>grains of sand or of pebbles, burn up speeding</a>
<b>grains of sand or pebbles, burn up while speeding</b>
<c>grains of sand or pebbles, which burn up while speeding</c>
<d>a grain of sand or pebble, which burns up as it speeds</d>
<e>a grain of sand or a pebble, burns up when it speeds</e>
<answer>B</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>32429-!-item-!-188;#058&006970</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The Kwakiutl recognized one social unit larger than the tribe--the confederacy, which was a cluster of loosely knit, informally related neighboring tribes who interacted with themselves more often than between other tribes.</content>
<a>tribes who interacted with themselves more often than between</a>
<b>tribes who interacted among each other more often than among</b>
<c>tribes who interacted with one another more often than with</c>
<d>tribes, interacting among each other more often than between</d>
<e>tribes, interacting among one another more often than with</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32475-!-item-!-188;#058&007134</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The gyrfalcon, an Arctic bird of prey, has survived a close brush with extinction; its numbers are now five times greater than when the use of DDT was sharply restricted in the early 1970's.</content>
<a>extinction; its numbers are now five times greater than</a>
<b>extinction; its numbers are now five times more than</b>
<c>extinction, their numbers now fivefold what they were</c>

<d>extinction, now with fivefold the numbers they had</d>
<e>extinction, now with numbers five times greater than</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32521-!-item-!-188;#058&007141</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Australian embryologists have found evidence that suggests that the elephant is descended from an aquatic animal, and its trunk originally evolved as a kind of snorkel.</content>
<a>that suggests that the elephant is descended from an aquatic animal, and its trunk originally evolved</a>

<b>that has suggested the elephant descended from an aquatic animal, its trunk originally evolving</b>
<c>suggesting that the elephant had descended from an aquatic animal with its trunk originally evolving</c>
<d>to suggest that the elephant has descended from an aquatic animal and its trunk originally evolved</d>
<e>to suggest that the elephant is descended from an aquatic animal and that its trunk originally evolved</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32567-!-item-!-188;#058&007187</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The United States will be affected by whether Taiwan develops a closer relationship with mainland China or preserves the status quo, since the island nation is the United States' seventh-largest trading partner.</content>
<a>The United States will be affected by whether Taiwan develops a closer relationship with mainland China or preserves the status quo</a>
<b>Whether or not Taiwan develops a closer relationship with mainland China or preserves the status quo affecting the United States</b>
<c>Whether or not Taiwan develops a closer relationship with mainland China or the status quo is preserved, it will affect the United States</c>
<d>It affects the United States whether Taiwan will develop a closer relationship with mainland China or preserves the status quo</d>
<e>It affects the United States whether or not Taiwan will develop a closer relationship with mainland China or preserve the status quo</e>
<answer>A</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>

<mark>32613-!-item-!-188;#058&007195</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>The global-warming effect of ocean white caps are one of the many aspects of the ocean environment that are not yet incorporated in any detail into the computer models used for predicting how rising greenhouse gas concentrations could affect climate.</content>
<a>The global-warming effect of ocean white caps are one of the many aspects of the ocean environment that are not yet incorporated in any detail into the computer models used for predicting</a>
<b>The effect on global warming of ocean white caps are one of the many aspects of the ocean environment not yet incorporated in any detail into computer models, which they use to predict</b>
<c>The effect of ocean white caps on global warming is one of the many aspects of the ocean environment that are not yet incorporated in any detail into the computer models used to predict</c>
<d>That ocean white caps have an effect on global warming is one of the many aspects of the ocean environment not yet having been incorporated in any detail into the computer models that are used for predicting</d>
<e>That ocean white caps have an effect on global warming is one of the many aspects of the ocean environment not yet being incorporated in any detail into computer models, which they use to predict</e>

<answer>C</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32659-!-item-!-188;#058&007220</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>Hydrocarbons, with which fruit flies perfume themselves in species-specific blends, are known to be important in courtship, and apparently this assists flies that taste the hydrocarbons on prospective mates to distinguish their own species from that of others.</content>
<a>and apparently this assists flies that taste the hydrocarbons on prospective mates to distinguish their own species from that of</a>
<b>and apparently this assists flies when they taste the hydrocarbons on prospective mates in distinguishing their own species from those of</b>
<c>which apparently assists flies that taste the hydrocarbons on prospective mates in being able to distinguish their own species from</c>

<d>apparently assisting flies to taste the hydrocarbons on prospective mates to distinguish their own species from those of</d>
<e>apparently assisting flies that taste the hydrocarbons on prospective mates in distinguishing their own species from</e>
<answer>E</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32705-!-item-!-188;#058&007266</mark>
</item>

<item>
<content>A new study finds that the more hostility people show in their behavior and attitudes, then calcium deposits are more likely to be in the arteries of their hearts.</content>
<a>then calcium deposits are more likely to be</a>

<b>then the more likely calcium deposits are</b>
<c>the more there are likely to be calcium deposits</c>
<d>the more likely they are to have calcium deposits</d>
<e>the more likely there are to be calcium deposits</e>
<answer>D</answer>
<source>PREP3</source>
<mark>32751-!-item-!-188;#058&007276</mark>
</item>



</sc>